we have to get over these money myths
我们必须摒弃这些关于金钱的迷思。
that you can't build wealth if you rent
如果你租房，就无法积累财富。
where you live you can't build wealth if
如果你居住的地方不允许你积累财富，
you don't have access to millions of
你无法获得数百万美元
dollars that's not true and there's one
美元？那不是真的，而且只有一个。
he think has given much better returns
他认为已经带来了更好的回报。
than any real estate and any stock and
比任何房地产和任何股票都更重要
even any cryptocurrency so let's talk
甚至任何加密货币，所以我们来聊聊。
about the real way to build true wealth
关于真正积累财富的真正方法
Jas bre Singh is the non-nonsense
贾斯·布雷·辛格是个不废话的人
financial Guru realtor and entrepreneur
金融专家、房地产经纪人和企业家
whose methods have help millions of
他们的方法已经帮助了数百万人
people solve their crippling money
人们解决了困扰他们的资金问题。
problems and unlock Financial Freedom
解决问题并解锁财务自由
people don't like when I say this but I
人们不喜欢我这么说，但是……
don't say what I say to make friends I
不要像我一样为了交朋友而说这些话
say what I say to help people be better
我所说的一切都是为了帮助人们变得更好。
with money there's a lot of people that
很多人在金钱方面……
are lacking Financial education and
缺乏金融教育和
we're Tau study hard get a good job and
我们是Tau，努力学习，找份好工作，
if you continue working down that path
如果你继续沿着这条路走下去
you're going to become successful that
你将会获得成功。
most people buy a house they can't
大多数人买的房子都是他们负担不起的。
afford and statistically are living
负担得起，而且从统计数据来看，他们也确实在生活。
paycheck to paycheck in fact that's 78%
实际上，靠工资度日的比例高达78%。
of Americans because ironically the key
讽刺的是，美国人的关键在于
thing that keeps so many people poor for
导致许多人贫困的原因
the rest of their life is they're scared
他们余生都将在恐惧中度过。
to look broke so what do they do they're
为了显得穷困潦倒，他们会怎么做呢？
driving around in nicer cars going on
开着好车到处兜风
better vacations went to the or
更好的假期去了或
restaurants but they no longer have
餐厅，但他们不再有
money to save they no longer have money
他们没有钱去存钱了。
to invest and the problem is we need
投资的问题在于我们需要
about $1.8 million to comfortably wow so
大约需要180万美元才能让人感到舒适和惊艳。
if you are in the financial danger zone
如果你处于财务危险区
which is you don't have $2,000 saved up
也就是说，你没有2000美元的存款。
for an emergency and you have credit
紧急情况下，如果你有信用额度的话。
card debt you have to make drastic
你必须采取极端措施来偿还信用卡债务。
changes today so what do I do well the
今天发生了变化，那我该怎么做才能做得好呢？
first thing you got to understand is a
首先你要明白的是……
75151 plan which is but now let's dig
75151计划，但现在让我们开始挖掘吧。
this a little bit deeper and let's talk
我们再深入探讨一下这个问题。
about making money I put my money in
关于赚钱，我把钱投了进去
five places that has been proven to win
五个已被证明能够获胜的地方
number one
第一
this has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点难以置信。
bit 53% of you that listen to the show
53% 的听众收听了该节目
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
经常还没有订阅
show so could I ask you for a favor
所以，我能请你帮个忙吗？
before we start if you like the show and
在我们开始之前，如果你喜欢这个节目，
you like what we do here and you want to
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，并且你想……
support us the free simple way that you
您支持我们的方式很简单，而且完全免费。
can do just that is by hitting the
做到这一点的方法就是点击
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅按钮以及我对订阅的承诺
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你那样做，那我也会那样做。
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保这个节目对……更好
you every single week we'll listen your
我们每周都会听取您的意见。
feedback we'll find the guest that you
我们会根据您的反馈找到合适的客人。
want me to speak to and we'll continue
你想让我跟你谈谈，我们继续
to do what we do thank you so much
感谢你们让我能够做我们所做的一切
[Music]
[音乐]
just PR who should care about your
只是公关人员，谁会在乎你？
message and why should they
信息以及他们为什么要这样做
care anybody who uses money which is
关心任何使用金钱的人
everybody the interesting thing about
每个人都觉得有趣的事情是
money is we use money every single day
我们每天都在使用金钱。
it costs money to eat and it costs money
吃饭要花钱，而且也要花钱。
to feed other people yeah most of us are
为了养活其他人，是的，我们大多数人都是如此。
never taught about money so most people
大多数人从小就没有学过理财。
say money doesn't matter I shouldn't
说钱不重要，我不应该这样。
think about money I shouldn't have to
考虑我本不该考虑的钱
worry about money money's bad money's
担心钱，钱不好，钱不好
evil when in reality it cost money to
邪恶，而实际上却要花钱。
eat and it cost money to feed other
吃东西需要花钱，而喂养其他食物也需要钱。
people and when you don't understand
人们，以及当你不理解的时候
that now you're the one that's going to
现在轮到你了
be paying the highest taxes you're the
你是缴纳最高税款的人。
one that's going to be struggling to pay
一个将难以支付费用的人
your bills you're the one that's not
你的账单，你才是那个不该付账单的人。
going to be able to go to Disney World
能够去迪士尼世界
you're the one that can't pay for that
是你付不起这笔钱。
amazing gift for your wife for your
送给妻子的绝佳礼物
husband and you're the one that can't
丈夫，而你却做不到。
pay for the health care for your parents
支付父母的医疗保健费用
and you wonder why and in this economic
你会想知道为什么，在这种经济形势下。
system that we all live in Money talks
我们生活在一个金钱至上的体系中。
and unless you understand that you're
除非你明白你
never going to be able to win in the
永远不可能在这场比赛中获胜
system what is the difference between
系统之间有什么区别
people who figure out how to make
那些想办法制造的人
themselves wealthy and those that don't
他们自己富有，而那些不富有的人则不然。
if we put all objective advantages aside
如果我们把所有客观优势都抛开。
Rich parents inherited lots of money all
富裕的父母继承了大量遗产
these kinds of things what is like the
这类事情就像……
fundamental difference that you've seen
你已经看到的根本区别
from the many many hundreds of thousands
从成千上万个
of people that you've worked with and
你曾经共事过的人以及
taught and that have consumed your
教导并消耗了你的
content
内容
what is the
什么是
fundamental there's one difference one
根本区别在于一点：
key difference people that become
关键区别在于那些成为
wealthy understand how money works and
富人懂得金钱的运作方式，
everybody else does not and I'll tell
其他人都不知道，我会告诉别人的。
you where I came to this
你，我来到这里的原因
conclusion I checked all the boxes I
结论：我已完成所有步骤。
studied hard in school I went through
我在学校努力学习。
high school I went to college I spent
高中时我上了大学，我在那里度过了
one year in graduate school and then I
在研究生院读了一年，然后我
went through law school but I never once
我读过法学院，但我从未……
learned a thing about money I never once
我学到了一件关于金钱的事情，这是我以前从未做过的。
learned to think about Building Wealth I
学会了思考如何积累财富
never once learned to think about
从未学会思考
investing I never once learned to think
投资方面，我从未学会思考
about passive
关于被动
income but if you look at the wealthiest
收入，但如果你看看最富有的人，就会发现他们收入最高。
people in the world they don't get there
世界上的人都到不了那里。
by working a job and getting a raise
通过工作和加薪
they don't get there by working to climb
他们不是通过努力攀登才到达那里的。
the corporate ladder they get there
他们晋升到的职业阶梯
because they understand how money works
因为他们了解金钱的运作方式。
and they understand how to win in the
他们懂得如何取胜。
economic system and the crazy thing
经济体系和疯狂的事情
about that is we're all taught to trust
这件事的关键在于，我们从小就被教导要信任他人。
the system my parents are immigrants
我父母是移民，我所处的这个系统
from a state in India called
来自印度的一个邦
Punjab and like many other traditional
旁遮普邦和其他许多传统地区一样，都是旁遮普邦的传统地区。
Indian immigrants they wanted me to
印度移民他们想让我
become successful now in my house that
现在在我家取得成功
definition of success was very simple
成功的定义非常简单。
they gave me two options I can guess
他们给了我两个选择，我猜是这样的。
well option number one was just you can
第一个选项就是你可以
be a doctor yeah option two was just
当医生？是的，第二个选项就是这个。
prit you can be a failure okay and they
没错，你失败了也没关系，他们
said they get to pick which one and this
他们说他们可以选择哪一个，而这个
is me when I'm like one-year-old that
那是我一岁左右的样子
since the day I could start talking my
自从我能说话的那天起
parents told everybody not just people
父母告诉了所有人，而不仅仅是某些人。
around us they called my family in India
他们周围的人都叫我印度的家人
my family all around the country that J
我的家人遍布全国各地，J
is going to grow up and become a doctor
他长大后会成为一名医生。
because he's going to become
因为他将会成为
successful now I had nothing against
现在成功了，我没有任何反对意见
that because I wanted to become
因为我想成为
successful too I saw how hard my parents
我也取得了成功，我亲眼目睹了我的父母有多么努力。
worked my dad if he got a Saturday on a
我爸如果周六上班的话，就会去上班。
Sunday off was considered a long weekend
周日休息被认为是一个长周末。
I mean my parents bust their butt and I
我的意思是，我父母拼命工作，而我
wanted to become successful so I could
我想获得成功，这样我就可以
give back to them and they told me that
回报他们，他们告诉我……
if I wanted to become successful the way
如果我想通过这种方式获得成功
I do that is by becoming a doctor which
我实现这一目标的方式是成为一名医生，
makes sense because when you're in
这很有道理，因为当你在
school you get those like pamphlets
学校里你会拿到那些小册子之类的东西。
those career pamphlets and they show you
那些职业宣传册会告诉你
the different career options you have
你有哪些不同的职业选择？
and anytime you look at that the top of
任何时候你看向顶部
the list is always doctor and so they
名单上总是医生，所以他们
said just if you want to become
只是说，如果你想成为
successful you have to become a doctor
要想成功，你必须成为一名医生。
and because we came to this country you
因为我们来到了这个国家，所以你
have to become successful so you have to
你必须获得成功，所以你必须
become a doctor now I didn't think
我没想到现在居然会成为一名医生。
anything wrong with it because I liked
它有什么问题吗？因为我喜欢它。
the idea of becoming successful so when
成功的想法，所以当
went down that
事情就是这样发生的。
path now along the way I realized I
现在，在前进的路上，我意识到我
didn't want to be a
不想成为
doctor I told my parents that I'm not
医生，我告诉父母我不是
going to be a doctor my mom almost had a
我妈妈差点就当医生了
heart attack my dad couldn't believe it
我爸心脏病发作，简直不敢相信。
and so my dad essentially told me that
所以，我爸基本上是这么告诉我的。
just if you want to keep any pride in
如果你想保留任何尊严的话
the family you have to at least become
你至少要成为这个家庭的一员。
an attorney so I said okay I went to law
我当时想，好吧，我就去学法律了。
school parttime worked on my business
我在学校兼职，也经营我的生意。
full-time now today I am a licensed
我现在全职工作，持有执照
attorney but I've never worked a day as
律师，但我从未当过一天律师。
an attorney
律师
and the reason why I've never worked as
而我从未从事过以下工作的原因是：
an attorney is because it's just not
找律师是因为事情并非如此。
worth my time and it's not where my
值得我花时间，而且这不是我所在的地方
passion is and along that way that's
激情就是如此，而沿着这条路走下去就是如此。
when I learned that we're taught this is
当我得知我们被教导的是这个时
how you win go to school study hard get
如何才能赢？去学校努力学习。
good grades get a good job and if you
成绩好就能找到好工作，如果你
continue working down that path you're
继续沿着你正在走的这条路走下去
going to become successful but if you
你会获得成功，但如果你
look at the successful people that's not
看看那些成功人士，他们并非如此。
the path that they
他们走的路
followed and if we take a look at the
接下来，如果我们看一下……
three things that have built more wealth
三件能积累更多财富的事
than anything else over the last century
比过去一个世纪以来的任何其他事情都更甚。
it's starting a business investing in
这是创办一家投资企业。
real estate and investing in
房地产及投资
stocks yet along my entire educational
然而，股票却贯穿了我整个教育生涯。
path I was never taught that we're focus
我从未被教导过要专注于这条路
on how do you get a good job but our
关于如何找到一份好工作，但是我们的
wealthy people are focused on is how do
富人关注的是如何……
I grow my
我成长
assets and that's the key difference
资产，这就是关键区别。
here as wealthy people are working to
这里，富人正在努力工作
own the corporate letter everybody else
拥有公司信函，其他人都一样
is working to climb the corporate letter
正在努力攀登企业字母
and then the next thing I'm going to go
接下来我要去
back to what you said assuming that you
回到你刚才说的，假设你
don't have Rich parents because most
大多数情况下，我没有富裕的父母。
people assume that you have to be rich
人们通常认为你必须富有才行。
in order to do this you need millions of
为了做到这一点，你需要数百万
dollars you need access to all this
你需要美元才能获得这一切
money but that's not true you can start
钱，但那不是真的，你可以开始
now with $100 $10 but you have to get
现在有 100 美元，只需 10 美元，但你必须先获得
started the problem is most of us are
问题的根源在于我们大多数人都是
never taught how to do this but unless
从未教过如何做到这一点，但除非
you start doing this you're never going
你一旦开始这样做，就永远不会走了。
to build wealth and that's the way that
积累财富，这就是方法。
you win in this economic system so I
在这个经济体系中，你是赢家，所以我
want to go through all of those three
想把这三件事都经历一遍。
things you've just said I want to talk
你刚才说的那些话，我想跟你聊聊。
about starting businesses I want to talk
我想谈谈创业方面的事情。
about investing in stocks and also want
关于股票投资，也想了解一下。
to talk about real estate but I'm
想谈谈房地产，但我
curious in your own personal story there
我很好奇你的个人经历。
when did the penny drop because it's so
什么时候才恍然大悟的？因为这太不可思议了。
interesting in my life there's key
我生活中有趣的地方在于关键
moments where I got to see behind the
那些让我看到背后的时刻
curtain and when I say see behind the
幕布后面，当我说“看看幕后”的时候
curtain I I'll refer to my friends when
窗帘 I 我会提到我的朋友们
we we're speaking uh privately I'll say
我们正在私下交谈，我会这么说。
I'll refer to it as money games like the
我称之为金钱游戏，例如……
day where I saw these billionaires
那天我见到了这些亿万富翁
playing money games that I was I didn't
我玩的那些赌钱游戏，我都没赢。
know existed and I was there working my
我知道它的存在，而且我当时在那里工作。
butt off working in call centers or
别在呼叫中心工作了
building whatever and then I got to meet
建造任何东西，然后我就遇到了
a billionaire got to spend time with
一位亿万富翁有机会与……共度时光
them got to see behind the curtain and
他们得以一窥幕后真相，
was like oh they just play these money
当时我就想，哦，他们只是玩弄这些钱而已。
games which nobody else has been told
别人都没听说过的游戏
about right um when was the penny drop
差不多吧，嗯……你是什么时候恍然大悟的？
moment for you you qualified as a lawyer
对你来说，这是你获得律师资格的时刻。
why didn't you end up pursuing that some
为什么你最终没有继续追求那个目标呢？
some something happened yeah so when I
是的，发生了一些事，所以当我
was in grade school I began working at
我上小学的时候就开始工作了。
Indian weddings I played a drum called
在印度婚礼上，我演奏了一种叫做……的鼓
the toll it's a Punjabi drum that's
那是一种旁遮普鼓。
where my family is from in India and I
我的家人来自印度，而我
used to play this drum at weddings now
现在经常在婚礼上演奏这种鼓
my parents didn't like that I did this
我父母不喜欢我这样做。
because anything that was not math or
因为任何与数学无关的东西
science was like you don't do this so I
科学就像是说你不能这样做，所以我
had to play this drum uh in secret but I
我不得不偷偷地打这鼓，但是
played at weddings and I started to make
我在婚礼上演奏，然后我开始制作
a little bit of money and by a little
一点点钱，再加上一点点
bit of money I mean $50 per wedding when
一点钱，我的意思是每场婚礼50美元。
I was in Middle School then maybe $100
我当时还在上中学，大概有100美元吧。
$200 in high school and one of the DJs
高中时赚了200美元，还有一位DJ
that I was working with said J you know
我当时和J一起工作，你知道的。
a lot of kids in high
很多高中生
school uh how about we host a teen party
学校，呃，不如我们举办一个青少年派对吧
for some of these kids in your school I
对于你们学校的一些孩子，我
was like okay why not so we hosted this
我们当时就想，好吧，为什么不呢？所以我们就举办了这个活动。
teen party and it was a big success and
青少年派对非常成功。
at the end of the night uh the DJ then
晚上结束时，呃，DJ
starts paying out all the costs because
开始支付所有费用，因为
we were going to go in 50/50 on this
我们原本打算五五分成。
business venture and then we pay out the
商业投资，然后我们支付收益。
money for the security for the venue for
场地安保费用
the marketing and then he says all right
市场营销，然后他说，好的
let's count our profits and he has four
让我们清点一下利润，他有四份。
bills in his hand one two three four
他手里拿着的钞票有四张：一、二、三、四
there's four singles left $2 for him $2
还剩四张单张的，给他两美元，两美元。
for me and I saw that we put in so much
对我来说，我看到我们投入了这么多。
work into this business venture into
投入到这项商业冒险中
this idea into this this first party and
这个想法融入到第一方和
we made $4 of profit which we split
我们赚了4美元，我们平分了这笔钱。
50/50 and at that moment he was really
五五开，那一刻他真的
upset but I was really not upset at all
虽然有点生气，但我其实一点也不生气。
because I was like this was fun you know
因为我觉得这很有趣，你知道吗？
it was it was it was a lot of fun
那真是太有趣了
putting this together but in my mind it
把这些整理好，但在我看来
was just one of those hobbies that I was
这只是我众多爱好之一。
doing because I needed to become a
这样做是因为我需要成为一个
doctor well I did a few of those teen
医生，嗯，我做过几个青少年检查。
parties when I was in high school and
我在高中时参加的聚会
now it was time for me to go to college
现在我该上大学了。
I was 17 years old and I get there and I
我当时17岁，到了那里，然后我
see everybody partying drinking blowing
看到大家都在聚会、喝酒、吹箫。
money they don't have and I was shocked
他们根本没有钱，我感到很震惊。
I had no idea that people went to
我完全不知道人们会去那里
college to party and I had no idea
大学生活就是为了参加派对，而我对此一无所知。
people got the money to spend money on
人们有钱可以花钱
all this
这一切
alcohol I don't drink I'm not into
我不喝酒，我对酒精没兴趣。
partying but now I needed something to
聚会结束了，但我现在需要一些东西
do on Friday nights and so now I'm
我周五晚上会这样做，所以现在我是
thinking what do I do
我在想我该怎么办
how about I take this teen party
我来参加这个青少年派对怎么样？
business concept that I had in high
我高中时就有的商业理念
school and now do it in college so I was
以前在学校，现在在大学也做，所以我是
17 and I started knocking on the doors
17岁时，我开始敲门。
of all the bars venues restaurants
所有酒吧、餐厅
trying to see if anybody would let me
我想看看有没有人愿意让我
host a party there and in the beginning
在那里举办派对，一开始
some said sure you can host a party here
有人说当然可以在这里举办派对。
we just need a $10,000
我们只需要1万美元
deposit I don't have $10,000 I was 17
我没有1万美元的存款，我当时才17岁。
years old so I kept going some said I
几岁了，所以我继续前进，有人说我
need a $20,000 deposit but eventually I
需要2万美元的押金，但最终我
found this one club that said yeah you
找到一家俱乐部，他们说“是的，你”。
can host a party here you don't got to
你可以在这里举办派对，你不必非得……
pay us anything just pay us half of the
付多少钱都行，只要付我们一半就行。
cover charge that you generate pay has
你产生的入场费已支付
50% of whatever Revenue you generate now
你现在所产生收入的50%。
I'm in business I made the same
我做生意，我也赚了同样的钱。
arrangement with my DJ I said look how
我和我的DJ约定好，我说看看
about you DJ for me for free and I'll
请你免费为我做DJ，我会
split whatever profits I make with you
我赚到的所有利润都和你平分。
and that was the beginning of my first
那是我第一次经历的开始。
real business it was this party
这才是真正的生意，这才是这场派对。
promotion company which then became an
一家推广公司，后来发展成为一家
event planning
活动策划
company and it grew pretty big in
公司规模越来越大
college I mean I started off by hosting
我是说大学的时候，我一开始是做主持人。
these one-off parties then I was
这些一次性的聚会，当时我……
contracted by one of the largest clubs
受雇于一家大型俱乐部
on campus to host their weekly college
在校园里举办他们的每周大学活动
night so I was hosting their parties
那天晚上，我负责主持他们的派对。
every week we were hosting official
每周我们都会举办官方活动。
shows and After parties and it grew
演出和派对，以及它的发展
pretty
漂亮的
large
大的
and now as this business starts to make
现在，随着这项业务开始盈利
money the first thing that I realized is
我首先意识到的是金钱。
I don't need a license or degree to make
我不需要执照或学位就能制作
money I thought that was something that
钱，我以为那是……
I needed because I thought I needed
我需要，因为我以为我需要
these good grades to qualify for this
这些优异的成绩才能获得这个资格
thing to make money so that was the
赚钱的方法就是这样。
first kind of shock and
第一种冲击和
realization the second realization that
第二次意识到
I had was I knew nothing about money I
我当时对金钱一无所知。
was making a little bit of money and I
我当时赚了点小钱，而且
was very fortunate that I started
我很幸运能开始这段经历。
reading books about money and
阅读有关金钱的书籍
business and I started reading these
商业，我开始阅读这些
books and the first thing I learned was
书，我学到的第一件事是
the difference between an asset and a
资产与资产之间的区别
liability which were things I had never
我从未承担过的责任。
heard of before
以前听说过
an asset is something that puts money in
资产是指能带来收益的东西。
your pocket a liability is something
你的口袋可能成为一种负担。
that takes money out of your pocket
那会让你掏钱
wealthy people want to own assets I was
富人都想拥有资产，我曾经也是。
buying a whole lot of liabilities
购买大量负债
because I was working in this party
因为我当时在这个党工作。
promotion business and I wanted to look
推广业务，我想看看
the part so I would make a little bit of
所以我会稍微做一点这部分
money buy a nice watch make a little bit
用钱买块好表，赚点小钱
more money put some new rims on my car
我又有钱了，给我的车换了套新轮毂。
put a new sound system in my car put a
给我的车装了一套新的音响系统
new uh subwoofer in my car I mean I was
我车里新装了个低音炮，我是说，我之前……
blowing money and all these dumb things
挥霍金钱和所有这些愚蠢的事情
to look like I was rich when in reality
表面上看起来很有钱，但实际上
I was just making a lot of other people
我当时只是在做很多其他人的事。
rich and then I learned about this thing
富有之后，我了解到了这件事。
called
称为
investing which really started to upset
投资真的开始让人不安了。
me because I thought I was doing
因为我以为我在做
everything right and I'm reading these
一切都好，我正在读这些。
books that are talking about how every
讨论如何一切的书籍
wealthy person invests in real
富人投资房地产
estate I have no idea what that means
遗产？我不知道那是什么意思。
nobody in my family is a real estate
我家没人从事房地产行业。
investor I had never heard of this
我之前从未听说过这位投资者。
concept of real estate investing
房地产投资的概念
before I don't know what it is is but if
之前我不知道那是什么，但如果
wealthy people are Real Estate Investors
富人都是房地产投资者。
and I want to become wealthy maybe I
我想变得富有，也许我
should invest in real
应该投资房地产
estate so when I was 19 I'm now studying
所以，我19岁的时候就开始学习房地产了。
to get into medical school because I
为了考上医学院，因为我
still think that I'm going to become a
仍然认为我会成为一个
doctor and I was bored out of my mind
我和医生都无聊透了。
because I would spend all day 10 to 12
因为我每天都会花10到12个小时。
hours a day in the library
每天在图书馆待几个小时
studying and this was around
学习期间，大约是这个时候。
2011 and the reason why I say the year
2011年，以及我之所以提到这一年的原因是
is because if you remember 2008 was was
因为如果你还记得的话，2008年是……
the great financial crisis that was when
那场大金融危机
we had the real estate collapse in
我们经历了房地产崩盘
America so real estate prices were
所以美国的房地产价格是
decimated and they didn't hit rock
损失惨重，而且他们没有击中岩石
bottom until 2012 that's why I'm saying
直到2012年都处于谷底，所以我才这么说。
this so in 2011 I'm studying to take the
所以，2011年我正在学习准备参加考试。
Medical College ad Mission test the MCAT
医学院广告使命测试MCAT
and I'm reading these books talking
我一边读这些书一边聊天。
about how wealthy people invest in real
关于富人如何投资房地产
estate and now I'm making a little bit
我现在有块地，赚了点钱。
of money from this party business and
从这个政党生意中赚到的钱
have a little bit of cash in the bank so
银行账户里有点现金，所以
during my breaks when I'm studying for
休息时间，当我学习的时候
the test I start looking on the internet
我开始在网上查找相关的测试信息。
websites of finance and they all talk
金融网站，它们都在谈论
about how real estate prices have hit
关于房地产价格如何受到影响
rock bottom how real estate is being
房地产市场跌至谷底
decimated in America and so I was like
美国遭受重创，所以我当时就想
well maybe I start looking to buy real
或许我应该开始考虑购买真正的
estate and so on August 22nd I took the
庄园，因此在8月22日，我接管了
Medical College admission test and then
医学院入学考试，然后
on August 23rd I purchased my first real
8月23日，我购买了我的第一辆真正的
estate investment property it was a
房地产投资房产
small condo that I purchased out of
我从……中购买了一套小公寓
foreclosure a few years prior it had
几年前它曾因止赎而被拍卖
sold for a little bit over
售价略高于
$150,000 and then like many properties
15万美元，然后就像很多房产一样
it went through foreclosure the banks
它被银行取消赎回权了。
couldn't sell it and it was listed on
卖不出去，已经挂牌出售了。
sale for
出售
$8,400 that was a total price of the
总价为 8,400 美元。
condo so I came in with an offer of
所以我带着一套公寓的报价来了。
$4,000 because I don't know what how
4000美元，因为我不知道该怎么做
this real estate investing stuff works
这些房地产投资方法确实有效。
and we were back and forth with the bank
我们和银行之间来回沟通。
the bank said will sell it to you for
银行说会把它卖给你
$7,000 I tried to negotiate them even
我试着跟他们谈判，最终只给了7000美元。
lower and then the bank said that they
降价后，银行表示他们
had another offer on the table so now
当时还有另一份报价摆在桌面上，所以现在
it's a bidding war and I had to pay
这是一场竞价战，我不得不付钱。
offer my highest and best
我将竭尽全力，做到最好。
price so I said I'm willing to offer
价格方面，我说我愿意出价
$8,000 to buy the condo no more and they
8000美元就能买下这套公寓，他们不再需要这笔钱了。
accepted my bid so I purchased this
我的出价被接受了，所以我买下了这件商品。
condo for
公寓
$88,000 I put in a few thousand worth
我投入了价值几千美元的88,000美元。
the work and then I rented it out for
完成这项工作后，我把它租了出去。
$600 a month and now I start start to
每月600美元，现在我开始……
question things why did nobody tell me
质疑为什么没人告诉我
about this this condo is putting money
关于这套公寓，它正在投入资金。
into my pocket without me having to do
无需我费力，它就放进了我的口袋。
something because I own this asset we're
因为我拥有这项资产，所以我们……
all taught to trade our time for dollars
我们都被教导要用时间换取金钱
we're all taught to work to get paid
我们从小就被教育要工作才能获得报酬。
because that's what we're taught to do
因为我们从小就被教导要这样做。
but wealthy people are not working for a
但富人并非为……工作
bigger salary they're working for more
他们为了更高的薪水而工作。
assets because that can continue to pay
因为这些资产可以继续支付
you even when you're not working and
即使你不工作的时候，你也会这样。
that's that shift when I saw that that
我看到那件事的时候，转变就发生了。
really sparked a fire under me and
这真的点燃了我内心的火焰。
really made me angry and I don't know
真的让我很生气，我不知道为什么
why I got so angry but I got angry
我为什么这么生气？但我确实生气了。
because I felt like I was checking all
因为我觉得我好像在检查所有东西。
the boxes I was doing good in school I
我在学校表现很好的那些盒子
bust my butt in school I was going to do
我在学校拼命学习，我本来打算……
all the right things become a doctor and
具备成为医生的所有条件
do everything that I was told but what I
我照做了所有被告知的事情，除了我……
didn't realize
没意识到
is those boxes weren't my boxes who
那些箱子不是我的箱子，是谁？
created these boxes and why is there
这些盒子是做什么用的？为什么会有这些盒子？
this whole world of financial education
整个金融教育领域
that were never taught because if this
因为如果这种情况，那些从未被教授过的内容就无法被教授。
is how wealthy people build and grow
这就是富人积累财富和发展壮大的方式。
their wealth why is everybody else not
为什么其他人没有他们的财富？
taught this so I want to make a
我教过这个，所以我想做一个
distinction here are you saying that in
你是说，这里的区别在于……
order to build wealth people should buy
为了积累财富，人们应该购买
a
一个
house no if you want to build wealth you
如果你想积累财富，房子编号是你
have to buy assets when people say buy a
当人们说买资产时，你必须买入资产。
house what does that mean to most
房子对大多数人来说意味着什么？
people's eyes it means buy my home yeah
在人们眼里，这意味着买我的房子，是的。
I want to buy this nice place for me to
我想买下这处好地方留给自己。
live which is what most people do when
生活，这也是大多数人所做的。
they get a bit of money they take their
他们弄到一点钱，然后就拿走他们的
salary from work and then they go and
他们靠工作挣工资，然后就走了
buy a house to live in and then they pay
买房自住，然后他们支付
into the mortgage which means that they
计入抵押贷款，这意味着他们
are now building an asset right they're
他们现在正在积累一项资产，对吧？
building what many people call
建造许多人所谓的
generational wealth which is one of the
代际财富是其中之一
biggest lies when it comes to money the
关于金钱的最大谎言
reason why is because your house is
原因在于你的房子是
actually a money
实际上，这是一笔钱
pit and that's why I want you to think
深渊，这就是为什么我想让你思考
of your house as a liability but I want
你的房子可能成为你的负担，但我想要
you to hear me clearly I'm not saying
让你听清楚，我不是在说
you shouldn't buy a house I'm not saying
我不是说你不应该买房。
it's bad to buy a house you have to
买房很糟糕，你必须
treat your house like a liability this
把你的房子当成负债来对待
suit that I'm wearing is a liability
我身上这身西装是个累赘。
this watch is a liability my shoes are
这块表是个累赘，我的鞋子也是。
liabilities should I not buy them no I
负债我应该不买吗？不，我不
got to make sure I can afford them so
我得确保自己买得起才行。
when people think about buying a house
当人们考虑买房时
what do they think of they think I'm
他们会怎么想？他们会怎么想我？他们认为我是……
going to build generational wealth I'm
我要创造世代财富。
going to build wealth I'm going to pay
我要积累财富，我要付出代价
it off and I'm going to be able to have
把它关掉，我就能拥有
more freedom in my life because I can
因为我可以，我的生活将拥有更多自由。
own this house let's go with the best
拥有这栋房子，就选最好的。
case scenario you buy a home for let's
假设你买了一套房子出租
call it
就叫它
$300,000 you pay it
你付30万美元
off and throughout your lifetime this
关闭，并贯穿你的一生
$300,000 home grows in value to a
价值 30 万美元的房屋增值至
million dollar and now you're going to
一百万美元，现在你要……
say just PR I showed you this is an
就说公关稿吧，我已经向你展示了这是一个
asset my house tripled in value more
我的房子价值翻了三倍多
than tripled in value and now I'm going
价值翻了三倍，现在我要走了
to pass it down to my kids so now yeah
想把它传给我的孩子们，所以现在，是的。
your kids got a million dollar house but
你的孩子得到了一栋价值百万美元的房子，但是
unless they have the income to support
除非他们有足够的收入来维持生计。
paying for a million dollar house they
他们用这笔钱买了一栋价值百万美元的房子
might have to find some more cash now
现在可能得再找点钱了。
would what do they do because you can't
他们会怎么做？因为你做不到。
just pull cash out of this house right I
直接把现金从这房子里取出来就行了。
mean it's not an ATM unless you go to
这意味着除非你去那里，否则它就不是自动取款机。
the bank the bank will give you the cash
银行会给你现金
because the bank says oh you have a
因为银行说，哦，你有一个
million dollar house how about we loan
价值百万美元的房子，我们贷款怎么样？
you
你
$800,000 but that's not an ATM because
80万美元，但那不是自动取款机，因为
you have to pay that money back plus
你必须把那笔钱还回去，而且
interest and unless your kids have the
兴趣，除非你的孩子有
income to pay for the property tax to
收入用于支付房产税
pay for the insurance to pay for the
支付保险费以支付
upgrades to pay for the maintenance and
升级费用用于支付维护和
the mortgage they can't afford that
他们负担不起那笔抵押贷款
house so maybe now they have to
所以现在他们可能不得不搬房子了
sell okay now you sell it you got a
好了，现在你把它卖掉，你得到了一个
million dollars great we're not even
一百万美元很棒，我们甚至都还没到呢
going to talk about taxes right now but
我们现在要谈谈税收问题，但是
you got a million dollar you're
你得了一百万美元，你是
rich but if they don't have any
富有，但如果他们没有任何东西
Financial education and you have a
金融教育，你拥有
million dollars what's going to happen
一百万美元，接下来会发生什么？
well let's think about this if you had a
好，我们来想想，如果你有一个
million dollars what would you do with
如果你有一百万美元，你会怎么做？
it if I went down the street and I asked
如果我走到街上问……
the average person if I wrote you a
如果我写信给一个普通人，他会怎么想？
check for a million dollars today what
今天查一下有没有一百万美元？
would you do what are people going to
你会怎么做？人们会怎么做？
say I'm going to go to the Bahamas I'm
我说我要去巴哈马群岛，我是
going to buy myself a nice house I'm
我打算给自己买一套好房子。
going buy myself a nice car buy myself
我要给自己买辆好车，买给自己
some nice clothes go to the Gucci store
去古驰店买些漂亮的衣服吧
go to the Louis Vuitton store and buy
去路易威登专卖店购买
myself the extra guaca Chipotle that's
我自己加了一份Chipotle的牛油果酱。
what the average person will do now
普通人现在会怎么做
maybe you're a little bit more
或许你更……
financially smart you say I'm just going
你说我理财有道，那我这就走。
to live off of $50,000 a year but after
靠每年5万美元生活，但之后
20 years you have nothing left not to
20年后，你已经没有什么可以不去的了。
mention the fact that 10 years from now
提到10年后的事情
that $50,000 a year lifestyle is going
年收入5万美元的那种生活方式正在消逝
to buy you half of what it can
可以买给你它所能买到的一半。
today so now let's go back to that
今天，所以我们现在回到那个话题。
situation you thought you built
你以为你已经建立的局面
generation of wealth you did a good
你创造财富做得很好
thing about paying off the mortgage
想想还清房贷的事儿
because you don't have to pay the
因为你不需要支付
mortgage
抵押
payment but is that really the type of
支付方式真的是这种类型吗？
generational wealth that you
你拥有的世代财富
want and now to fully Hammer this home
想要，现在要彻底改造这栋房子
I'm not saying it's bad to own a house
我并不是说拥有房产不好。
it's actually very great it's an amazing
它真的非常棒，简直令人惊叹
thing to own your house free and clear
拥有完全属于自己的房子是一件很棒的事。
because now you can rest assured you
因为现在你可以放心了
don't have to worry about the mortgage
不必担心房贷
payments if you have the financial
如果您有经济能力，可以支付。
education that's great but let's talk
教育固然很好，但我们来谈谈吧。
about now the real way to do this and
现在才是真正做这件事的方法，
build true wealth when I buy my real
当我购买我的真正产品时，就能积累真正的财富。
estate investment properties and my
房地产投资物业和我的
property values go up the rental values
房产价值上涨，租金上涨
also go up the rent is what pays for the
租金上涨也是因为租金要用来支付其他费用。
maintenance the rent is what pays for
租金是支付维护费用的来源。
the upgrades the rent is what's paying
租金就是用来支付升级费用的。
for the property taxes and the insurance
用于支付房产税和保险费
the rent is putting money in my
房租让我的收入增加了。
pocket and this is cash flow that I can
这是我口袋里的现金流。
use I can use this cash flow to buy a
我可以利用这笔现金流来购买
vacation I can use this cash flow to buy
我可以用这笔现金流来度假。
food I can use this cash flow to pay for
我可以用这笔现金流来支付食物费用
my lifestyle
我的生活方式
but your house doesn't do that you have
但你的房子不会那样，你有
to pay to live in your house but people
付钱住在自己的房子里，但人们
think you know they're getting their
你以为你知道他们正在得到他们的
mortgage payments they're spending
他们正在支付的抵押贷款
whatever they are you know spending on
无论他们花在什么地方，你知道的
their mortgage payments they they think
他们的抵押贷款还款，他们认为
they're well we're kind of told that
他们，嗯，我们被告知……
that mortgage payment is an
那笔抵押贷款付款是
investment into an
投资于
asset your mortgage payment is a payment
你的抵押贷款还款额就是一项资产支付
to your bank banks are not stupid in
银行并不傻，你的银行……
fact they're very smart Banks do
事实上，他们非常聪明，银行确实如此。
something called front front loading
叫做前置装载
your mortgage what that means is if you
你的抵押贷款，这意味着如果你
go out and get a 30-year mortgage which
出去申请一份30年期抵押贷款，
is what many people do in
这是许多人都在做的事情
America and you pay $3,000 a month on
在美国，你每月要支付 3000 美元
your
你的
mortgage you're not paying $1,500 to
你无需支付1500美元的抵押贷款
your interest your bank and $1,500 to
您的利息、您的银行和 1,500 美元
your principal your Equity the way it
你的本金，你的权益，就是这样
works is Banks frontload your mortgage
银行提前收取抵押贷款费用的做法是行不通的。
which means for the first almost 15
这意味着在前近15
years it's about 14 years and 8 months
大约是14年零8个月
or so but for almost 15 years of your
或者说差不多，但近15年来，你的
mortgage the first 15 years the majority
抵押贷款的前15年大部分
of your mortgage payment is going
你的房贷还款额正在减少
directly into your Banker's pocket in
直接进入你银行家的口袋
the form of Interest which means if
利息的形式，这意味着如果
you're paying $33,000 a month on your
你每月要支付 33,000 美元。
mortgage for the first part of your
您第一部分的抵押贷款
mortgage maybe $100 is going out of the
房贷可能要花掉100美元。
$3,000 into your Equity the other
将 3,000 美元投入您的股权，另一方
$2,900 is going right into your Banker's
2900美元将直接存入您的银行账户。
pocket with interest and now yeah after
口袋里装满了利息，现在，是的，之后
15 years now half of your mortgage
15年后，你还清了一半的房贷
payment is going to your equity and half
款项将用于您的股权和一半。
is going to
将会
interest but if you refinance before
利息，但如果您在之前进行再融资……
that 15year Mark that starts over and so
那15年的里程碑重新开始，就这样。
this is where Banks understand the gain
这就是银行明白收益所在的地方。
again I'm not against buying a house but
我并不反对买房，但是
you got to understand the game of money
你必须了解金钱的游戏规则。
and most people don't understand that
大多数人都不明白这一点。
and so the mistake that people make is
因此，人们犯的错误是
they buy a house they can't afford and
他们买了一套他们负担不起的房子，
now they're paying all this money into
现在他们把所有这些钱都投入到
their mortgage thinking that I'm
他们以为我是他们的抵押贷款人
Building Wealth they no longer have
他们不再拥有的财富
money to save they no longer have money
他们没有钱去存钱了。
to invest into other real
投资其他房地产
assets and their money is just going to
资产和他们的钱都将流向
pay down their mortgage thinking that
他们想着偿还房贷。
this is going to build my wealth but
这将为我积累财富，但是
you've been sold a lie this term
这学期你被骗了。
opportunity cost most people don't know
机会成本，大多数人并不了解。
what this term opportunity cost means
机会成本这个术语是什么意思？
but it appears to be very pertinent to
但这似乎与此非常相关
what you're saying especially when you
你说的这些话，尤其是在你……的时候
just said this is money that you can't
刚才说了，这是你不能拿走的钱
then invest in assets can you explain
然后投资资产，你能解释一下吗？
what opportunity cost is and how it's
什么是机会成本，以及它是如何产生的。
impacted if you if you buy a house sure
如果你买房，肯定会受到影响。
if you have let's let's make the numbers
如果你有的话，我们就来计算一下数字吧。
very simple you want to buy a $100,000
很简单，你想买一辆价值 10 万美元的
home and let's say the banks require a
假设银行要求……
20% down payment
首付20%
$20,000 you could do a few things number
2万美元你可以做很多事
one you can take that $20,000 and go out
你可以拿着那2万美元出去玩。
and buy this house and now that's how
然后买下这栋房子，事情就是这样。
that money has been used but if you use
那笔钱已经被用过了，但是如果你使用
that money to buy the house you lose the
你失去的那笔买房的钱
opportunity to take that $20,000 and say
有机会拿走那2万美元，然后说
use it to buy a rental property you lose
用它来购买出租房产，结果却输了。
the opportunity to use that $20,000 to
利用这2万美元的机会
inv in the stock market you lose the
投资股市你会亏损
opportunity to take that $20,000 and
有机会拿到那2万美元
maybe build a
或许可以建造一个
business now the question is what is
现在商业的问题是：什么是
going to give you the best and most
将会给你最好、最棒的
growth now hopefully this house that you
希望你现在能拥有这栋房子，并且它能发展壮大。
buy will go up in value it's not
买入后价格会上涨，并非如此。
guaranteed we know the houses don't
我们保证我们知道这些房子不
always go up in value no matter what
无论如何，价值总是会上升的。
your Banker says no matter what your
你的银行家说，无论你
real estate agent says because we saw
房地产经纪人说，因为我们看到
what happened after the 2008 crash where
2008年车祸后发生了什么？
real estate prices were slashed in
房地产价格大幅下跌
half it was as much as is
一半和现在一样多
93% real estate values dropping in the
93%的房地产价值下跌
state of Michigan where I am so we know
我所在的密歇根州，所以我们知道
real estate prices don't always go up
房地产价格并非总是上涨的。
stock prices don't always go up
股票价格并非总是上涨。
businesses don't always
企业并非总是如此
work everything has a risk but now the
任何工作都有风险，但现在
question is which risk do you want to
问题是，你愿意承担哪种风险？
take and which risk do you want to take
你愿意承担哪种风险？
first are you in a situation now where
首先，你现在所处的情况是？
you're ready to go out and buy a house
你准备好去买房了
or do you want to build your wealth
或者你想积累财富？
first a little bit more and that's the
首先再多一点，就是这样。
question that I want people to start
我想请大家提出这个问题。
thinking is am I ready to buy a house
我在想，我准备好买房了吗？
and then people say well if I go out and
然后人们会说，如果我出去……
invest my money the problem is housing
我的钱要投资，问题是住房。
prices keep going up I'm chasing this
价格持续上涨，我正在追赶。
housing market it keeps getting more and
房地产市场持续上涨
more and more
越来越多
expensive and you're 100% right it's a
很贵，你说得完全对，它确实很贵。
risk but there's also a risk the housing
风险，但住房也存在风险。
prices could fall I think one of the
我认为价格可能会下跌。
biases that makes people want to buy
促使人们购买的偏见
house is that they're currently renting
他们目前租住的房子
and they see that as just giving money
他们认为这只是捐钱而已。
away so they think listen I could spend
离开，所以他们认为听着我可以花
this money on a mortgage and I'll own
这笔钱用来还房贷，我就能拥有它了。
this thing one day or I could spend this
这件事总有一天我会做，或者我可以花掉这个
same $2,000 whatever it is on rent and
还是那2000美元，不管租金是多少。
I'm never going to own this thing well
我永远也无法真正拥有它。
I'm here in Los Angeles right now I had
我现在在洛杉矶，我之前……
to stay in a hotel that hotel payment is
入住酒店，酒店付款方式为
paying somebody's mortgage it's paying
它帮别人还房贷。
somebody's College tuition it's paying
它支付的是某人的大学学费。
for somebody's stuff when I go to a
我去的时候是为了帮别人拿东西
restaurant and I eat out I'm paying for
餐厅，我出去吃饭，我付钱。
somebody's mortgage I'm paying for
我替别人还房贷
somebody's College tuition I'm paying
我替别人付的大学学费
for somebody's bills because when you go
为了帮别人付账单，因为当你去
out and your rent that's what everybody
出去，还有你的房租，这就是大家要说的。
says I making my landlord Rich well when
他说我让房东变得很富有
you eat at a restaurant you're making
你在一家餐厅吃饭，你正在制作
that restaurant owner Rich when you go
当你去的时候，餐厅老板里奇
to a hotel you're making the the hotel
去酒店，你正在做酒店
owner Rich when I go and buy a mug I'm
老板里奇，我去买马克杯的时候
making the mug owner
让杯子主人
rich and the reality
富有与现实
is yeah it's good for to own a house but
是的，拥有一套房子当然是好事，但是
are you ready to own a house can you
你准备好拥有自己的房子了吗？
afford to own a house and what do you
买得起房子，你打算怎么办？
want to own first I rent where I live
我想先买房，我现在住的地方是租的。
right now I am making my landlord Rich
我现在正在让我的房东发财
today I also rent for my offices I am
今天我的办公室也是租的。
making my off office landlord very wrch
让我的房东非常恼火
because my office rent is very expensive
因为我的办公室租金很贵。
do you feel bad for me I hope not and
你觉得我可怜吗？我希望你不会。
this is where we have to get over these
这就是我们必须克服这些困难的地方。
these money myths that many people keep
许多人仍然抱有的这些金钱迷思
selling you that you can't build wealth
向你灌输你无法积累财富的观念
if you rent where you live you can't
如果你租房住，你就不能
build wealth if you don't get a good
即使你没有获得一份好工作，也可以积累财富。
degree that's not the way that the
学位不是那样的
system works see there's the traditional
系统运作方式，可以看到传统的
rules and then there's the real
规则，然后才是真正的
Financial education Money Rules and
金融教育、金钱规则和
again I'm not saying it's bad to own a
我再次声明，我并不是说拥有……不好。
house but it's bad to own a house you
房子，但拥有房子并不好。
can't afford how do you know if you can
负担不起，你怎么知道自己能不能负担得起
afford one well there's three parts to
买得起一个，嗯，它分为三个部分。
afford in a house you have to afford the
要想买得起房子，你就必须负担得起
down payment you have to afford the
你必须负担得起的首付
monthly payment and you have to afford
每月还款额，你必须负担得起。
the moving costs I'm going to go start
我打算开始计算搬家费用。
from the simplest one which is the
从最简单的开始
moving costs because many people don't
因为很多人不搬家，所以搬家费用很高。
Factor this in when you buy a house you
买房时要把这一点考虑进去。
got to move in and I'm not talking about
我得搬进去，我说的可不是……
the the closing costs you might have to
您可能需要支付的交易费用
hire movers which are expensive you
雇佣搬家公司很贵
might have to upgrade your furniture
可能需要升级家具
which which is expensive you might have
你可能会发现，这很昂贵。
to upgrade the house which is expensive
房屋升级改造费用昂贵。
factor that in then I want to talk about
考虑到这一点，我想谈谈……
your down payment people don't like when
你的首付，人们不喜欢你
I say this but I don't say what I say to
我这么说，但我不会对别人说我跟他们说的话。
make friends I say what I say to help
我交朋友，我说话直来直去，是为了帮助别人。
people be better with money if you want
如果你愿意，人们应该更好地管理金钱。
to afford the house you have to have at
要想买得起这套房子，你必须拥有
least a 20% down payment that way you
这样至少需要20%的首付。
actually have some Equity some skin in
实际上我持有一些股权，一些利益相关方。
the game that way you can actually
那样玩游戏你就可以真的
afford the
负担得起
house the third part is you have to
房子的第三部分是你必须……
afford the monthly payments now every
现在就能负担得起每月还款额
bank is going to have a different rule
银行将采用不同的规则。
for you banks have like the 28% Rule and
对你们来说，银行有类似28%规则之类的规定。
these other rules I have sorry just on
很抱歉，我还有其他一些规定。
that last Point why do people not like
最后一点，为什么人们不喜欢
it when you say that because it's very
你说这话的时候，确实如此，因为这非常
hard to pay a 20% down payment housing
很难支付20%的首付住房费用
is expensive you want to buy a $500,000
很贵，你想买一辆价值 50 万美元的车。
house you have to have $100,000 as a
买房你需要有10万美元作为首付
minimum for your down payment and that's
你的首付最低金额就是
extra cash okay now if we talk about the
额外的现金，好的，现在我们来谈谈……
monthly
月度
costs the simple way that I like to
成本以我喜欢的简单方式计算
follow it is you have to have a system
遵循这个原则，你必须要有一套系统。
for yourself you have to know how much
你自己必须知道多少
money you are allowed to spend how much
你被允许花费多少钱
money you need to be investing and how
你需要投资的资金以及如何投资
much money you have to be saving every
你必须每周存下很多钱。
single
单身的
month then just Factor it in so the way
一个月后，就把这部分因素考虑进去。
I like to look at it a simple rule of
我喜欢把它看作一条简单的规则。
thumb is something like a
拇指有点像
75151 plan which says for every dollar
75151 计划规定，每一美元
that you earn from here on out 75 cents
你从现在开始每人赚75美分
is the maximum that you can spend 15
最多可以花费 15
cents is the minimum that you invest 10
最低投资额为 10 美分
cents is the minimum that you save now
现在你至少可以节省几美分。
let's do the math if you know that you
如果你知道你
make let's call it $100,000 a year that
假设年收入是 10 万美元。
means the max you can spend out of the
指你可以用这笔钱花掉的最大金额
$100,000 is
10万美元是
$75,000 so if out of that
75,000美元，所以如果从中取出的话。
$75,000 you can afford your mortgage
75,000 美元，你就能负担得起房贷。
costs you can afford your food you can
你能负担得起的食物成本
afford your vacations and Life Style
负担得起你的假期和生活方式
then sure you can afford it but if you
当然，如果你买得起的话，但是如果你
can't afford that then you can't afford
如果买不起，那就是买不起。
that mortgage and the reason why I like
那笔抵押贷款以及我喜欢它的原因
to go by this rule is because some
遵循这条规则是因为某些
people are going to say I can live in a
人们会说我可以住在
small house I just want an expensive car
我想要一辆豪车，而不是一栋小房子。
and some nice vacations other people are
还有一些其他人的美好假期
going to say I want a beautiful home I
我要说的是，我想要一个漂亮的家。
don't care about the car and Vacations
不在乎车和假期
so now you can Factor it all in there
所以现在你可以把所有因素都考虑进去了。
how much can you afford out of that 75%
你能负担得起这75%中的多少？
of what you make do you think people
你认为人们会如何看待你所创造的东西？
even know how much money they spend no I
我甚至不知道他们花了多少钱。
was thinking I wonder how many people
我在想，不知道有多少人
listening right now know over the last 6
现在正在收听的内容，了解过去 6 年的情况
months the exact figure that they spend
几个月，他们花费的确切数字是多少
every single
每一个
month most people
一个月内大多数人
statistically are living paycheck to
从统计数据来看，人们往往是月光族。
paycheck so they're basically spending
他们基本上是在花掉工资。
everything or more okay 78% of Americans
一切或更好，78%的美国人
are living paycheck to paycheck which
他们过着月光族的生活。
means I make some money and I spend all
这意味着我赚了一些钱，然后把所有的钱都花光了。
of it or more there's a there's a joke
其中或者更多，有个笑话
that I like to make which
我喜欢做哪个
is in the traditional Indian culture
属于印度传统文化
people make a dollar to spend
人们挣一美元来消费
20 in the traditional American culture
20 在传统的美国文化中
people make a dollar to spend $2 through
人们赚一美元，却要花掉两美元。
the help of lines of credit credit cards
信用卡提供的信用额度
and other forms of
以及其他形式的
debt and the reason why I'm going to
债务以及我打算……的原因
take it a step back I don't think you
退一步想想，我觉得你
wanted me to go this way I'm I'm going
他想让我走这边，我这就走。
to go anywhere
去任何地方
anyway we live in what's called a credit
总之，我们生活在一个所谓的信用体系中。
based
基于
economy which means if you make $50,000
经济状况意味着，如果你赚了 5 万美元
a year you don't live off of $50,000 a
一年下来，你靠不到 5 万美元的生活费。
year at least most Americans don't
至少一年内大多数美国人不会这样做。
we live in what's called a credit-based
我们生活在一个所谓的基于信用的社会中。
economy which means you have the ability
经济能力意味着你有能力
to spend the $50,000 you earned plus
花掉你赚到的5万美元
debt because as you make more money as
因为随着你收入的增加，债务也会增加。
you have a good job you become more
你拥有一份好工作，你会变得更加
credit worthy and so as you show the
信用良好，正如你所展示的那样
bank hey I made $50,000 they'll give you
银行，嘿，我赚了5万美元，他们会给你的
credit cards they'll give you lines of
他们会给你信用卡，然后给你写字。
credit they'll give you whatever types
他们会给你各种类型的信用额度。
of debt that they can that way now you
他们现在可以用这种方式偿还债务了
can go out and spend 60,000 70,000
可以出去消费6万到7万。
$80,000 because that's what grows the
8万美元，因为那是增长所需的资金。
economy the more money you spend the
经济效益越高，你花的钱就越多。
Richer somebody else gets and so now
别人越富有，所以现在
when you live in this credit based
当你生活在这种基于信用的环境中时
economy with no Financial education
缺乏金融教育的经济体
people spend spend spend the economy
人们消费，消费，消费，经济
grows grows grows and most people have
增长，增长，增长，而且大多数人都有
no idea what hit them do you know what's
他们完全不知道发生了什么，你知道是什么吗？
really interesting is two days ago I was
两天前我的经历真的很有意思。
having a conversation with one of my
和我的一个朋友聊天
friends it was actually I did a podcast
朋友们，其实是我做了一个播客。
about Finance um recently and in there I
最近我谈到了金融方面的事情，在那方面我……
mentioned some of my friends and then
我提到了我的一些朋友，然后
they messaged me on Whatsapp and we were
他们通过WhatsApp给我发了消息，我们当时
having a chat in our group chat and I
我们在群聊中聊天，我
for the first time ever one of them
有史以来第一次，他们中的一个
asked me to guess we're very close
他让我猜我们关系很密切。
friends we talk about money we talk
朋友们，我们谈论金钱，我们谈论
about how much money we have Etc they
关于我们有多少钱等等
said guess who has the most money in the
他说，猜猜谁最有钱？
group so I went through and I did I
所以我加入了小组，并且我做到了。
think this is this person's net worth of
我认为这是此人的净资产
my five best friends and I think this is
我和我的五个最好的朋友，我觉得这是
how much cash they have now one of my
他们现在有多少现金？我的一个
friends
朋友们
who
WHO
is very what's the word I guess Frugal
非常……该怎么说呢，我想应该是节俭吧。
lives a very very simple life as I was
我过着非常非常简单的生活，就像我以前一样。
going through I go you know what this
经历这一切，你知道这
friend is this like highflying guy lives
朋友，这就像个飞黄腾达的人的生活一样。
in this aming apartment this person has
在这间漂亮的公寓里，这个人有
all these wonderful things this person's
这个人拥有所有这些美好的品质
been successful in business this
在商业上取得了成功
person's successful in crypto but you
这个人虽然在加密货币领域取得了成功，但你
know what I bet my M and I won't say his
你知道我跟我的M打赌什么吗？我不会说他的。
name I bet he's richer than everyone
我敢打赌他比所有人都有钱。
else in that chat um all of my other
聊天记录里还有我其他的所有内容
friends in the chat and so I did my
聊天室里的朋友们，所以我做了我的
little prediction and I said I bet
我做了个小小的预测，然后我说我打赌
you've got X figure and he replied and
你有X数字，他回答说，
go and said this is my current cash
然后他说这是我目前的现金
position he was richer than everyone in
他的职位使他比所有人都富有。
the chat in terms of cash combined this
就现金而言，聊天内容结合了这一点
guy lives so he lives in like a studio
他住在一个类似单间公寓的地方。
apartment he never balls he doesn't have
他没有公寓，他从来不在那里打球。
like a fancy car doesn't have fancy
就像一辆豪华轿车没有豪华元素一样。
clothes and he's richer than the entire
他的衣服比所有人都富有。
lot of my friendship group and I thought
我的很多朋友都这么想，我觉得
God there's something really important
天哪，这真的很重要
here in terms
这里指的是
of and it's it's so crazy if you if you
哦，这太疯狂了，如果你……
know the context of what I'm saying
请理解我所说的话的背景。
because I've got a friend in that chat
因为我有个朋友在那个聊天室里
who's built like a big business I've got
谁像个大企业一样建立起来的？我有
a friend like everyone in that chat runs
一个像聊天室里其他人一样的朋友
businesses is successful but they're
企业很成功，但它们
living in different ways and the one
以不同的方式生活，以及其中之一
friend who runs the smallest business
朋友经营着一家小企业
who like probably has the least income
像他这样收入可能最低的人。
is the
是
richest and over the last couple of days
最富有的，以及过去几天
it's it's so funny I was thinking about
真是太搞笑了，我一直在想……
all the dinners I bought this [__]
我买的所有晚餐都他妈的
guy and I'm like I didn't know you were
我当时就想，我不知道你是……
a millionaire like I [__] I would
像我这样的百万富翁，我肯定会……
have been paying for everything but this
除了这个以外，其他所有费用我都付了。
is really I mean if we ignore your
我的意思是，如果我们忽略你的
friends it's very easy to look fake Rich
朋友们，装出一副假富婆的样子很容易。
yeah because everybody will give you a
是的，因为每个人都会给你一个
line of credit if I want a Gucci person
如果我想要一个古驰人，就得先贷个款。
I can't afford the Gucci guess what I
我买不起Gucci，猜猜我买了什么
can buy now pay later I can open up a
可以先买后付，我可以开一个
credit card and buy the Gucci and look
用信用卡买Gucci，然后看看
like I'm rich when in reality I'm just
感觉自己像个有钱人，但实际上我只是个普通人。
making Gucci rich in fact one of the
事实上，让 Gucci 致富的因素之一是……
richest people in the world in 2023 he
2023年世界首富是他
was the richest person in the world is
曾是世界上最富有的人是
Bernard arnal he's the founder and CEO
伯纳德·阿纳尔，他是创始人兼首席执行官
of lvm or he's the founder and CEO of
他是LVM的创始人兼首席执行官，还是LVM的创始人兼首席执行官？
the company that owns Louis
拥有路易斯的公司
Vuitton and why because millions of
路易威登，以及为什么？因为数百万
people pay him to look rich when in
人们付钱让他看起来很有钱。
reality he's the one that's getting rich
事实上，真正发财的是他。
and we assume that when you make some
我们假设当你做一些
more money you got to start looking the
钱越多，你就越需要开始寻找……
part and this is that mindset shift that
一部分，也是这种思维转变的一部分。
we have to make and you know a lot of
我们必须制作，你知道很多
people resonate who come from the Indian
来自印度的人们会产生共鸣
traditional families they messaged me
他们给我发信息说，他们都是传统家庭。
saying jit I became a doctor or my wife
吉特说我成了医生，或者我的妻子
and I are doctors we make hundreds of
我和都是医生，我们每年生产数百份
thousands of dollars a year we make a
我们每年能赚到数千美元
great income but we have no savings and
收入很高，但我们没有积蓄。
no Investments and I don't know what to
我没有投资，也不知道该怎么办。
do and the reason why is we have a Range
这样做，原因是我们有一个范围
Rover and a b we have a nice house we go
罗孚和a b我们有一栋漂亮的房子，我们去
on the doctor vacations we have to look
医生休假期间，我们必须注意
the
这
part but we don't have any money left
一部分，但我们已经没钱了。
over at the end of our paychecks and
到了发薪日，一切都结束了。
it's a very easy thing to get caught up
很容易陷入其中。
in because when you make more money you
因为当你赚更多钱的时候，你
become more credit worthy banks will
银行将变得更有信誉
give you bigger loans when you make more
当你收入更高时，你可以获得更大的贷款。
money you want to spend more money and
你想花更多的钱，而且
it's very easy and you have to
这很简单，你只需要
understand how do you control that
了解如何控制这一点
spending and that's why if you follow
消费，这就是为什么如果你关注
something like 75 15 10 one of the
类似 75 15 10 的其中一个
simplest things you can do to start is
最简单的入门方法是
just always no matter what whether
无论如何，总是如此
you're making $110,000 a year or $10
你一年挣11万美元，或者10美元。
million a year you always put money
年入百万，你总是把钱投进去。
aside to invest you always put money
除了投资之外，你总是会投入资金。
aside to save and you spend whatever's
留出一部分钱，剩下的钱就都花掉。
left my friend doesn't invest the friend
我的朋友离开了，他没有投资这位朋友。
I'm talking about doesn't actually
我指的是实际上并没有
invest he just doesn't spend he like
他投资，只是不花钱，他喜欢
just doesn't spend money and he's just
他就是不花钱，他就是这样
stacked up like a million dollars in
堆积如山，价值百万美元
cash whilst earning less than everyone
收入比所有人都低，却能拿到现金
else of my five friends in that chat and
聊天室里我的其他五个朋友
it's it didn't take a long time like it
它并没有像那样花费很长时间。
took him four years or something four 5
他花了四年时间，或者差不多四五年。
years of just running this small
多年来一直经营着这家小公司
business with a couple of people when I
当我和几个人做生意时
say a small business I mean a really
比如说一家小企业，我的意思是真正的
like a small business like a business of
就像一家小型企业，就像一家企业
maybe four or five employees and he's
可能有四五个员工，他就是其中之一。
built up a million million dollars in
积累了100万美元
cash for
现金
himself because he just doesn't spend
他自己不花钱，因为他根本不花钱。
money and he lives at he doesn't have
他没钱，而且他住的地方他也没有钱。
like a an ego doesn't care if people
就像自负的人不在乎别人怎么想一样
what people think of him yet my other
人们如何看待他，以及我的其他
friends who are rning maybe five times
朋友们可能正在 rning 五次
more a month have five times less cash
每月现金流少于五倍的人，现金反而更少。
than him it's like it's it was so
比他强多了，就好像……
inspiring it was honestly so spiring
真是太鼓舞人心了，真的非常鼓舞人心。
because it it says something about the
因为它说明了关于……的一些事情
importance of saving but who the hell
拯救固然重要，但谁又在乎呢？
wants to save if I titled this podcast
如果我给这个播客起个名字，它就想保存下来。
today this something about saving no
今天这件事跟储蓄有关。
one's going to click it's not fun saving
有人会点击保存，但这可不是什么有趣的事。
isn't exciting who wants to go out and
谁会想出去玩呢？这不令人兴奋。
save $2,000 who wants to spend less
想少花钱的人可以省下 2000 美元
money we want to buy more nice things
我们想用这些钱买更多好东西。
but unless he can control the spending
但除非他能控制支出。
unless you know how to save you will
除非你知道如何省钱，否则你就会
never build wealth do you know for
你知道吗，千万别积累财富。
people that are in that paycheck to
那些拿着那份薪水的人
paycheck cycle which I was in for many
我经历了很长一段时间的工资发放周期。
many years of my life where I'd get paid
我生命中的很多年都是在领取报酬的。
for my call center I'd go and spend the
为了我的呼叫中心，我会去花时间
money I'd pretty much spend all the
我几乎会把所有的钱都花光
money within the first couple of days of
头几天就能拿到钱
getting the paycheck and I was just
拿到工资支票的时候，我就……
waiting the next three weeks for the
接下来三周要等待
next
下一个
paycheck what advice would you give them
薪水方面，你会给他们什么建议？
about getting out of that cycle because
想办法摆脱那种恶性循环，因为
it because you almost feel imprisoned by
因为你几乎感觉自己被囚禁了。
that cycle if you're absolutely well
如果你身体完全健康，那么那个周期就适合你。
before I give the advice I want to
在我给出建议之前，我想说的是……
explain to that person what's happening
向那个人解释发生了什么事。
because you are the Prime customer for
因为您是Prime客户
our economic system Banks love you
我们的经济体系，银行爱你
because they can sell you payday loans
因为他们可以向你出售发薪日贷款。
they can sell you credit cards they can
他们可以卖给你信用卡，他们可以
sell you lines of credit and they can
他们会向你推销信用额度，而且他们可以
keep you in debt for the rest of your
让你余生都背负债务
life which means you keep making the
生活意味着你要不断地创造
bank Rich corporations love you because
银行和富裕企业都喜欢你，因为
you're not going to think twice when we
当我们
show you this nice bag when we show you
我们向您展示这款漂亮的包包时，也会向您展示它。
this nice vacation you're going to want
你一定会想要这次美好的假期
the stuff and so we love selling you the
这些东西，所以我们很乐意卖给你。
stuff the government loves you because
政府喜欢你的原因
you're going to pay the highest
你将支付最高价格。
taxes employees pay the highest
员工缴纳的税款最高
taxes and so when you're in that
税收，所以当你身处其中时
situation you are making everybody else
你给其他人造成的局面
Rich at your
富足
expense and so if you want to break out
费用高昂，所以如果你想突破
of this the first thing you got to
这是你首先要做的事情
understand you need to make yourself
明白你需要让自己变得优秀
rich before you make everybody else Rich
在你让其他人也变得富有之前，你首先要自己变得富有。
because when you're spending all your
因为当你把所有的……
money you are putting your money into
你把钱投入的资金
their pockets and you have to stop that
他们的口袋，你必须阻止这一切。
you got to keep that money for yourself
你得把那笔钱留给自己。
you're in a boat think of it this way
你现在在一条船上，不妨这样想：
you're in a boat and this boat has water
你在一艘船上，这艘船上有水。
just flowing in and you are sinking and
就像水流一样涌入，你正在下沉。
you got to start by sealing the holes
首先要把孔封住。
you got to stop the water leaving this
你必须阻止水从这里流走。
you got to stop the water coming in you
你必须阻止水涌进来。
got to stop the bleeding and that means
必须止血，这意味着
you got to stop the
你必须阻止
spending so if you are in what I call
所以，如果你处于我所说的消费水平，那么你就会明白我的意思。
the financial danger zone which is you
金融危险区就是你
don't have $2,000 saved up for an
我没有攒够2000美元来买……
emergency and you have credit card debt
紧急情况下，你还有信用卡债务
if you are in that situation you are in
如果你处于那种境地，你就身处
the financial danger zone and you have
你已经身处金融危险区，而且你还有
to make drastic changes that means right
做出剧烈的改变，这意味着正确
now no more eating at restaurants no
现在不能再去餐馆吃饭了
more vacations
更多假期
no more doing anything that doesn't put
不再做任何无益的事情
money in your pocket and no more Netflix
口袋里有钱，再也不用看Netflix了。
no and the reason why I say this isn't
不，我这么说的原因并非如此。
because you're going to save $15 a month
因为你每月可以省下15美元。
it's so you can save two hours of your
这样可以节省你两个小时的时间。
time a day the average American is
美国人平均每天有多长时间
watching more than two hours of
观看超过两个小时
Television a day and if you don't have
每天看电视，如果你没有
$2,000 saved up if you have credit card
如果你有信用卡，就能攒下 2000 美元。
debt you cannot afford those 2 hours a
你负担不起那2个小时的债务
day being wasted on TV and that means
一天都浪费在看电视上了，这意味着
right now you have to go out and start
现在你必须出去开始行动。
using the time to learn start using the
利用这段时间开始学习使用
time to work and start using the time to
是时候开始工作并利用时间了
make some extra dollars so what do you
想赚点外快，你会怎么做？
do start selling stuff stop spending
开始卖东西，停止消费
money selling stuff you own selling
出售自己拥有的物品来赚钱
stuff you own so if you have a TV that
你拥有的东西，比如如果你有一台电视机……
you're not using sell it you have a car
你没打算卖掉它，你有辆车。
that you can't afford sell it if you're
如果你买不起，就卖掉它。
living in a house that you can't afford
住在自己负担不起的房子里。
sell it downgrade move
卖出降级
smaller and then work to earn more money
先从小规模做起，然后努力赚更多的钱
I've got to say the couple of things
我必须说几件事
that I came to mind is you were saying
我想到的就是你刚才说的话
that and funnily enough I put myself in
有趣的是，我把自己置于……
the shoes of 18-year-old Steven Bartlett
18岁史蒂文·巴特利特的鞋子
when I was in that small apartment with
当我住在那间小公寓里的时候
three or four immigrants in Mosside rush
莫赛德涌入三四个移民
home and I was you know my rent was
我当时在家，你知道我的房租是
nothing my rent was a 1 15 a month which
没什么，我的房租是每月1.15英镑，
I could not afford and I could not pay
我负担不起，也付不起。
and I was intermittently working between
我断断续续地在两地之间工作。
call center jobs and whatever money I
呼叫中心工作以及我挣的钱
got I spent and part of the reason I
我花了很多钱，部分原因是……
spent it just pre is because like many
只是提前花掉了，因为像许多人一样
people watching especially men who
人们围观，尤其是男性。
sometimes feel the need because of the
有时因为……而感到需要
way Society is I was trying to get laid
社会现状，我当时正试图找人上床
at the same time and it's hard yeah when
同时，这确实很难，是的。
you're a young man and I say young men
你是个年轻人，我说的是年轻人
in particular because the stats do
尤其因为统计数据确实如此
support the fact that there is an
支持存在以下事实
expectation that men pay um when you're
期望男人在你……的时候付钱
a young man it's particularly difficult
对年轻人来说尤其困难。
to do all of these things to cut back
做所有这些事情来减少
and also get laid and what am I going to
而且还能上床，我该怎么办？
do defer getting laid for 10 years when
推迟性生活十年
I say laid I'm really saying meeting
我说“躺下”，其实我说的是“见面”。
someone and falling in love and having a
和某人坠入爱河，并拥有一个
having a life so what do I if I if I'm
我有自己的生活，那我该怎么办？如果我……
living in a shoe box which I was I can't
我以前住在鞋盒里，我不能
bring anyone back there I can't take
我不能把任何人带回去。
anyone for dinner I can't take anyone to
有人想来吃晚饭吗？我不能带任何人去。
the movies so what do I do and this is
电影，那我该怎么办？这就是……
why every Indian parents tell their kids
为什么每个印度父母都会告诉他们的孩子
to become a doctor so their son can get
为了让儿子能获得医疗资格，他们想成为医生。
married it's the same concept but here's
已婚也是同样的道理，但这里是……
the thing you have to pick your hard
你必须选择你的硬汉。
either life's going to be hard now or
要么以后生活会很艰难，要么
it's going to be hard for the rest of
这对其他人来说将会很困难。
your life and you have to pick what's
你的人生，你必须做出选择。
more important to you right now and you
对你来说，现在更重要的是你
know if we talk about balance if you
如果您知道我们谈论的是平衡，那么您会怎么说？
want to have a balance of everything
想要在各方面都达到平衡。
where you wna find a girl and you want
你想在哪里找个女孩？
to make money and you want to stay
你想赚钱，并且想留下来
healthy you are dividing your attention
健康的你正在分散注意力
everywhere not saying it's impossible
并非到处都说这不可能
but very few people can actually do
但实际上能做到这一点的人寥寥无几。
everything all at
一切都在
once and if your number one goal is to
一次，如果你的首要目标是
become wealthy if your number one goal
如果你的首要目标是致富，那么你就能实现这个目标。
is to turn your finances around you have
扭转你的财务状况，你需要……
to get serious about it
认真对待这件事
because where you put your attention is
因为你把注意力放在哪里，
where you get the results and so if you
你可以在哪里获得结果，所以如果你
want to be in a better financial
想拥有更好的财务状况
situation you are going to have to make
你将不得不面对的情况
sacrifices and difficult I can't come
牺牲和困难，我无法前来
here and tell you it's going to be easy
在这里告诉你，这很容易。
yeah because that's going to be me lying
是啊，因为那样我就等于撒谎了。
to you I got to be honest I did make a
说实话，我确实做了一件
sacrifice and for me the sacrifice was I
牺牲，对我而言，牺牲就是我
started a business and frankly that
创办了一家公司，坦白说，那
meant that I didn't have time to be
这意味着我没有时间……
going out getting laid or meeting people
出去寻欢作乐或结识人
or socializing but it's it my story arc
或者社交，但这就是我的故事线
ends with it going well and then the
最后一切进展顺利，然后……
Romantic situation taking care of itself
浪漫情愫自然而然地浮现。
many years later once it had gone well
多年以后，当一切进展顺利时
because I was so focused on myself and
因为我当时太关注自己了
it's funny there is a bit of a paradox
有趣的是，这里存在一点悖论。
to life that the more you actually Focus
生活就是如此，你越专注于此。
inward the more you become a magnet yeah
你越向内，就越像一块磁铁，是的。
um and the more I focused outward the
嗯，而且我越是把注意力放在外面……
more I pursued and chased and sort of
我越是追求、追逐，就越是……
neglected myself the the more harder it
越是忽视自己，就越难做到。
was to get people interested in me yeah
是为了引起人们对我的兴趣，是的。
and you know I I also want to say that
你知道，我还想说的是……
when I talk about Building Wealth I'm
当我谈到积累财富时，我
not talking about becoming a money
不是说要成为金钱
hungry just money greedy this is evil
贪婪，唯利是图，这是邪恶的。
person that just cares about money
只关心钱的人
that's not what I'm talking about
我说的不是这个。
because I want you to live a holistic
因为我希望你过上一种整体的生活。
life because money is just one part of
因为金钱只是生活的一部分
your life but the second part to that
你的生活，但第二部分是这样的。
yes I'm not telling you to never enjoy
是的，我不是说你永远不要享受。
life I'm telling you to make a sacrifice
我告诉你，人生需要做出牺牲
for a period of your life that way you
在你的人生某个阶段，你会那样做。
can enjoy the rest of your life and
可以享受余生，
never have to worry about money again
从此再也不用为钱发愁了
it's hard for us to naturally see life
我们很难自然地看到生命。
for Seasons especially when we're
尤其对于四季而言，当我们
looking forward when we're looking back
当我们回顾过去时，也在展望未来。
it's very easy to say oh that was that
说“哦，那件事就到此为止了”很容易。
season like I can sit here now and say
就像我现在可以坐在这里说的那样
oh that 20 to 25 was that sacrifice
哦，那20到25岁就是那份牺牲
everything in my life to make myself
我生命中的一切都是为了成就我自己
something season and then 25 to 30 was
某个季节，然后是25到30岁。
like building and learning and then I I
就像建造和学习，然后我
now you know can can think of it's
现在你知道了，你可以想想它。
easier actually now to think forward in
现在更容易展望未来了。
Seasons now that I've been through some
现在我已经经历了一些季节了。
Seasons but for someone that's hasn't
四季，但对于一个没有经历过的人来说。
been through seasons in life it's hard
人生总有起伏，这很艰难。
to think about life in those terms I now
现在回想起来，如果用那种方式思考人生，我会……
think of my life in these fiveyear
想想我这五年的生活
Seasons MH and that helps me to say to
Seasons MH，这让我能够说……
you even have conversation with my
你甚至还和我聊天
partner where I go this is the season
伙伴，无论我去哪里，这都是季节
I'm in um and it'll last probably
我明白了，而且这种情况可能会持续下去。
roughly this this long and I'm going to
大概这么长，我打算
sacrifice these things and prioritize
牺牲这些，优先考虑其他事情
these things in this season mhm but um
本季的这些事情，嗯，但是……
it's hard for people to understand this
人们很难理解这一点。
idea it's difficult and that sacrifice
这个想法很难，而且需要牺牲
is difficult especially during a time
尤其是在这段时间，这很困难。
where everybody's showing off everything
每个人都在炫耀一切
on Instagram you look at your friends
在Instagram上，你会看看你的朋友们
who have a crappy job but they're
他们有一份糟糕的工作，但他们
driving around in nicer cars going on
开着好车到处兜风
better vacations going to the nicer
去更美的地方度假，会更好。
restaurants and you're thinking what did
餐厅，你心想：这是什么？
I do wrong and then especially if you're
我做错了，尤其是如果你……
a guy you have a girlfriend you have a
一个男人，你有女朋友，你有一个
wife she's going to say how come they
妻子会问，为什么他们
keep get to go can they keep getting go
继续前进，他们能继续前进吗？
to Cancun they keep going to these nice
他们一直去坎昆，去那些漂亮的地方。
restaurants how come you can't take me
餐厅，为什么你们不能带我去？
to these nice places and now you feel
去到这些美好的地方，现在你感觉
like you're doing something wrong
感觉自己好像做错了什么事。
because where is this discrepancy the
因为这种差异究竟在哪里？
reason why I call my show the minority
这就是我把我的节目称为“少数派”的原因
mindset is because I'm a big advocate of
之所以会有这种心态，是因为我非常支持……
not doing what the majority of people do
不做大多数人做的事
the first time I made a million dollars
我第一次赚到一百万美元的时候
in a year I was in my 20s I was driving
在我二十多岁那年，我开车了。
a car worth
一辆价值
$500 it didn't have a bumper on it it
500美元，它没有保险杠。
was not
不是
pretty my wife sat in the car with me
我妻子和我一起坐在车里。
and my employees drove better cars than
我的员工开的车比别人的都好。
I
我
did
做过
so you know you got to be
所以你知道你必须是
confident and you got to work for
自信，你得努力工作
something bigger and you want a partner
想要更大的目标，你需要一个伴侣
that's going to understand that that's
他会明白这一点。
my
我的
belief which is not the easy
信念并非易事
thing it's interesting because
我觉得这很有趣，因为
confidence is such a internal thing and
自信是一种内在的东西，
I just feel like I just probably just
我感觉我可能只是
didn't have it then cuz I I I think I
当时没有，因为我觉得我
was scared for someone to know that I
我害怕别人知道这件事
was broke I was so scared to know for
我破产了，我害怕知道真相。
someone to know that I was broke that I
让别人知道我当时很穷
just didn't entertain romantic
就是不感兴趣浪漫
relationships and that is the reason why
人际关系，这就是原因。
so many people will go into debt to buy
所以很多人会负债购买
vacations to buy things to buy stuff to
度假是为了买东西，为了买东西
look rich and ironically that's the
看起来很富有，讽刺的是，那正是……
thing that keeps so many people poor for
导致许多人贫困的原因
the rest of their life is because
他们余生都是因为
they're scared to look broke and now
他们害怕显得穷困潦倒，现在
when you try to look rich that's the
当你试图让自己看起来很富有时，那就是……
thing that's actually keeping you broke
真正让你破产的原因
there's another element to this which is
这件事还有另一个因素，那就是
my life was pretty miserable so when you
我的生活相当悲惨，所以当你
have
有
a relatively miserable life when you
当你过着相对悲惨的生活时
don't have many nice things CU you're
没什么好东西，你好。
working in a call center as I was until
我之前一直在呼叫中心工作，直到
11:00 at night time doing overtime every
晚上11点还在加班
overtime hour I could get then because
那时我可以获得加班费，因为
you're all so lonely you're going home
你们都太孤独了，所以要回家了。
alone walking home because you can't
因为你无法独自步行回家
afford the
负担得起
bus anything that gives you a little
任何能给你一点好处的东西
dopamine hit gambling this is why all
多巴胺刺激赌博，这就是为什么所有
the gambling shop are in the areas that
赌博场所位于以下区域：
struggle the worst financially because
经济上最艰难，因为
those I mean a lot of people say because
我的意思是，很多人都这么说，因为
those people are looking for that you
那些人正在寻找你
know that big payday that dopamine hit
知道那次多巴胺飙升带来的大收益吧
from a Payday um my TV in my tiny tiny
从发薪日开始，嗯，我的电视在我小小的
little bedsit room was like half the
小单间公寓就像一半那么大
size of the wall I was making Reckless
我正在建造的墙的尺寸是鲁莽的
spending decisions because I think it
消费决定，因为我认为
gave me some kind of hit that I I was
给了我某种打击，我当时
missing in my life it gave me like a
我生命中缺失的那一部分给了我一种……
dopamine Rush that was and there wasn't
那种多巴胺激增的感觉曾经存在过，但后来消失了。
many things giving me a dopamine hit at
很多事情都能让我获得多巴胺的刺激。
that point in my life and see here's the
我人生中的那个阶段，你看，就是这样
thing during that time you are making
在那段时间里，你正在做的事情
emotional decisions yes as many people
是的，许多人都会做出情绪化的决定。
are and it's very difficult to speak
是，而且很难开口说话。
logic to
逻辑
emotion but this is where now you have
情绪，但这就是你现在所处的位置
to be able to understand the difference
能够理解这种差异
because if you're listening to this and
因为如果你正在听这段话，而且
you're in that
你身处其中。
situation you have to understand that if
你必须明白，如果
you want to continue being able to live
你想继续活下去
that lifestyle you're going to have to
你必须接受那种生活方式
make some changes today otherwise you're
今天就做出一些改变，否则你就会……
going to be stuck in this lifestyle for
我将被困在这种生活方式中
the rest of your life and it's only
你余生都将如此，而且这只是
going to get more difficult
难度会越来越大
and that's the thing is if you want to
关键在于，如果你想……
become wealthy the first part is just
致富的第一步仅仅是
your own mindset it's your own
你的想法，那是你自己的。
discipline and until tell you can
自律，直到你被告知可以
conquer that I can tell you everything
克服这一点，我可以告诉你一切
about investing I can tell you different
关于投资，我可以告诉你一些不同的说法。
ETFs and index funds to invest in I can
我可以投资哪些ETF和指数基金？
tell you different investment
告诉你不同的投资方式
institutions out there I can tell you
我可以告诉你，外面的那些机构……
which stock brokerages to use I can tell
我可以告诉您应该使用哪些股票经纪公司。
you just invest 15% of your income into
你只需将收入的15%投资于
this for the next 10 20 30 years and
这种情况将持续未来10年、20年、30年，并且
you're going to become wealthy but until
你将会变得富有，但在此之前
you can get over that mindset you're
你可以克服那种心态。
never going to become wealthy because
我永远不会变得富有，因为
then what happens in that sit a is when
那么，在这种情况下会发生什么呢？
you're in that state
你处于那种状态
of I just want to look rich I just want
我只是想看起来很有钱，我只是想
to have that dopamine I just want to
我只想获得那种多巴胺。
have some nice things because I deserve
给我一些好东西吧，因为我值得拥有。
it I work hard you know what happens
我努力工作，你知道会发生什么吗？
next you the one that gets caught up in
接下来是你，那个被卷入其中的人
all the get-rich quick schemes because
所有快速致富的计划都是如此，因为
someone's going to say
有人会说
look put $1,000 into this you'll have
瞧，你往这上面投1000美元，你就会拥有
$10,000 in the next three months or I'm
未来三个月内给我1万美元，否则我就……
going to show you you can live the
我会向你展示你可以过上怎样的生活
laptop lifestyle you can work 5 hours a
笔记本电脑生活方式，你可以每天工作 5 小时
week make $10,000 a month $10,000 a week
每周赚 10,000 美元，每月 10,000 美元
you're never going to have to worry
你永远不必担心
about money again just buy this
又说到钱了，就买这个吧。
program and now you're a prime candidate
这个项目，现在你是一名非常理想的候选人。
because now you were driven by this
因为你现在被这个驱动了。
emotion of I want that I can't imagine
我想要的那种情感，我无法想象。
if I had an extra $10,000 a month and I
如果我每月有额外的1万美元，而且
don't even have to work for it because
甚至不用努力就能得到，因为
you can't see past it you're all you're
你看不见它之外的东西，你就是你。
doing is being sold by emotion and So
行动是受情绪驱使的，因此
you you're the one that's going to get
你，你才是那个会得到它的人。
caught up in the get-rich quick schemes
陷入快速致富计划
you're the one that's going to make the
你才是最终的决定者
bank Rich because you're going to get
银行存款会让你变得富有，因为你将会获得
stay stuck in debt corporations are
深陷债务泥潭的公司
going to love you because they can keep
他们会爱你，因为他们可以保持
selling you the nicest the newest stuff
我们出售最优质、最新的商品
because you want to look rich you want
因为你想看起来很有钱，所以你想
to show it off to your friends you want
你想向你的朋友炫耀一下
to show it off to the
为了向……炫耀
girls and you get stuck in that cycle so
女孩们，你很容易陷入那种循环。
I want to talk about what the money
我想谈谈钱的事。
mindset is but just on that thing you
心态就是你关注的那件事。
just said there you said get rich quick
你刚才说了，你说要快速致富。
schemes
方案
crypto what's your point of view on
你对加密货币有什么看法？
cryptocurrencies and investing in
加密货币及投资
crypto so I'll tell you where I invest
所以我会告诉你我投资了哪些加密货币。
my money so you can understand I put my
我的钱，所以你明白我把我的钱放进去了
money in five places I put my money into
我把钱放在五个不同的地方。
my own business I invest my money into
我投资自己的事业
real estate and inv my money into stocks
投资房地产，并将资金投入股票。
I invest my money into speculative
我把钱投资于投机性投资
assets which includes cryptocurrency and
资产包括加密货币和
then I own some physical gold so
那么我就拥有一些实物黄金了。
starting with my own business I run a
从我自己的公司开始，我经营着一家
company called briefs media we're
我们是一家名为 Briefs Media 的公司
probably most known for our Market
我们最出名的可能是我们的市场
briefs newsletter where we break down
简讯简报，我们将为您详细解读
what's happening in the financial
金融界发生了什么？
markets so that's briefs media number
市场，所以这就是简报媒体数量
two is I invest in physical real estate
第二点是我投资实体房地产。
so I'm going out to buy rental
所以我打算出去买房租房。
properties that I can use to generate
我可以用来生成的属性
cash flow number three I invest in
我投资的第三笔现金流
stocks this is in the form of investing
股票投资就是以这种形式进行的。
in in individual companies and investing
在个别公司和投资方面
in funds funds are ETFs index funds
基金中的基金包括ETF和指数基金。
mutual funds where you can get
您可以购买共同基金
investment into a broad basket of
投资于广泛的投资组合
companies number four is my speculative
第四家公司是我的推测
Investments notice how I said number
投资，请注意我说的是数字。
four this is one of the smallest pieces
第四，这是最小的部件之一。
now which are things that I believe can
现在，我认为可以做到以下几点：
go up very quickly but can also fall
上升速度很快，但也可能下降
just as fast so the speculative assets
投机性资产也同样迅速地涌现。
which make up a small piece of my
这构成了我生活的一小部分。
portfolio include things like startups
投资组合包括初创公司等。
that I invest in it also includes things
我投资的也包括一些东西。
like
喜欢
cryptocurrency and then I own a little
然后我持有少量加密货币。
bit of physical gold physical gold makes
少量实物黄金，实物黄金构成
up about 2% of my
上升了大约 2%
portfolio but going back to
投资组合，但回到
cryptocurrency because that's what you
加密货币，因为那就是你
asked I think it is a speculative
有人问，我认为这只是推测。
investment I have made a ton of money in
我通过投资赚了很多钱
cryptocurrency uh and I started buying
加密货币，然后我就开始买了
cryptocurrency before it was as popular
在加密货币流行之前
as it is today I began buying it in uh
就像今天我开始购买它一样……
2016 or so when Bitcoin was around 3,000
大约在2016年，当时比特币的价格在3000美元左右
maybe 2016 2017 when Bitcoin was around
或许是2016、2017年比特币兴起的时候。
$3,000 a coin and I have sold some and
每枚硬币售价 3000 美元，我已经卖出了一些。
for me I understand it can go up very
就我而言，我知道它可能会大幅上涨。
fast but it can fall just as fast and
它上升得很快，但下降的速度也一样快。
the issue that I have is when people now
我遇到的问题是，当人们现在
want to get into this idea of investing
想深入了解一下投资这个概念。
because now they're in this tough
因为他们现在处境艰难。
situation I'm living paycheck to
我现在的情况是月光族。
paycheck and I hear about this financial
我拿到工资后，就听说了这笔财务问题。
education and investing if I just dump
如果我只是抛售，教育和投资就无从谈起了。
my money into Bitcoin or crypto maybe
我可能会把钱投资到比特币或其他加密货币上。
it'll 10x and it'll have Financial
它会增长10倍，而且它会有财务方面的优势。
Freedom and that that's where I have
自由，而这正是我所拥有的。
issue because you're taking your money
问题在于你要拿走你的钱
and you're going for your long-term
你的目标是长期的
investments into a speculative asset
对投机性资产的投资
that hasn't been proven maybe it will
这一点尚未得到证实，也许会如此。
work and you'll become a
努力工作，你就会成为一个
multi-millionaire maybe you'll lose
身家数百万美元的人，也许会输。
everything but I don't want to gamble
什么都行，但我不想赌博。
with my wealth I want to build my wealth
我想用我的财富来积累财富。
with something established and then use
先建立一些东西，然后再使用
the speculative assets as something that
投机性资产作为一种……
is speculative and treated as such in
是推测性的，并被视为推测性的。
terms of your net worth then how is it
就你的净资产而言，情况如何？
broken down in terms of percentage
按百分比细分
between these five things so if we look
在这五件事之间，如果我们看一下
at real estate real estate is probably
房地产行业可能
close to almost 50% of my investments
接近我投资额的50%。
okay stocks make
好的股票
up probably right around
大概就在附近
30% speculative is about 18% of my
30%的投机性投资约占我总投资的18%。
portfolio soorry just the 30% how much
投资组合，抱歉，只有30%，多少钱？
of that is into individual company
那是进入单个公司
stocks versus ETFs it's about half and
股票与ETF相比，大约各占一半。
half okay so 15% each okay cool and then
一半可以，所以每人15%，好的，酷，然后
versus startups it was a lot more crypto
与初创公司相比，加密货币的使用率要高得多。
now it's a lot more startups I sold a
现在我卖出的创业公司多了很多。
chunk of Bitcoin when it was breaking
比特币破裂时的一小块
record highs and I'm going to be using
创纪录的高点，我将使用
that money to buy some more rental
那笔钱可以用来买更多的出租房
properties okay and gold about 2% of my
房产状况尚可，黄金约占我总资产的2%。
portfolio
文件夹
Okay and the reason why I buy gold I
好的，我买黄金的原因是……
don't myself don't consider gold an
我自己并不认为黄金是
investment I look at gold as a way of
我认为投资黄金是一种……的方式
saving hard money because my
省钱是因为我
theory is if I take $10,000 of cash and
理论上讲，如果我拿走10000美元现金，
I take 10 ,000 worth of physical gold
我取价值10,000美元的实物黄金
and I bury both of these things in my
我把这两件事都埋在了我的……
backyard today in 10 years what's going
今天后院的样子，十年后会变成什么样？
to have more buying power my theory is
我的理论是，为了拥有更强的购买力，
that the gold is going to have more
黄金价格将会更高
buying power and so that's why I own
购买力，所以这就是我拥有的原因。
some physical gold for me it's this way
对我来说，一些实物黄金就是这样。
of saving Hard Cash I look at it as a
我认为，节省现金是一种……
insurance against doomsday against
末日保险
something really bad happening against
发生了非常糟糕的事情
something bad happening to our currency
我们的货币出了问题。
something bad happening to the economy
经济出现不好的情况
that's why I own a little bit of
这就是为什么我拥有少量股份的原因。
physical gold but the problem with gold
实物黄金，但黄金的问题在于
is when I own my physical gold it just
当我拥有实物黄金时，它就……
sits there in a vault it doesn't produce
它静静地躺在保险库里，却不产生任何产品。
cash flow it doesn't create new value it
现金流并不能创造新的价值。
just sits there when I invest in real
当我投资房地产时，它就静静地待在那里。
estate it produces cash flow when I
当我拥有这处房产时，它会产生现金流。
invest in stocks the companies are
投资这些公司的股票
working to produce a better product to
致力于生产更好的产品
grow the profits the gold doesn't do
增加利润，而黄金则做不到这一点。
anything what about cash do you keep a
现金方面呢？你留着现金吗？
lot of cash on hand uh cash is
手头有很多现金，呃，现金是
definitely position I I don't know about
绝对位置 I 我不知道
percentage but I always keep
百分比，但我总是保留
cash and I'm going to break this down a
现金，我会把它分解开来。
few
很少
ways because I have
因为我有很多方法。
one let's call it bucket of cash which
我们姑且称之为“一桶现金”吧，
is my emergency savings this is cash
这是我的应急储蓄，这是现金。
that is there to protect me against an
那是用来保护我免受……
emergency my personal life I also have a
我的个人生活也出现了紧急情况。
separate bucket of cash which is my
单独的现金桶，那是我的
business emergency savings then I have a
我还有一笔应急储蓄。
bucket of cash which is their to be
那里有一桶现金
invested money this is money that's
投资的钱，这是钱。
waiting to be invested in real estate
等待投资房地产
and then I have and stocks and then I
然后我还有一些股票，然后我
also have another little piece of cash
另外还有一点零钱。
that's waiting to be invested more into
这部分资金正等待进一步投入。
speculative assets so I have cash
投机性资产，所以我手头有现金
waiting to be invested in speculative
等待投资投机性
assets cash waiting to be invested in
待投资的现金资产
real estate cash waiting to be invested
待投资的房地产现金
in stocks and then I have my emergency
投资股票，然后我还有应急措施。
cash so I like to separate it all out a
现金，所以我喜欢把它们都分开存放。
second ago you said that unless you have
刚才你说，除非你有
a money mindset you're never going to be
你永远不会拥有的那种金钱观
wealthy what is the money mindset the
富有的金钱观是什么？
mindset is number one you have to
心态是最重要的，你必须……
believe that you're going to become
相信你会成为
wealthy what I like to say is you have
富有，我常说的就是你拥有
to say I will become wealthy why because
说我会变得富有，为什么？
if you don't believe you're going to
如果你不相信你会……
become wealthy it is going to be
变得富有是必然的。
impossible for you why I used to guest
对你来说不可能，为什么我以前会来做客
to teach in Detroit public schools so
在底特律公立学校教书
Detroit is a um it was a very rough and
底特律……嗯，那段时间非常艰难。
it still is rough area certain parts of
某些地区仍然比较崎岖。
it our office is in downtown Detroit but
我们的办公室位于底特律市中心，但是
there are parts of Detroit which are
底特律有一些地区是
still very rough and I suggest teach in
仍然非常粗糙，我建议边教边学。
some of the public schools there and
那里的一些公立学校和
these are kids good kids who were not
这些都是好孩子，他们并非如此。
exposed to some of the best things and
接触到了一些最美好的事物，
what I mean by that is when I would go
我的意思是，当我……
into these
这些
classrooms you'd first have to go
你首先得去教室
through multiple metal detectors there'd
穿过多个金属探测器
be police there you might have to be pat
如果你在那里当警察，你可能需要接受搜身检查。
down and when I get into the classroom
下来后，我走进教室。
I'd ask the kids how many of you have
我会问孩子们，你们当中有多少人有
two parents in a home almost nobody
两个父母住在一个几乎没有任何人的家中
would raise their hand I would then ask
他们会举手，然后我会问
how many of you work a job almost
你们当中有多少人几乎都在工作？
everybody would raise their hand and as
每个人都会举手，然后……
I got to know the students better I also
我更好地了解了学生们，我也
started to realize that these kids high
开始意识到这些孩子高
school kids some of them are already in
一些学生已经在学校了。
gangs some of them already have been
一些团伙已经……
arrested by the police some have already
有些人已被警方逮捕
been involved in these what we consider
参与了我们认为的这些事情
bad things and they are bad
坏事，它们确实不好。
things but to the kids that's just
对孩子们来说，那只是……
normal because when I talk to them about
正常，因为当我跟他们谈论……
these gangs what they'll tell me is I
这些团伙会告诉我的是……
don't have parents at home I don't have
家里没有父母，我没有
a dad I don't know my Dad my mom is
我不认识的爸爸，我的爸爸，我的妈妈是
working how am I going to eat my
上班族，我该怎么吃饭？
brothers this gang provide me some
兄弟们，这帮人给我提供了一些
comfort because there's people that are
因为有人会感到安慰
around me they give me food they help
我周围的人给我食物，他们帮助我。
give me
给我
money it's not a bad thing in their eyes
在他们眼里，钱并不是坏事。
and so when you grow up in that mindset
所以，当你在这种心态下长大后，就会产生这种想法。
it's very hard for you to think bigger
你很难进行更宏观的思考。
and so when I would come into these
所以当我进入这些地方时
classrooms I would talk about life
在课堂上，我会谈论生活。
motivation money all things and and so
动机、金钱、一切等等，所以
one of the things I'd like to do an
我想做的一件事是
exercise that I would do is try to get
我做的练习是努力获得
you to think about successful things
让你思考成功的事情
what are things that kids want a nice
孩子们喜欢什么？
car so I would ask these kids what is
所以我会问这些孩子，车是什么。
your dream car and the responses that I
你的梦想之车以及我的回应
would get were things like a Ford
会得到像福特之类的东西
Mustang or a Dodge Challenger and you
一辆野马或道奇挑战者，你
know these these nice cars but I would
我知道这些车都很漂亮，但我不会
follow up with why not a Bugatti why not
紧接着问：为什么不选布加迪？为什么不选布加迪？
a Lamborghini why not a
兰博基尼，为什么不呢？
Rolls-Royce and they would say somebody
劳斯莱斯，他们会说某人
like me can never have something like
像我这样的人永远不可能拥有类似的东西
that so I can't even dream about having
所以，我连想都不敢想拥有它。
these nice things and that was really
这些美好的事物，真是太棒了。
shocking to me I
令我震惊的是
mean that you are kind of suppressed to
这意味着你在某种程度上受到了压制
the point but not only do you not think
重点是，你不仅不这么认为
that you can achieve it but you can't
你可以做到，但你做不到。
even dream that you can achieve it you
甚至梦想着你能实现它
can't even achieve it in your own dreams
甚至在自己的梦里都无法实现
and so when you don't believe that you
所以当你不相信你
are worthy of anything more than a Ford
配不上比福特更好的车
Mustang how in the world are you going
野马，你到底要去哪儿？
to work for something nicer and I'm not
想找份更好的工作，但我没找到。
saying you have to work just for
意思是说你必须工作才能
materialistic
物质主义
things but this is that mindset shift
但这就是思维方式的转变。
that if you don't believe that you can
如果你不相信自己可以
do it you are never going to be able to
去做吧，你永远不可能做到。
do
做
it and so this is where the first thing
所以，这就是第一件事发生的地方。
is you have to say I will become wealthy
你必须说我会变得富有。
and sometimes you have to be able to
有时候你必须能够
find a taste of success and see what
尝到成功的滋味，看看会发生什么
that looks like and there are many ways
看起来是这样，而且有很多方法。
to go by doing it I mean you can just go
我的意思是，你可以直接去做。
on to Instagram and see what success
转到 Instagram 上看看效果如何
looks like to some people but you start
有些人觉得是这样，但你开始
to Define what is that success and tell
定义什么是成功并说明
yourself I will become wealthy not that
你自己会变得富有，不是那样。
I might not that I can but I will become
我或许不能保证自己能做到，但我终将成为
wealthy the second thing is money is a
富有的第二点是金钱是一种
tool and the reason why I say that is
工具，我这么说的原因是
because we've been kind of hinting at
因为我们一直在暗示……
this throughout this entire
贯穿整个过程
discussion but the reason why many
讨论，但原因有很多
people are so scared to talk about money
人们太害怕谈论金钱了。
the reason why money is such a taboo
金钱之所以成为禁忌，原因何在？
topic is because we are insecure about
之所以讨论这个话题，是因为我们对此缺乏安全感。
our own money I just want to pause there
我们自己的钱，我只想在这里停一下。
before we carry on on the money as a
在我们继续讨论资金问题之前
tour Point um it's so interesting what
旅游点，嗯，真有趣，什么
you're saying about those kids so
你是说那些孩子吗？
interesting because I was thinking as
有趣的是，我当时正在想……
you were speaking about stereotype
你刚才在谈论刻板印象。
threats and in my previous book I I
威胁，在我之前的书中我
spent some time talking about
花了一些时间谈论……
self-belief and confidence and this idea
自我信念和自信以及这种想法
of stereotype threats and some of the
刻板印象威胁和一些
studies I came across showed that if
我看到的研究表明，如果
there's a stereotype that people like
有一种刻板印象，人们喜欢
you let's say black people like me are
比如说，像我这样的黑人
bad at a certain thing let's say
比如说，不擅长某件事。
maths before they do a math test if they
如果他们参加数学测试之前先学好数学的话
reminded a black person that they were
提醒一位黑人，他们是
black just got them to tick a box saying
黑人只是让他们勾选了一个方框，说：
that they were black their performance
他们的表演很黑
on that test would drop and they did the
那次测试结果会下降，他们也确实这么做了。
same with women so if there's a
女性也一样，所以如果有一个
stereotype surrounding your ability and
围绕你能力的刻板印象
something if they remind you of that
如果他们让你想起那件事的话。
part of you before you do a test your
在你进行测试之前，先了解一下你的一部分
performance drops and really importantly
性能下降，而且非常重要
in the studies when they don't remind
在研究中，当他们没有提醒时
the black person or the woman about that
那个黑人或者那个女人
particular feature of themselves their
他们自身的特殊特征
performance is the same as everybody
表现和所有人一样
else and it's it's interesting that you
否则，有趣的是，你
say that when you're talking about money
谈到钱的时候就这么说。
that we have a stereotype threat there
我们这里存在刻板印象威胁。
we we exist in a world where we think
我们生活在一个我们认为的世界里。
people like us make a certain amount of
像我们这样的人能挣到一定数额的
money and if the stereotype threat
金钱以及刻板印象威胁
studies are true that means that I'm
研究结果属实，这意味着我是
going to show up in the world in such a
将会以这样的方式出现在世人面前
way yes that's going to bring that
没错，那肯定会带来那种结果。
amount of money about but it's not easy
金额大约不小，但这并不容易。
to genuinely
真心实意地
believe outside of your stereotype 100%
100% 相信自己不认同刻板印象
outside of the context in which you were
脱离你所处的语境
raised I went undercover in a school in
我从小就卧底潜入一所学校。
a rough area in Liverpool that was doing
利物浦一个治安混乱的地区正在发生
very poorly and I was undercover as a
情况非常糟糕，我当时是卧底……
school teacher so I was getting to know
我是学校老师，所以我开始了解她
the kids and I met this one kid and I I
我和孩子们遇到了一个孩子，然后我
remember him saying to me um about his
记得他跟我说过关于他的事。
plans for the future and I sat there and
我坐在那里，思考着未来的计划。
I said do you know any millionaires he
我说，你认识哪个百万富翁吗？
was like no there's no no millionaires
当时就想，不，根本没有百万富翁。
around here I was like have you ever met
我当时就想，你有没有见过我？
one he goes I've never ever met one and
他说：“我从来没见过这样的人。”
in that moment I his mom which it's on
那一刻，我看到了他的妈妈，就在这时
video it was a channel four documentary
视频是第四频道的一部纪录片。
I did
我做了
um he then goes but I think I want to be
嗯，然后他就走了，但我认为我想成为
a millionaire and his mom burst out
一位百万富翁和他的母亲突然爆发了
laughing she was on the sofa next to him
她笑着坐在他旁边的沙发上。
and she burst out laughing and I
她突然大笑起来，而我
remember asking her on I remember asking
记得问过她，我记得问过
her on camera saying why are you
她在镜头前说，你为什么？
laughing and she goes no there's no CH
她笑着说，不，没有CH
there's no chance so it's like
没机会了，所以就像
indoctrinated into your context your
被灌输到你的环境中
family your roots your friendship
家庭，你的根，你的友谊
networks that you can't make it so it's
你无法创建的网络，就是这样。
hard it is 100% difficult and it it
很难，这绝对很难，而且
doesn't
不
stop in any level
在任何级别停止
if for example when I told my parents
例如，当我告诉父母时
that I didn't want to be a
我不想成为一个
doctor I was told by everybody I'm
医生，大家都这么说，我是
throwing my parent sacrifice away and
抛弃父母的牺牲
that somebody like me can never make it
像我这样的人永远不可能成功
in business because I don't know
在商业领域，因为我不知道
anything about business no one in my
任何关于商业的事情，我身边的人都不知道。
family is a business person no my family
家人是商人，不，我的家人
is an investor no one in my family does
我家里没人是投资者。
this you've never learned this stuff
你从来没学过这些东西
before you didn't get into business
在你进入商界之前，你并没有涉足这个行业。
school you how are you going to do this
学校，你打算怎么做？
and I'm not saying this to compare I'm
我这么说不是为了比较。
saying this to explain that there are so
这么说是为了解释有这么多
many levels to this mindset BL
这种思维方式有很多层次 BL
block that if you
如果你阻止它，
cannot break out of this invisible
无法挣脱这种无形的束缚。
barrier you will never become successful
阻碍你成功的障碍将永远存在。
when when any employee joins my team the
当任何员工加入我的团队时
first day we make every employee every
第一天，我们让每位员工都……
single one regardless of a role do this
无论角色如何，每个人都应该这样做。
exercise it's called the nine dots
这项练习叫做九点练习
exercise and you have these nine dots on
锻炼时，你会得到这九个点。
the screen and if you go to Google you
屏幕，如果你去谷歌搜索……
can see the nine dots exercise or nine
可以看到九点练习或九
dots trivia where it's nine dots we'll
关于点的冷知识，其中有九个点，我们将
put it on the screen yes
把它显示在屏幕上，是的。
and I'm not going to spoil it but I will
我不会剧透，但我会
actually that's the only way I can get
实际上，这是我唯一能得到的方法。
it across but the way that this Exercise
它穿过，但这种练习的方式
Works is you have to in four lines touch
作品是这样的，你必须在四行中触摸
every dot on the screen without picking
屏幕上的每一个点，无需挑选
up your pen you have to touch every dot
举起笔，你必须点到每一个点。
all of these nine dots without picking
无需挑选，即可获得这九个点。
up your pen and so when you do that you
拿起你的笔，当你这样做的时候
might say well uh there it's impossible
可能会说，呃，那是不可能的。
how do you do that and so this is where
你该怎么做呢？所以，这就是问题所在。
now oh okay not going over a previous
哦，好的，不再赘述之前的事情了。
line right not well you can go over a
线对吧，你可以越过
previous line but you cannot pick up
上一行，但你不能拿起它。
your pen so if there's nine dots one 1 2
你的笔，所以如果有九个点，1、1、2。
3 4 5 6 7 8 nine yeah you have to
3 4 5 6 7 8 9 是的，你必须
connect all four dots sorry all nine
连接所有四个点，哦不，是所有九个点
dots with four lines you can't curve the
四个点组成的四条线，你不能弯曲它们
pen and you can't pick up your pen and
笔，但你不能拿起你的笔
people will say this is impossible and
人们会说这不可能，
the reason why you say it's impossible
你为什么说这不可能？
is because you have just created an
这是因为你刚刚创建了一个
invisible barrier because now if you go
无形的屏障，因为现在如果你去
outside of the box if you extend the pen
如果把笔伸出来，就超出盒子范围了。
a little bit further then you can start
再往前走一点，你就可以开始了。
to connect all of these dots and now you
将所有这些点连接起来，现在你
realize oh it is possible if I don't
意识到如果我不这样做，哦，这是有可能的
create these invisible walls around
在周围建立这些无形的墙
myself if I don't put myself in this
如果我不把自己置于此，我自己就无法做到。
invisible box and that's what we do
看不见的盒子，这就是我们所做的。
we're all conditioned to do this to some
我们都被训练成这样对待某些人。
extent if you grow up in poverty it
如果你在贫困中长大，情况会有多大？
might be that you can never become any
也许你永远无法成为任何人
level of
水平
successful if you grow up thinking that
如果你从小就这么认为，你就成功了。
you're going to beig be this thing it
你将会成为这件事
might be that you can never start a
也许你永远无法开始
business you can never become an
你永远无法成为的企业
investor if you have become an engineer
如果你已经成为一名工程师，那么你就是投资者了。
and now in your 30s you want to go out
现在你30多岁了，你想出去玩。
and do something different it might be
尝试一些不同的方法
that somebody like you can never do
像你这样的人永远做不到这一点。
something different but these are all
虽然有些不同，但这些都是
invisible boxes you see it right there
你看到的那些隐形盒子就在那里。
and that is that's why we make every
这就是为什么我们制作每一份东西的原因。
team member every employee do that on
团队成员，每位员工都要这样做
the first day because what we say is
第一天，因为我们所说的是
look we got to come here and innovate
我们必须来到这里进行创新。
and if you want to be able to innovate
如果你想具备创新能力
and do something big you have to get out
要做一件大事，你就得离开。
of your own mind and you have to be able
你必须拥有自己的思想，并且能够
to break out of these invisible barriers
突破这些无形的障碍
and so now when you go back to your
所以现在当你回到你的
question it's very difficult it is
这个问题很难回答。
difficult and so how do you do it and so
很难，那么该怎么做呢？
this goes into now your personal
这现在将进入你的个人生活。
development what I would recommend is
我建议的开发方式是
read five books on self-development
阅读五本关于自我提升的书籍
personal development and really now try
个人发展，现在真的要尝试
to implement these things into your life
将这些事情融入你的生活中
because until you can start to think a
因为直到你能够开始思考……
little bit different and you can start
有点不一样，你可以开始了
to see the world a little bit bigger
把世界看得更广阔一些
you're never going to be able to achieve
你永远不可能实现
the maximum level of wealth that you
你所拥有的最大财富水平
deserve I've just uh Gone on Google and
我应该得到……我刚刚在谷歌上搜索了一下……
found this nine dots thing which I've
我找到了这个九点图案，我已经
got here this is the nine dots you got
到了这里，这就是你得到的九个点。
it so you're telling me I've got to
所以你的意思是说我必须……
connect all of the dots without lifting
无需起身即可将所有点连接起来
up my pen exactly okay let me try you
我的笔正好，让我试试。
have only four L and you can't curve I
只有四个 L，而且你不能弯曲 I
can I can only do four lines only four
我只能写四行，只有四行。
lines four straight
四条直线
lines it's not as easy as it looks come
线条并不像看起来那么容易，来吧
on Stephen show me how to do
Stephen，请教我怎么做
it so what most people do is they start
所以大多数人的做法是开始
going like this this and then now we
像这样，然后现在我们
freeze up because I don't know where I
我愣住了，因为我不知道我在哪里
can go next but the way that you do it
接下来可以继续，但你的方式……
is we're going to break the invisible
我们将打破无形的束缚。
barrier so what I'm going to do now is
障碍，所以我现在要做的是……
I'm going to start the same way I did
我打算用和之前一样的方式开始。
before but in instead of creating the
之前，但不是创建
same cut that I did last time I'm going
我这次去剪的发型跟上次一样。
to break the invisible barrier go a
要打破无形的障碍，就去
little bit further down and now I'm
再往下走一点，我现在……
going to come up like this then I'm
如果就这样出现，那我就是
going to go this way and then I'm going
我打算走这边，然后我就走
to finish it up like that you break the
就这样结束，你就打破了
invisible barrier you go beyond what you
你超越了无形的障碍。
think you can
你认为你可以
do because you blew past your own
因为你超越了自己。
expectations we have this invisible box
我们对这个无形盒子的期望
around ourselves and this is what you
我们周围的一切，这就是你所看到的。
want to be able to break out of this is
想要摆脱这种困境是
that mindset shift that you have to be
你必须转变思维方式
able to make and that's the first part
能够做到，这是第一部分
of becoming
成为
wealthy when you talked about invisible
当你谈到隐形的富有时，你就会明白这一点。
barriers it reminded me of a video that
这让我想起了一段视频，视频中描述的障碍是……
actually changed my life and it was a
它真的改变了我的生活，而且是
video of an ant some people have heard
一段关于蚂蚁的视频，有些人听说过
me talk about this video before this is
我之前说过这个视频的事。
the
这
video shows an ant and they get a
视频中出现了一只蚂蚁，它们得到了……
Sharpie pen and draw a circle around it
用记号笔在它周围画一个圆圈
and the Ant now believes that it's
蚂蚁现在认为自己是
trapped in the circle no matter what it
无论如何，都困在圆圈里
does it goes around and it checks all
它会四处巡视并检查所有项目
the to the circle it thinks that it's
它认为圆圈是
it's trapped we can see that that circle
它被困住了，我们可以看到那个圆圈
is a figment of its imagination and when
是其想象的产物，而当
I see this I think oh my God we've all
我看到这个，心想我的天哪，我们都……
got this sort of imaginary Circle drawn
我画了这样一个假想的圆。
around us and then I watched this video
在我们周围，然后我看了这个视频
of a spider so they can do the same
蜘蛛也能做到这一点
thing with a spider but the key moment
跟蜘蛛有关的事情，但关键时刻
in this video that really inspired me is
这段视频真正激励到我的是
the spider's currently trapped by this
这只蜘蛛目前被困住了。
pen right but in this video there's a
对，但在这个视频里有一个
moment where the spider accidentally
蜘蛛意外出现的那一刻
steps over the pen and when it steps
跨过笔，当它跨过时
over the pen it can never ever be
笔杆子永远不可能成为
trapped by the pen again you'll see it
你很快就会看到，你又一次被笔困住了。
in a second it's running towards WS it
一秒钟后，它就朝着WS方向跑去。
so this is like an imagin imaginary
所以这就像一个想象中的想象
barrier in its mind um and then if I
它心中的障碍，嗯，然后如果我
just bring it forward a little
稍微往前挪一点。
bit this is the moment here where it
但此刻，它
gets wow it's like a real wall it thinks
它惊叹道：“它就像一堵真正的墙！”
it's a real wall and then it gets too
这是一堵真正的墙，然后就变得太……
tight here it runs over it and it can
这里很紧，它会碾过它，而且可以
never be trapped
永远不要陷入困境
again I love that because once you break
我再次喜欢这一点，因为一旦你打破
it you can't be stabed after that you
之后你就不会被刺伤了。
realize that it's an illusion that was
意识到那只是一种幻觉
trapping you the whole time and this
一直困住你，而这
kind of feeds into what we've been
这某种程度上也契合了我们一直以来的想法。
saying about these stereotypes for me
对我来说，这些刻板印象是……
when I at a very young age when I was
当我很小的时候，当我还是个孩子的时候
able to make my first money or start
能够赚到我的第一笔钱或开始
start a business or turn an idea into a
创办企业或将想法变成现实
thing that put money in my pocket that
能让我赚钱的东西
illusion was broken forever the illusion
幻觉永远破灭了。
that the only way to become successful
这是成功的唯一途径
you said the same thing was to go to
你说过同样的话，那就是去
school get a degree get a job um and you
上学，拿到学位，找到工作，嗯，然后你
can't you can't unsee it you can't
你无法忘记它，你做不到。
unlearn it yeah you can't ever go and
是的，你永远无法忘记它。
follow that same traditional path and do
遵循同样的传统道路并这样做
that again because you saw the other
因为你看到了另一个
side
边
and until you get a taste of it you're
在你尝到它的滋味之前，你……
going to be stuck and that's where again
会被困住，那就是另一个地方了。
all success starts with their mindset
所有成功都始于他们的心态
and that's why I say I will become
这就是为什么我说我会成为
wealthy that first point though of
富有，这是第一点想法
awareness just knowing the fact that
意识到这一点，仅仅是知道……
you're trapped by something and it's
你被某种东西困住了，而且是
it's not to say that I've broken out of
这并不是说我已经摆脱了
all of my psychological barriers now I'm
现在我所有的心理障碍都已克服。
just in a new one I'm just in a new set
我只是在一个新的场景里。
of barriers I think that I can be I can
我认为我可以克服障碍，我可以
have nine figures I don't I probably
我有九位数，但我可能没有。
don't think I could be a billionaire or
我不认为我能成为亿万富翁。
or whatever at this moment and all of us
或者此刻的任何事情，以及我们所有人。
no matter how successful we think we are
无论我们自认为多么成功
are in some kind of circles in every
在任何情况下都处于某种圆圈中
stage of your life you're in some sort
你人生中的某个阶段，你正处于某种
of barrier and you
障碍和你
[Music]
[音乐]
know everything that you do now has to
知道你现在所做的一切都必须
be constantly working to shock yourself
不断努力让自己感到震惊
when I started my YouTube channel it's
当我开始创建我的YouTube频道时，
kind of funny uh I I didn't start my
有点搞笑，呃，我没开始我的
YouTube channel thinking that it was
YouTube频道认为它是
going to be big and the funny thing was
将会变得很大，有趣的是……
I always thought that I thought big I
我一直以为我胸怀大志。
think big I'm going to start a business
胸怀大志，我要创业。
I'm going to prove everybody wrong I
我要证明所有人都错了。
didn't start my YouTube channel to make
我开通 YouTube 频道并不是为了赚钱
money this was kind of a hobby for me
赚钱对我来说算是种爱好。
but I remember and I laugh at this
但我记得这件事，想到这我就笑。
now I told my brother when I started my
现在我告诉了我哥哥，当我开始……的时候
YouTube channel if I hit 100,000
如果我的YouTube频道订阅人数达到10万
subscribers I don't know what I'm going
订阅者们，我不知道我要去哪里。
to do but if I had a million subscribers
要做，但如果我有100万订阅者的话。
I'm going to shut my channel down
我要关闭我的频道了。
because there's no way it's impossible
因为根本不可能
that my channel is going to hit 1
我的频道即将达到1
million subscribers like there's not 1
百万订阅者，好像没有1个一样
million weirdos in the world I going to
世界上有数百万个怪人，我要去
want to watch this random guy on YouTube
想看看这个YouTube上的陌生人。
talk about guacamole and money right and
谈谈鳄梨酱和金钱吧
the funny thing is I started making
有趣的是，我开始制作
these videos I started enjoying making
我开始喜欢制作这些视频。
these videos because I started talking
这些视频是因为我开始说话了。
about the things that I wish somebody
关于我希望某人做的事情
would have told me
他会告诉我的
before and people started to watch and
之前，人们开始观看，
people started to actually enjoy it and
人们开始真正喜欢上它了，
share it with their friends and then we
和他们的朋友分享，然后我们
hit 100,000 subscribers and I couldn't
订阅人数达到10万，但我却无法……
believe it we hit 500,000 subscribers
难以置信，我们的订阅用户突破了50万！
and I couldn't believe
我简直不敢相信
it and then one day we hit a million
然后有一天，我们达到了一百万。
subscribers and I was like oh crap I
订阅者，我当时就想，糟了！
hope my brother doesn't remember this
希望我哥哥不记得这件事了。
promise because I don't want to shut
答应我，因为我不想关闭
this down but then we continued
这之后我们继续
growing and here I was this guy who had
不断成长，而我，就是那个曾经……
been successful I'm already investing in
如果成功，我已经开始投资了。
real estate I've had some business
我有一些房地产方面的业务。
success I broke out of this idea of
我打破了这种成功的想法
becoming a doctor and started a business
成为一名医生并创办了自己的企业
and I'm still putting these limitations
我仍然坚持这些限制。
on myself that I can't start a YouTube
我承认自己无法创建 YouTube 频道。
channel mhm why did I do that because I
频道嗯，我为什么要那样做呢？因为我
had never done that before I had never
我以前从未这样做过
seen this happen for somebody like me
我见过这种情况发生在像我这样的人身上。
before so is there anything practical
之前有什么实际的办法吗？
that someone who's currently trapped in
那个目前被困在
some kind of psychological barriers can
某些心理障碍可能
do practically to help them be more
采取实际行动来帮助他们变得更好
expansive with how they think about
他们思考方式很开阔
their life what I do and I don't know if
他们的生活，我所做的一切，我不知道是否
I recommend this to anybody else is I'm
我向其他人推荐这个，因为我
a little stubborn I'm going to kind of
我有点固执，我打算……
preface it with that is I do things
首先声明，我做事
to stick out and be different so what I
为了脱颖而出，与众不同，那又怎样？
mean by this I'm going to go back to
我的意思是，我要回去……
what I said before the first time I made
我第一次做之前说过的话
a million dollars in a year I thought
我想，一年赚一百万美元。
originally that I would be flying in
原本我打算乘飞机前往
private jets and balling out and doing
私人飞机、挥霍无度等等
all this stuff but I knew that I wanted
所有这些东西，但我知道我想要的
something different I I wanted to build
我想建造一些与众不同的东西。
this wealth but I didn't want to now
这份财富，但我现在不想拥有。
start living like everybody else I
开始像其他人一样生活
wanted to do something different so I
我想做点不一样的事情，所以我
continued living small that's why I
这就是我继续保持简约生活的原因。
continued driving around in this car
继续开着这辆车到处转悠
because everybody questioned what the
因为每个人都质疑……
heck I was doing people were wondering
哎呀，我当时在做什么，人们都在想
is just PR actually successful or is
公关真的成功了吗？还是
this guy a hoax is Just
这个人是个骗子，他只是个骗子而已。
Breath broke can you not afford a nicer
呼吸困难，你买不起更好的吗？
car and so I kind of put myself in this
车，所以我把自己置于这种境地。
position of like hearing the stuff and
就像听到这些东西一样，
wanted to really you talked about
我真的想和你谈谈
confidence I wanted to really build my
我想要真正建立的自信
confidence to be that person that did
有信心成为那样的人
something
某物
different and I I don't know I get joy
不一样，我不知道，但我感到快乐
I'm a weirdo I get joy out of that when
我是个怪人，我从中获得快乐
I graduated law
我法学院毕业了。
school I told my dad before I graduated
我在毕业前告诉了我爸爸学校的情况
law school even before that I'm only
甚至在那之前，我都只是法学院学生。
doing this for
这样做是为了
you and so when when it was my
你，所以当那是我的
graduation day everybody you know you
毕业典礼那天，你认识的每个人……
wear a nice suit and tie and you kind of
穿上一套漂亮的西装打上领带，你就会显得……
get all dressed up to go I told my dad
我告诉爸爸，我要穿戴整齐准备出门。
look I told you I'm going to get you the
听着，我告诉过你我会帮你搞定的
diploma but I'm going to do it on my
但我打算用我的文凭来完成它
terms so I decided not to wear a suit I
鉴于以上情况，我决定不穿西装。
decided to wear a very traditional
决定穿一件非常传统的衣服
Punjabi outfit called a c pajama which
旁遮普人的服装叫做睡衣，
is a a long shirt and pants and I wore
我穿了一件长衬衫和裤子。
traditional it's called a Punjabi jti
传统上，它被称为旁遮普语 jti
meaning Indian
意思是印度
shoes
鞋
and for me I just wanted to do that
而我，我只是想这么做。
because it gave me this confidence and
因为它给了我这种自信
yeah I mean people will say what the
是的，我的意思是人们会说……
heck are you wearing but for me I needed
你穿的什么衣服？但我需要
that burst of confidence that I'm doing
我正在做的那股自信爆发
this for me and
对我来说是这样。
I I get fueled by people questioning me
别人的质疑会激励我。
and you have to find what fuels you I'm
你必须找到你的动力源泉。
not first point of it's my duty to
这不是首要问题，这是我的职责。
become
变得
wealthy is that just something you say
富有，这只是你用来形容一种感觉的词吗？
out loud is there a way you can remind
大声说出来，有没有办法提醒自己
yourself of this so I I'm not a big fan
你自己也这么觉得，所以我不太喜欢这种风格。
of you know meditating on this idea of
你知道，思考这个想法……
you become wealthy I'm not a big fan of
你变得富有了，我不太喜欢这样。
this woo woo idea of I'm G become
这种“我是G”的玄乎想法变成了
wealthy I'm going come wealthy and
我会变得富有，而且
that's not how it works but what I do
事情并非如此运作，但我这样做
believe is you have to keep reminding
相信这一点，你必须不断提醒自己。
yourself and giving yourself the
让自己，并给予自己
motivation and discipline in the
动机和纪律
beginning as to why you started some
首先，谈谈你为什么开始做一些事情。
fuel as to why you started so one of the
至于你为什么开始这么做，其中之一是燃料。
things I like to talk about is what is
我喜欢谈论的事情就是……
your why
你为什么
who are you doing this for and so in our
你这样做是为了谁？所以，在我们的
office everybody has next to their desk
每个人办公桌旁边都有一个办公室。
this this tackboard where you can put
这是一块可以放置东西的软木板
pictures or whatever it might be to
图片或其他什么东西
remind you of why you're working
提醒自己你工作的意义
hard and in the beginning for me it was
很难，一开始对我来说是这样。
I was pissed off I wanted to prove
我当时很生气，我想证明
people wrong and I was angry and I don't
人们做错了事，我很生气，但我并不……
try to cuss on camera that often but
尽量不要经常在镜头前说脏话，但
here we go uh I was angry and the reason
好了，我当时很生气，原因是
I was angry is because when I
我生气是因为当我
made that decision to not become a
决定不成为一名
doctor the thing that I was
医生，我当时的情况
told was I'm throwing away the sacrifice
有人告诉我，我要抛弃牺牲品。
that my parents made and I started a
那是我父母做的，然后我开始……
business at the time I was working in
当时我从事的行业
the e-commerce world and I started a
电子商务领域，我创办了一家
sock company and so then the comments
袜子公司，然后是评论
that we get was so just PR you were
我们所得到的只是公关宣传而已。
going to become a doctor now you're
你现在要去当医生了
selling
销售
socks and it was just very just
袜子，而且非常……
reoccurring just like ah you gave up
反复出现，就像啊，你放弃了
your dream dreams you gave up all the
你放弃了所有的梦想
sacrifices that your family did you
你的家人为你做出的牺牲
don't even appreciate the things the
甚至都不懂得珍惜这些东西
sacrifices and now you're just going to
做出牺牲，现在你却要……
sell socks on the
在……上卖袜子
internet
互联网
and that was my
那就是我的
fuel
燃料
because I knew I don't know how but I
因为我知道我不知道怎么做，但我
knew I was going to prove you wrong
我知道我会证明你是错的
toxic fuel it 100% you know it was just
有毒燃料，百分之百确定，你知道那只是
anger just pure just anger I'm going to
愤怒，纯粹的愤怒，我要……
prove you wrong and uh slowly the
证明你是错的，然后慢慢地
business started to grow I started to be
生意开始增长，我也开始……
seen on TV and all these things started
电视上看到的，所有这些事情就开始了。
to happen and and so I was fortunate
事情就这样发生了，所以我很幸运。
that my business also flipped that now
我的生意现在也发生了翻天覆地的变化。
I'm not selling socks I'm you know
我不是在卖袜子，你知道的。
building this financial Media Company
打造这家金融媒体公司
briefs
内裤
media and now for me it's there is a
媒体，现在对我来说，情况就是这样。
purpose for what I
我这样做的目的是什么
do there's a lot of people that are
确实有很多这样的人
lacking Financial education there's a
缺乏金融教育，存在……
lot of people that are working really
很多都在努力工作的人
hard that have no idea why they can't
那些不知道为什么自己做不到的人真是太难了
build any wealth they keep hearing about
他们一直听说要努力积累财富。
how people are becoming so wealthy
人们是如何变得如此富有的？
investment levels are skyrocketing
投资水平正在飙升
billionares are becoming even richer and
亿万富翁们变得越来越富有了。
they don't understand and people just
他们不理解，人们只是
get angry when in reality you can
生气，但实际上你可以
participate in that same game and win in
参加同一场比赛并获胜
this game because our economic system is
这场游戏是因为我们的经济体系是
designed to benefit
旨在造福
investors and if you don't understand
投资者，如果你不明白
that you will never be able to win in
你永远不可能赢
the
这
system Point number two in your money
系统中的第二点，关于你的钱
mindset is that money is a tool what do
心态是把金钱当作工具，那会怎样？
you mean by money is a tool and how is
你的意思是说金钱是一种工具，那么……
that different from how everyone else
这和其他人的做法截然不同。
thinks about
思考
money you have to understand how money
你必须了解金钱的运作方式。
plays a part in your
对你来说，它起着一定的作用。
life when I say money is a tool what I
当我说金钱是一种工具时，我指的是生活中的……
mean by that is money doesn't make you a
意思是说，金钱并不能让你成为一个……
good person money doesn't make you a bad
好人有钱并不会让你变成坏人。
person it amplifies who you are and what
它放大了你是谁以及你是什么。
I'd like to say is that there are four
我想说的是，共有四个。
fitnesses in your life if you want to
如果你想在生活中融入健身元素
live a happy and fulfilled life you have
过上你拥有的幸福而充实的生活。
to be physically fit mentally fit
身体健康，精神健康
spiritually fit and financially fit if
精神健康且经济健康，如果
you're physically fit you're on your
你身体健康，你正处于你的……
deathbed you're morbidly obese having
临终之际，你因病态肥胖而痛苦不堪。
$10 million is not going to make you
1000万美元并不能让你……
happy all you want to do is be healthy
你只想健康，你真快乐！
again mentally fit is about being happy
再次强调，心理健康的关键在于快乐。
if you're surrounded by toxic people if
如果你身边都是有毒的人，
you're unhappy if you're depressed if
如果你感到抑郁，你就会不快乐。
you're anxious if you're just miserable
如果你只是感到痛苦，那你就是焦虑。
you're never going to be able to really
你永远不可能真正
enjoy life having more money is not
拥有更多金钱并不意味着就能享受生活
going to fulfill that hole spiritually
去填补精神上的空缺
fit does not mean religious it means
合身并不意味着信教，它指的是
having a purpose what is the reason for
具有目的性的原因是什么？
getting out of bed every day what is the
每天起床是什么感觉？
reason for wanting to go out and Achieve
想出去并取得成就的原因
and do something because if you have $10
然后做点什么，因为如果你有10美元的话。
million what's the reason for wanting to
百万，想要……的理由是什么？
get up and
起床
Conquer at the very top this financial
征服金融业的顶峰
Fitness and once you have the bottom
健身，以及一旦你达到目标
three having Financial Fitness gives you
三、拥有财务健康能给你带来什么？
the most power and ability to live the
拥有最大的力量和能力去生活
best life possible because this is all
尽可能过上最好的生活，因为这就是一切
about now being able to solve solve your
现在能够解决你的问题
financial problems being able to not
财务问题导致无法……
worry about paying your bills being able
担心无法支付账单
to have the nicer stuff when you want
想什么时候拥有更好的东西就什么时候拥有。
and not have to worry about the price
而且不用担心价格
and the thing about this that I want to
而关于这件事，我想说的是……
really Hammer home is if you don't have
真正的锤子之家，如果你没有
this financial Fitness now your physical
现在，财务健康就是你的身体健康
fitness can get hurt because you can't
健身可能会受伤，因为你无法做到
afford the nice gym membership you can't
你负担不起你办不起的那张不错的健身房会员卡。
afford the healthy food you can't afford
你买不起健康食品。
to take care of your
照顾好你
body if you don't have the financial
如果你没有足够的经济能力，那就放弃吧。
Fitness your mental Fitness can get
保持良好的精神状态可以让你获得良好的心理健康。
hurt financial problems are one of the
财务困境是其中之一
leading causes of suicide and divorce
导致自杀和离婚的主要原因
financial problems can really stress you
财务问题真的会让你压力很大。
out and they can cause a whole lot of
出去，它们可能会造成很多问题
anxiety and depression financial
焦虑和抑郁的经济状况
problems can also ruin your spiritual
问题也会摧毁你的精神状态。
Fitness because if you can't pay your
健身是因为如果你付不起钱
bills you can easily lose your sense of
账单很容易让你失去理智
purpose so yes being financially fit is
所以，财务健康是其目的。是的，财务健康是……
its own part but it all comes together
它本身就是一部分，但最终会融合在一起。
in your
你的
life number three to this money mindset
这是我对金钱观的第三个理解。
money is
钱是
abundant and what I mean by that
丰富，我的意思是
is you have to be willing to think
你必须愿意思考
bigger because often times what happens
更大，因为很多时候发生的事情
is we start to think about the dollars
当我们开始考虑美元的时候
that I'm giving as opposed to the
我给予的，而不是
dollars that I'm getting if I pay you a
如果我付钱给你，我能拿到多少钱？
dollar you are getting rich off of me
你靠我发财了。
but I'm not looking at what I'm getting
但我并不在意我得到了什么。
if I'm getting $2 from you well is it
如果我从你那里得到2美元，那又怎样呢？
bad that I pay you
我付钱给你真是太糟糕了
$1 no and this is right now we not just
1美元，不，现在我们不仅仅是
we need to start to understand there's a
我们需要开始明白，存在着……
lot of money in the world just because
世界上有很多钱，仅仅因为
somebody gets Rich that doesn't mean
有人发了财，但这并不意味着……
somebody else can't get rich and the
其他人就无法致富，而且
reason why we get this confused is
我们之所以会把这两件事混淆，原因是
because we assume that money is
因为我们假设金钱是
scarce and this comes from our childhood
稀缺，这源于我们的童年
because when you grow up you're fighting
因为长大后你就要战斗。
for your parents attention and there's a
请家长注意，还有……
limited attention span that your parents
父母注意力持续时间有限
have if you have siblings now it's
如果你现在有兄弟姐妹的话……
divided and so you can't have all
被分割了，所以你不可能拥有全部
attention so if they're giving your
所以如果他们关注你
parents are giving their attention to
父母们正在关注
somebody else that means you're not
其他人，这意味着你不是
getting attention it's is it's a yes or
引起关注，答案是肯定的。
no it's a black and
不，它是黑色的，而且
white but with money that's not the case
白人，但有钱人就不是这样了。
you can be rich and I can be
你可以很富有，而我可以
rich but we have to understand that
富有，但我们必须明白这一点。
there's a lot of money in the world I
世界上有很多钱。
mean the United States government has 35
意味着美国政府拥有35
some trillion dollars of debt it's a lot
数万亿美元的债务，这可不是个小数目。
of money and so if you just take a small
钱，所以如果你只拿一小笔钱
piece of that a small piece of the
一小部分
dollars out there you can build wealth
外面有钱，你可以积累财富。
and somebody else can build wealth and
其他人也可以积累财富，
why is that that particular point in
为什么是这一点呢？
this m money mindset so critical why is
这种金钱观如此重要，为什么？
it important to know that there's so
重要的是要知道，有很多……
much money out there how does that
外面那么多钱，那该怎么办？
change you so if you make $50,000 a year
改变你，这样如果你年收入达到 5 万美元。
right
正确的
now what you might start doing if you
现在，如果你开始这样做，你可能会开始做什么呢？
become financially smart is you might
变得精明理财或许会让你受益匪浅。
say all right I'm going to start living
好吧，我要开始生活了。
off of 75% of what I make and I'm going
我要拿出我收入的75%，然后离开。
to invest the other
投资其他
15% that means I'm going to live off of
15% 意味着我将靠……生活
uh 30 ,000 and save and invest we'll
呃，30,000，然后储蓄和投资，我们会
call it
就叫它
$20,000 you might now say ah I like this
2万美元，你现在可能会说，啊，我喜欢这个
idea of investing I'm seeing the
我看到了投资的想法
potential what do I do I make $50,000 a
我年收入5万美元，我该怎么办？
year how about I keep cutting back now
今年，我打算继续减少开支。
I'm going to live off of
我打算靠……生活
25,000
25,000
23,000 there's a limited number of
23,000，数量有限
dollars that you can squeeze out of this
你可以从中榨取多少钱
pie but there's no limit to how much you
馅饼，但数量没有限制。
can earn so what if I say let's flip it
能赚钱，那我说不如我们把它翻过来呢？
up a little bit how about instead of
稍微向上挪一点，不如换成……
trying to squeeze more pennies out of
试图从中榨取更多利益
this $50,000 you
这5万美元
have let's try to earn $500,000 a year
让我们努力争取年收入50万美元。
now and the first thing that's going to
现在，首先要做的事情是……
happen is you're going to say whoa whoa
事情的结果是你会说“哇哇”。
whoa $500,000 a year my boss is not
哇，我老板年薪50万美元，这可不是开玩笑。
going to give me a $500,000 a year
打算每年给我50万美元。
salary what are you talking about J well
薪水？你在说什么？嗯
okay let's break this down if you want
好的，如果你想的话，我们可以详细分析一下。
to make more money how do you do
如何才能赚更多钱？
it I don't know well let's start
我不太清楚，好吧，我们开始吧。
learning where you going to to learn I
了解你要去哪里学习
don't know Google YouTube okay let's go
不知道谷歌和YouTube，好吧，我们开始吧。
to Google and YouTube how can I make
我该如何通过谷歌和YouTube制作视频？
more money maybe you start by learning
或许你可以先从学习开始，赚更多钱。
how to ask for raise maybe you learn to
如何要求加薪？也许你会学到这一点。
get a career change maybe you learn to
换个工作，也许你能学到……
change jobs or maybe now you start to
换工作，或者现在你开始……
think a little bit different and you say
换个角度思考，然后你说
maybe you start to build a side business
或许你可以开始发展副业。
or a side hustle that way you can start
或者，你可以通过这种方式开始一份副业。
earning more money but until you realize
赚更多钱，但直到你意识到
that it's possible to instead of trying
与其尝试，不如尝试一下。
to go from 50,000 to 55,000 58,000 to
从 50,000 到 55,000，再到 58,000
65,000 let's try to go a little bit
65,000，我们试着再往前走一点吧。
bigger how about 50,000 to
更大一些，比如50,000到
500,000 and that's going to require
50万，这需要
number one you break out of that mindset
第一，你要打破那种思维模式。
shift that that that invisible barrier
改变那种无形的屏障
but also understanding there's a lot of
但也要明白，这其中有很多……
money out there and the last Point here
资金就在那里，最后一点是……
is I will become wealthy which is
我会变得富有，也就是
different to the first point which is
与第一点不同的是，
it's my duty to become wealthy so we
致富是我的责任，所以我们
discussed the first one which is I will
讨论了第一个，那就是我将
become wealthy the last one is it is my
变得富有，最后一个是我的
duty to become wealthy oh okay why is it
致富的责任？哦，好吧，为什么？
your duty to become wealthy because I
你的职责是变得富有，因为我
believe that it's up to you to take care
相信照顾好自己是你的责任。
of your family to be the one that take
让你的家人成为那个承担责任的人
cares that takes care of yourself that
照顾好自己的那种关怀
we can also help take care of your
我们还可以帮助您照顾您
community that is my belief that it is
我认为，这就是社区。
your duty to do so and if you rely on
你有义务这样做，如果你依赖于
the government or somebody else to do it
交给政府或其他机构去做
well you are asking for
你这是在问……
problems and you know we've seen this in
问题，你知道，我们已经看到这种情况了
many
许多
instances where you might have heard in
你可能听说过以下情况：
the United States Social Security is
美国社会保障是
drying up it's never going to dry up
干涸？它永远不会干涸。
because the government can just print
因为政府可以随意印刷。
more money and pay it out but it's never
更多钱，然后支付出去，但这永远不会发生。
going to be enough to live a great life
足以过上美好的生活
people that relied on pensions well
那些依赖养老金的人
pensions are becoming a thing of the
养老金正逐渐成为……
past some pensions have gone bankrupt
过去有些养老基金破产了。
and people have lost that so it is more
人们已经失去了这种能力，所以现在的情况更加……
important than ever for you to become
对你而言，成为……比以往任何时候都更加重要
financially sufficient and financially
经济上充足且财务上
stable through your own Financial
通过您自己的财务状况保持稳定
education Trump has just been elected
教育 特朗普刚刚当选
the new president of the United States
美国新任总统
of America and when you saw that news
美国，当你看到那条新闻的时候
did it change your thesis as it relates
它是否改变了你关于此事的论点
to wealth creation is there anything
创造财富有什么意义呢？
you're now going to be doing differently
你现在要采取不同的做法。
is there any new opportunities that you
是否有任何新的机会？
now see are you shifting your Capital
现在看看你是否在转移你的资本
allocation towards more risky assets or
向风险更高的资产配置或
less risky assets or real estate if we
如果我们选择风险较低的资产或房地产，
take a look at the last 15 presidents in
让我们来看看过去15位总统。
the United States some have been
美国有些人已经
Democrat some have been Republican the
一些民主党人曾经是共和党人
stock market has gone up under
股市上涨
democratic presidents it's also Fallen
民主党总统也倒台了
under democratic presidents the stock
在民主党总统的领导下，股票
market has gone up under Republican
在共和党执政期间，市场上涨了。
presidents it's also Fallen under
总统们也已沦陷
Republican presidents
共和党总统
so what does that
那么，这又意味着什么呢？
mean well if you just investing for the
如果你只是为了投资而投资，那你的本意是好的。
long term who
长期谁
cares but for some investors that we'll
我们关心，但对于一些投资者来说，我们会
call it a little bit more
不妨再多说一点
sophisticated you might want to
你可能想要更高级的
understand what the president is going
了解总统的意图
to do in terms of Shifting government
就政府更迭而言，需要做些什么
spending now I'm going to make this a
现在我要花钱，我要把它变成一个
little bit technical but let me kind of
有点技术性，但让我来解释一下。
break this down our economy is measured
分解一下，我们的经济是如何衡量的。
through a number called
通过一个叫做
GDP and GDP is a measure of all spending
国内生产总值（GDP）是衡量所有支出的指标。
that happens in our economy in the
这种情况在我们的经济中时有发生。
United States the largest spender is the
美国是最大的消费国。
government 30% of our
政府占我们30%
GDP our economy is government
我们的经济就是GDP，也就是政府
spending which means that there are
支出意味着有
certain entities certain businesses that
某些实体，某些企业
will benefit depending on where the
将受益于……
government spends money and that can
政府花钱，这可以
then impact those stocks it can impact
然后，它可能会影响那些股票。
those Industries and it can impact those
这些行业可能会受到影响。
businesses so now let's break this down
现在让我们来详细分析一下各个业务。
if you're a long-term investor you're
如果你是一名长期投资者，你
investing in the S&amp;P 500 you're
投资标普500指数，你
investing in just general ETFs and index
仅投资于一般ETF和指数基金
funds and mutual funds it does not
它不涉及基金和共同基金。
matter but if you are let's say a little
重要，但如果你，比如说一点点
bit more sophisticated you want to
你想更复杂一些吗？
understand the government shifts that
了解政府的政策转变
are happening now we can dig a little
现在发生的事情，我们可以稍微深入挖掘一下。
bit deeper so prior to the election we
更深入一点，所以在选举之前我们
published a whole report in Market
在 Market 上发表了一份完整的报告。
briefs Pro on this where what we talked
Briefs Pro 就此发表了我们的观点。
about is if Trump is elected president
问题在于，如果特朗普当选总统的话。
here are the things that he has said
以下是他所说的话
that he's going to do number one he
他要做第一件事
wants to deregulate Oil and Gas number
希望放松对石油和天然气数量的管制
two he wants to deregulate the financial
第二，他想放松金融管制。
service industry and number three he
服务业排名第三
wants to invest in the military so if
想投资军工产业，所以如果
you're break this down oil and gas these
你要把这些石油和天然气分解开来
are companies that are investing and
是那些进行投资的公司
drilling oil and so if these companies
钻探石油，所以如果这些公司
have less regulations and more ability
监管较少，能力更强
to produce product and sell more product
生产和销售更多产品
they could see bigger revenues and
他们可能会获得更高的收入，
bigger profits number two with Financial
第二大利润来自金融领域
Service Industries things like the
服务行业，例如
companies on wall Street if you
如果你是华尔街的公司，
deregulate them and give them the
放松对它们的管制，并赋予它们
ability to do more things they can make
他们有能力做更多的事情。
bigger revenues and bigger profits and
更高的收入和更高的利润
crypto as well and crypto crypto since
加密货币以及加密货币，因为
the news that he's been he's going to be
他一直都在的消息，他将会……
inaugurated the prices have just
价格刚刚公布
skyrocketed
价格飙升
exactly and number three is investing in
没错，第三点是投资。
the military now what does it mean to
现在军队意味着什么？
invest in the military well if we're
如果我们是的话，就应该好好投资军事。
investing in the military that means
投资军工产业意味着
that we're going to be practicing
我们将要练习的
shooting more guns shooting more bullets
开枪射击，发射更多子弹。
having artillery having planes and other
拥有火炮、飞机和其他
machinery and these are then done by
机器，然后由……完成
private companies and so if the
私营公司，因此如果
government can spend and choose where to
政府可以自由支配资金，并选择支出方向。
spend money and the government then
花钱，然后政府
decides that they want to spend more
决定增加支出
money or allow companies to be more free
资金或允许公司拥有更大的自由度
to do whatever they want in these
在这些方面，他们可以为所欲为。
industries those Industries then have
这些行业随后拥有
the ability to potentially grow the
具有潜在的增长能力
revenues grow their profits grow the
收入增长，利润增长
stock prices these can then create what
这些股票价格随后会创造出什么？
we call a government shift because the
我们称之为政府更迭，因为……
government spending shifts and that can
政府支出转移，这可能会
create an investment opportunity for
创造投资机会
investors that want to be a little bit
想要稍微……的投资者
more sophisticated but I'm going to say
更复杂一些，但我还是要说
this again as a long-term
这再次体现了长期性
investor forget the collection Cycles
投资者忘记了收藏周期
you're investing for the long term for
你是在进行长期投资。
those less sophisticated investors as
那些不太成熟的投资者
you were when you were 19 years old you
你19岁的时候是……
chose to invest in real estate as a cash
选择投资房地产作为现金
generating asset now if I want to invest
如果我想投资，现在就应该开始积累资产。
in real estate it's my first investment
在房地产领域，这是我的第一笔投资。
as you did what are the things that I
你做了什么？我做了什么？
should be looking out for if I'm someone
如果我是个……，那应该注意些什么？
that knows nothing about real estate
对房地产一窍不通
what kind of properties should I be
我应该拥有什么样的房产
looking for how big doesn't matter how
寻找多大并不重要
how much those properties cost am I
这些房产多少钱？
looking for family rentals studio
寻找适合家庭出租的单间公寓
apartments what kind of things matter
公寓里哪些事情比较重要
what you invest in is going to depend on
你投资什么将取决于
what's best for you but the way I like
对你来说最好的，但我喜欢的方式。
to look at it for me cuz I can't tell
帮我看看，因为我看不出来。
you what to do is for me when I invest
你知道我投资时该怎么做吗？
in real estate is I look for a 7% cash
在房地产投资中，我寻求的是7%的现金回报。
on cash return minimum what does that
现金回报最低标准是什么？
mean so if I invested a dollar today I
也就是说，如果我今天投资一美元，
want 7 cents of cash flow after expenses
扣除费用后，希望获得 7 美分的现金流。
every year for my dollar that I invest
我每年投资的1美元
so if I buy let's just call it a
所以如果我买，我们就叫它……
$100,000 house and I'm going to keep it
价值10万美元的房子，我打算留着它。
very simple we're going to have no debt
很简单，我们不会负债。
I take a $100,000 out of my bank account
我从银行账户里取出10万美元。
and I buy this $100,000 house that I
我买了这栋价值10万美元的房子，
then rent out that rent after all the
然后把租金再租出去。
expenses should then put at least $7,000
那么支出至少应该达到7000美元。
into my pocket and every year that's
放进我的口袋里，每年都是如此。
what a 7% cash on cash return means now
现在7%的现金回报率意味着什么
for me I prefer single family houses or
我个人更喜欢独栋住宅。
multif Family Apartments because that's
多户家庭公寓，因为那是
kind of where I got started and I've
那算是我的起点，而且我已经
found more success there and it's a
在那里取得了更大的成功，而且这是一个
little bit more Innovation proof because
创新性更强一些，因为
we know that offices can go up and down
我们知道办公室可能会兴衰更替。
if companies are working from home
如果公司实行居家办公
offices can be affected the retail
办公室可能会受到零售业的影响。
sector can be impacted if companies are
如果公司……，该行业可能会受到影响。
moving online and we see that there's a
转向线上，我们发现……
lot of shifts happening in the retail
零售业正在发生很多变化。
spaces but uh at the end of the day you
空间，但归根结底，你
got to find what's right for you and how
必须找到适合自己的方法和途径。
involved you want to be when I invest in
你想在我投资时参与其中吗？
real estate I want it to be passive for
我希望我的房地产投资是被动的。
me that after I find a property after we
在我找到房产之后，我们
do the renovations I want to give the
进行我想做的翻新工程
keys over to a property manager I don't
钥匙交给物业经理了，我没有。
want to have to worry about it okay so
不想为此担心，好吗？
you don't you don't become the landlord
你不会，你不会成为房东
yourself and deal with the tenants
你自己去处理和租户的事情
directly I do not and the reason why is
直接不做，原因如下：
I have all the things that I need to do
我已经把所有需要做的事情都准备好了。
and I don't want to spend my time
我不想把时间浪费在这种事情上
managing the prop property I want to
管理 prop 属性，我想要
spend my time acquiring I want to spend
我把时间花在获取我想要花费的东西上
my time investing but I don't want to
我投入了时间，但我不想……
spend my time managing what's the best
我把时间花在管理哪些方面最好上。
investment you ever made the best
你做过的最棒的投资
investment I ever made is the investment
我做过的投资就是这笔投资
of
的
myself that has given me a much better
这让我自己感觉好多了。
return than any real estate than any
比任何房地产都更有回报
stock and even than any cryptocurrency
股票甚至比任何加密货币都更胜一筹。
and when I say best investment in myself
我说这是对自己最好的投资。
is two things number one is the
两件事，第一件是……
investment that I have made in my own
我对自己的投资
education outside of school so books
校外教育，例如书籍
podcasts classes
播客课程
coaching number
教练号码
two the
两个
failures I have made a lot of mistakes
我犯过很多错误，也经历过失败。
they have caused me a lot of stress a
他们给我造成了很大的压力。
lot of headache a lot of money but they
很麻烦，很费钱，但他们
have taught me a ton so we'll talk about
教会了我很多，所以我们来聊聊吧。
real estate for a
房地产
second if we go back to the first
其次，如果我们回到第一点
condo the sunshine and rainbows is I
公寓里阳光明媚，彩虹灿烂，我
rent this property up for $600 a month
这套房产每月租金600美元。
but the downfall or the risky part and
但其失败之处或风险所在
the bad part is that I made every
糟糕的是，我把一切都搞砸了。
mistake possible number one I hired a
我犯的第一个错误可能是我雇佣了一个人
bad
坏的
contractor number two I hired a property
我雇佣的第二位承包商是一处房产。
manager which I didn't realize was a
我之前没意识到，经理是……
fake property manager we didn't even
假冒的物业经理，我们甚至都没见过。
sign a lease with the tenant I didn't
我没有和租户签订租赁合同。
even sign a contract with the property
甚至与房产签订合同
manager they weren't working with the
他们没有和经理一起工作。
tenants and they gave the tenant my
租户们把我的东西给了租户。
phone number so here I am sitting in my
电话号码，所以我现在坐在我的
organic chemistry class getting calls
有机化学课接到电话
from my tenant ten saying the property
我的房客说，这处房产
is going to implode because the light
即将内爆，因为光
bulb fused then we hired brought in a
灯泡烧坏了，然后我们雇人送来了一台
bad tenant can I ask you a question then
糟糕的租客，我可以问你一个问题吗？
how could you have avoided all of
你如何才能避免这一切？
this well I could have either number one
嗯，我两个都可以选，第一个。
had a real estate investor that I could
我曾与一位房地产投资者有过合作。
have talked to which I didn't have
我跟一些人谈过，但我之前没有跟这些人谈过。
access to I read a lot of real estate
我经常阅读房地产方面的书籍。
books so if you say what could I have
所以如果你问我能有什么书，我能有什么书呢？
done
完毕
differently to avoid it because there's
避免这种情况的方法不同，因为有
people listening right now that are
现在正在收听的听众是
going Jesus I I want to get into this
耶稣啊，我想深入了解一下。
real estate game but I don't want to go
房地产游戏，但我不想去。
through you can learn as much as you
通过你，你可以学到很多东西。
want you're going to make mistakes it is
你想犯错，就是这样。
a part of the process you can learn as
你可以学习这个过程的一部分
everything you want but every real
你想要的一切，但所有真实的
estate deal is unique you are going to
房产交易是独一无二的，你即将面对的
screw up and I have made a lot of
搞砸了，我犯了很多错误
screw-ups but once you get through the
虽然会犯错，但一旦你挺过来了
screw-ups it becomes a lot easier I call
搞砸事情就容易多了，我称之为
it the
它
hurdle but then things get even more
这只是个障碍，但事情还会变得更糟。
exciting because now I bring on a new
令人兴奋的是，我现在带来了一个新的
property
财产
manager
经理
and the tennants move out and then we
然后租户搬走了，之后我们
think everything is good and now I get a
我觉得一切都很好，现在我却……
letter Del to me hand delivered well
Del 写给我的信，由专人递送，完好无损。
this is a nice gift it says Just Breath
这是一份不错的礼物，上面写着“深呼吸”。
sing you are being
唱歌，你正在被
sued and I said
起诉，我说
what those tenants then sued
那些租户随后提起了诉讼
me because they claimed that the bathtub
因为他们声称浴缸
was too slippery when the water was
水面太滑了
on true story and now here I have this
这是个真实的故事，现在我这里有这个
lawsuit I'm
我正在提起诉讼
2122 I have no idea what's going on just
2122 我完全不知道发生了什么事
bre was the bathtubs do slippery
浴缸很滑
well I'll tell you exactly what
好吧，我会告诉你确切的情况。
happened there was a chip about the size
碰巧有一个大约大小的碎片
of a quarter in the bathtub the paint
浴缸里的一枚硬币
had chipped they filed a complaint with
他们已经提交了投诉。
my new property manager thank God I
感谢上帝，我的新物业经理来了。
switched property managers because what
更换物业管理公司是因为什么？
a good property manager does is they're
一个好的物业经理会做的是：
going to document everything that
我会把所有事情都记录下来。
happens so my property manager documents
事情就是这样发生的，所以我的物业经理文件
that okay tenant complains of a chip in
那位还算不错的租户抱怨说有人在里面搞鬼。
their bathtub we send out the contractor
我们派承包商去修理他们的浴缸
so the property manager sends out the
所以物业经理发出了
contractor they go there to fix the chip
承包商去那里修理芯片
in the bathtub and you know what the and
在浴缸里，你知道那是什么吗？
says can you come back a different time
他说你能改天再来吗？
my husband slipped and fell at a
我丈夫在……滑倒了
friend's barbecue and so we don't want
朋友的烧烤聚会，所以我们不想去。
you to fix that chip today the
今天就把那个芯片修好。
contractor says okay we note this down
承包商说好的，我们记下来。
he tries to then fix the chip three more
他随后又尝试修复了三次芯片。
times but the tenant denies it every
多次，但租户每次都否认。
single time and so we thought okay just
一次，所以我们想，好吧，就一次。
let us know when you want the chip fixed
请告知我们您希望何时修复芯片。
the contractor is waiting they never
承包商在等他们，他们永远不会
brought it up again then we get this
再次提起这件事，然后我们就得到了这个
lawsuit saying that we were negligent
诉讼称我们存在疏忽
that I'm this evil greedy human being
我是一个邪恶贪婪的人
because I refused to fix this chip in
因为我拒绝修理这个芯片
the bathtub which made the bathtub
浴缸，也就是浴缸的制造者
slippery when the water was on which
水面湿滑时，地面很滑。
caused this person to slip and fall and
导致此人滑倒摔伤
break their
打破他们的
hip and so now we go through the lawsuit
嘻哈，所以现在我们要进入诉讼程序。
process thankfully I had insurance but
幸好我有保险，但过程很艰难。
the insurance company still has to pay
保险公司仍然需要支付
for the attorney I still have to be
至于律师，我仍然需要
involved through all the
参与所有
proceedings and now they're claiming
诉讼程序进行中，现在他们声称
that because I didn't fix this chip it
因为我没修好这个芯片
made the bathtub slippery and that's
把浴缸弄得滑溜溜的，就是这样。
what caused this tenant to get hurt but
是什么原因导致这位租户受伤？
we had the documentation saying that
我们有文件证明这一点。
they slipped and fell at a friend's
他们在朋友家滑倒了。
barbecue and then we go through the
烧烤，然后我们进行……
hospital records and we found out that
查阅医院记录后，我们发现
this person slipped and fell at a
这个人滑倒了。
barbecue but they wanted to get some
烧烤，但他们想吃一些
money out of this Rich
从这位富翁那里赚到钱
landlord I'm a 22y old kid a 21- year
房东，我是一个22岁的年轻人，一个21岁的年轻人
old kid I have no idea what's going on
老家伙，我完全不知道发生了什么。
and so the insurance company had to
因此，保险公司不得不
settle they paid
他们支付了和解金
$144,000 to make the case go away it's
支付14.4万美元就能摆平这起案件。
interesting because even when people
有趣的是，即使当人们
hear all of that they think gosh I
听到这些，他们心想：天哪！
really don't want to go through that so
真的不想经历那种事。
J PR please tell me something to avoid
J PR，请告诉我一些需要避免的事情。
some of those things and and you know as
有些事情，你知道的
you were talking I was I was writing
你在说话，我在写作
down some principles yeah and what the
遵循一些原则，是的，还有什么？
first principle that I wrote down which
我写下的第一条原则是
could have avoided you a lot of that
本来可以避免你经历很多那些事。
heartache is to really really really
心痛真的真的真的
really take time when picking
挑选的时候一定要花时间。
people
人们
100% And we no one does it no one does
100% 而且我们没人这么做，没人这么做
it and I have an Investment Portfolio
我和它有一个投资组合
where I have 40 50 companies now and
我现在拥有40到50家公司，
that if there was one piece of advice
如果只能给出一条建议的话，那就是
that I'd give to all of those portfolio
我会把这些给所有这些投资组合
companies which I know they are not
我知道他们不是这些公司。
going to listen to No matter how
无论如何，我都要去听听《No Matter how》。
passionately I say it no matter if I
我热情地说，无论我
bang on the desk no matter if I scream
不管我尖叫与否，他都会猛击桌子
or show them my scars the one piece of
或者向他们展示我的伤疤，那是唯一的
advice I'd say to them is that
我会给他们的建议是：
recruitment is the single most important
招聘是其中最重要的因素。
thing and and you can say that to people
这件事，你可以对人们说。
but they still rush the process they
但他们仍然急于推进这个过程。
still will just go with their Vibes and
还是会顺其自然，跟随自己的感觉。
bias they'll still just go with the
他们还是会因为偏见而选择这条路。
person who sounds the smartest they
听起来最聪明的人
won't acknowledge the fact that they
他们不愿承认这一点
don't know what good looks like you
不知道你看起来有多好。
don't don't know what good looks like if
不知道好是什么样子
you start with this base premise which
你从这个基本前提开始，
most people don't start with which is I
大多数人不会以“哪个是我”开头。
am really really bad at recruitment if
我真的非常不擅长招聘。
you start with that then you'll put
你先从那开始，然后你会放
systems in place to alleviate the
已建立系统来缓解
downsides of you being really bad at
你很差劲的缺点
Recruitment and if you had started with
招聘，以及如果你从……开始
that when you were I don't know 20 years
那时你……我不知道，大概20年前吧
old or whatever it might have
老旧或其他什么情况
been you would have gone to seek out
如果你当时在场，你就会去寻找
someone else's opinion on which
别人对哪方面的看法
contractor to hire which tenants to
承包商将雇用哪些租户
bring in and that could have alleviated
引入这种物质或许可以缓解这个问题。
a lot of this pain it seems like I was
很多时候，这种痛苦似乎都源于我。
in a rush in a rush yes I wanted to get
匆忙之中，是的，我想得到
it done and so I find the cheapest and
搞定了，所以我找到了最便宜的
fastest contractor the cheapest and
速度最快、价格最便宜的承包商
fastest property manager the cheapest
最快、最便宜的物业管理
and fastest or not the cheapest but you
速度快慢，价格是否便宜，但你
know the fastest tenant that I could
我能找到最快的租户
bring in because I wanted to do it
引入是因为我乐意这么做
quickly I wanted to get there fast it
我想尽快到达那里。
reminds me of people picking romantic
这让我想起人们挑选浪漫对象。
Partners I was in a rush so I ignored
当时我很赶时间，所以就没理会合伙人。
the red flags and it's funny because you
那些危险信号，真是滑稽，因为你
said the cheapest this is actually what
他说最便宜的其实是这个
plays out in business all of the time is
这种情况在商业中无时无刻不在上演。
I speak to these young Founders that are
我与这些年轻的创始人交谈过，他们
starting businesses and they go Steve
开始创业，然后他们就去了史蒂夫
yeah I know you say like take time and
是的，我知道你说过要花时间，
hire great people but look at the salary
雇佣优秀人才，但也要考虑薪资。
this person costs $100,000 and this
这个人身价10万美元，而这个
one's $50,000 so I'm going to go for the
一个是5万美元，所以我打算选这个。
one that saves me
一个救了我的人
money and that is the Trap one of the
金钱，这就是陷阱之一。
most expensive things that you can do is
你能做的最昂贵的事情是
be cheap and I learned that the hard way
我曾吃过亏，才明白吝啬的真谛。
because I was born to be cheap you know
因为我天生就爱抠门，你知道吗？
I talked about how Indian people make a
我谈到了印度人如何制作
dollar to spend 20 cents that was my
花一美元买二十美分，那就是我的
family growing up and that was the way
在家庭中长大，就是这样。
that I was raised
我从小就被抚养长大
that if you become a doctor you'll make
如果你成为一名医生，你就会……
a nice sixf figure salary you can live
年薪六位数，生活无忧。
off of $30,000 a year and save a whole
每年节省 3 万美元，就能省下一大笔钱。
lot of money and I never questioned it
很多钱，但我从未质疑过。
but this is a very kind of just don't
但这其实是一种非常不应该的做法。
spend money that's how you build wealth
花钱，这就是积累财富的方式。
because if I give you money that means
因为如果我给你钱，那就意味着
I'm taking my wealth and giving it to
我要把我的财富捐出去
you and I'm getting nothing in return
你我都得不到任何回报
and that's it goes back to the in that
而这一切又回到了那个地方。
mindset money is abundant and that
心态上，金钱是取之不尽的。
scarcity
缺乏
thinking is one of the most expensive
思考是最昂贵的活动之一。
things that you can do so true and I'll
你能做的事情确实如此，我会
give you a story of this I told you I
我给你讲个故事，我跟你说过我
have if you want to talk about mistakes
如果你想谈论错误的话。
we can go for hours and days about my
我们可以花上几个小时甚至几天的时间来谈论我的
mistakes because I screwed up a
因为我搞砸了而犯了错误
lot I had an
我有很多
accountant and I figured that if I'm
我和会计师商量了一下，觉得如果我是
paying less money in accounting fees I
减少会计费用支出
am saving money so my business can keep
我正在存钱，这样我的生意才能继续下去。
more money act and build more wealth
更多资金投入，创造更多财富
right but one of the most expensive
没错，但其中最贵的之一
things that you can do is be cheap so I
你可以做的就是节俭，所以我
had this accountant that was
我有个会计，
cheap and all he did was file my taxes
他收费便宜，而且他只帮我报税而已。
kind of I mean he was late and whatever
算是吧，我的意思是，他迟到了，然后……
but he was cheap the monthly payment was
但他很抠门，每月付款额是
cheap so I didn't really care too much
便宜，所以我不太在意。
because I got the taxes
因为我收到了税款
done and then I always wondered why we
做完之后，我一直想知道为什么我们
don't like talk about tax planning what
不喜欢谈论税务规划，什么？
should I do it's just like at the end of
我应该这样做吗？就像在结尾一样
the year I get this like big email send
那一年我收到一封类似这样的邮件
me all of your stuff and then I don't
把你的东西都给我，然后我就不……
hear from him for a long time and then
很久之后才收到他的消息，然后
he says sign this paperwork and I didn't
他说让我签这份文件，但我没签。
really think much of it but then one
真的很看重它，但是后来……
year it was January I'm in my office and
那年一月，我在办公室里。
I get a call Early in the Morning from
清晨，我接到一个电话。
my accountant and if you get a call from
我的会计师，如果你接到来自
your accountant early morning in January
一月份清晨，你的会计师
it's never a good sign I didn't know
我不知道这件事，这绝不是个好兆头。
that he calls me says justbu how are you
他打电话给我说：“你好吗？”
doing I said I'm good how are you
我说我很好，你呢？
thinking I'm going to get some good news
我以为我会听到一些好消息
he said hey uh I made a little mistake
他说，嘿，呃，我犯了个小错误
on the taxes could you do me a favor and
关于税务问题，你能帮我个忙吗？
uh wire $18,000 to the state of Michigan
呃，向密歇根州汇款 18,000 美元。
by the end of the day said excuse me he
到一天结束时，他说了声对不起。
said oh uh also could you also by the
他说哦，呃，你也能买吗？
end of the day please wire $100,000 to
请于当日结束时汇款 10 万美元至
the federal IRS by the end of the
联邦国税局在年底前
day excuse me oh and the last part
抱歉，还有最后一部分
you're going to have pay penalties and
你将面临工资处罚，
interest on this to and it took me a
我对这个很感兴趣，而且花了我……
minute to really absorb all this
需要花点时间才能真正消化这一切。
information so you want me to send a
所以你想让我发送信息
hundred some thousand dos by the end of
到年底，将有十几万个 dos
the day whose fault is this and I
这一天是谁的错？还有我
remember this response he said it's
记住他的这个回答，他说这是
nobody's
没有人
fault and you know I I didn't really
是我的错，你知道我其实并没有真的那么做。
process what he said but I had to think
我需要消化他说的话，但我必须思考。
through this I said whose fault was it
通过这件事，我说这到底是谁的错。
it's my fault that's whose fault it was
是我的错，是谁的错？
I wanted to blame him but it was my
我想责怪他，但其实是我的错。
fault because I was being
是我的错，因为我当时
cheap and I learned I hired a new
便宜，而且我发现我雇了个新人
accountant who cost me many many many
那个让我损失惨重的会计师
multiples more than what I was paying
比我付的钱多好几倍
before but you know the crazy thing is
以前，但你知道最疯狂的是
it's actually saving me more money now
实际上，它现在反而帮我省了更多钱。
because we do these tax
因为我们做这些税务工作
strategizing which then allows me to pay
制定策略后，我就可以支付费用了。
less money in taxes legally even though
即使合法地少缴税，也比其他人少缴税。
I'm pay more money to my accountant this
我这周要多付点钱给我的会计师。
is one of the most pivotal things that I
这是我经历过的最关键的事情之一。
learned in the last sort of three to
在最后三种中学到
four years my care I've been in business
四年来，我一直在从事护理工作。
for maybe well my first business maybe
也许，嗯，我的第一笔生意也许
15 years ago but in the last three years
15年前，但最近三年
in particular I just got overly obsessed
尤其是我，我变得过于痴迷了。
about hiring in Recruitment and
关于招聘和招聘
really how much the the exceptional
真正杰出的人物究竟有多少？
person costs is inconsequential to the
人员成本对……而言微不足道
long-term net impact I'll have on my
我对我的长期净影响
business I remember I spoke to Jay Jason
我记得我和杰伊·杰森谈过生意。
who's my older brother who works in my
我哥哥在我公司工作。
company now he's like super smart lsse
现在他就像个超级聪明的家伙
actal scientist he's like a calculator
他是个真正的科学家，就像个计算器。
um and I I'd said to him can you tell me
嗯，我跟他说，你能告诉我吗？
where my net worth has originated from
我的净资产来源
he said your net worth is X hundreds of
他说你的净资产是 X 百
millions or whatever I said can you like
数百万或者我说的任何东西，你能喜欢吗？
go upstream and tell me where it came
溯流而上，告诉我它来自哪里。
from and he he didn't come back and say
他从……他没有回来，也没有说
oh you made this great bet or this
哦，你下了个大赌注，或者……
investment he said effectively what
他说的投资实际上是什么？
happened is you
发生的事情是你
hired six or seven good people and those
雇佣了六七个好员工，这些人
six or seven good people ended up hiring
最终，六七个优秀的人被录用了。
a couple more good people and making a
再找几个好人，然后……
couple of good decisions and those
几个不错的决定和那些
people made a couple more hires and made
人们又招了几个人，并且
a couple more good decisions and it
再做出几个正确的决定，它
propagated and it reminded me of
传播开来，这让我想起了
something Steve Jobs said Steve Jobs
史蒂夫·乔布斯说过的话
said people think I've built this you
人们都以为是我建了这个。
know multi-billion Dollar business
了解数十亿美元的业务
because I'm so smart and he says in that
因为我太聪明了，他在那句话里说……
interview I've built my career by doing
我通过面试建立了我的职业生涯。
the really really hard work of finding
寻找的过程真的非常非常艰难
truly exceptional people and it
真正杰出的人，而且
propagates I
传播 I
a players High a players b players High
a 玩家高 a 玩家 b 玩家高
b b players C players high C players so
b b 球员 C 球员 高 C 球员所以
the game of business I mean the
我指的是商业游戏
definition of the word company is group
公司一词的定义是集团
of people but the game of business is to
人与人之间的博弈，但商业游戏的本质是……
assemble the best group of people and if
组建一支最优秀的团队，如果
you're
你是
cheap that mission is not possible yeah
廉价的那个任务不可能完成，是的。
and and you you'll get a shortterm win
这样你就能获得短期收益。
but the long-term pain which is that
但长期的痛苦在于……
January phone call from your accountant
一月份接到会计师的电话
when they say I [__] up you get what
当他们说我搞砸了的时候，你就知道了。
you paid for just and and you know it
你付了钱，而且你知道这一点。
goes back to we talked about touching
回到我们之前讨论的关于触摸的话题。
the fire right becoming successful means
火灾发生后，成功的方法
you're going to make mistakes you have
你会犯错，你已经犯过错。
to make mistakes you cannot bypass the
犯错是无法避免的
mistakes you ask me how does somebody do
你问我一个人犯了什么错误
this without the mistakes you're going
如果没有你犯的错误，你就能做到。
to make your own but the difference
自己动手做，但区别在于
between somebody who becomes successful
在成功人士之间
and somebody who does not become
以及一个不会成为
successful is they are willing to make
成功在于他们愿意付出。
those mistakes see most people say I
这些错误让大多数人说“我”。
don't want to try to touch the fire I
我不想碰火。
don't want to risk it but until you
不想冒险，但直到你
touch it until you screw up you're not
碰它直到你搞砸为止，你不是。
going to know it's hot and You' got to
你会知道天气很热，而且你必须
be willing to screw up I want to add
愿意尝试犯错，我想补充一点
something to that as well which I
这其中也有些东西，我
noticed in you you just said that
我注意到你刚才说的那句话了。
unless you're willing to make mistakes
除非你愿意犯错。
you're not going to become successful
你不会成功的。
but there was a question I asked you I
但我问过你一个问题……
said whose mistake was it when I was
当我说这是谁的错时
talking about your accountant and I was
我们正在聊你的会计师，我当时
testing you because I was I was trying
测试你，因为我当时正在尝试
to see where you put responsibility
看看你把责任放在哪里
today and I think that point of taking
今天，我认为这一点很重要。
responsibility is actually the biggest
责任才是最重要的。
indicator that that mistake turns into a
表明该错误会演变成
lesson so your your accountant [__] up
所以你的会计搞砸了
clearly incompetent but when I asked you
显然能力不足，但当我问你的时候
whose fault was it you said it was my
你说是谁的错，是我的错。
fault and that immediately tells me that
错误，这立刻告诉我
you don't have an internal locus of
你没有内在的……
control are you the control of that
控制权，你就是控制权。
decision and your belief of where the
决定以及你对……的看法
control lies is within you so in the
控制权掌握在你手中。
future you can do something about it but
未来你可以为此做些什么，但是
when I speak to people about bad
当我跟别人谈论坏事时
relationships about bad hires or about
关于糟糕的招聘或关于人际关系
any sort of bad personal decision
任何糟糕的个人决定
they've made maybe a bad friend 99% of
他们可能交了个坏朋友，99%的人
the time they will blame the person that
到那时，他们会责怪那个人。
was a bad person and what you did is
你是个坏人，而你所做的一切
what I think is the most important thing
我认为最重要的是
and actually the science cooperates that
事实上，科学研究也证实了这一点。
if you have this internal locus of
如果你有这种内在的……
control internal responsibility for what
控制内部责任，负责什么
happens you're much more likely to be
如果发生这种情况，你更有可能……
successful much more likely to learn
成功者更有可能学习
from it much more likely to be happy
由此更有可能感到快乐
much more likely to be rich which as you
更有可能变得富有，因为你
went it was my fault can I tie that
如果是我的错，我可以把那条线系起来吗？
together now with wealth when people ask
现在，当人们问起财富时，我们一起问。
me why is it that so many people are
为什么这么多人
poor and struggling with money I say
我说，我穷，而且经济拮据。
there's two things at fault and there's
有两个方面出了问题，而且……
two ways you can look at it there's the
你可以从两个方面来看待这个问题：一是……
it's your fault and the my fault and I
这是你的错，也是我的错，还有我
always like to talk about both of these
我总是喜欢谈论这两者。
because you have to understand this
因为你必须明白这一点。
because it ties in very well and I
因为它与主题非常契合，而且我
appreciate all the kind words because I
感谢大家的鼓励和好意，因为我
I really do appreciate that but when I
我真的很感激，但是当我
say it's your fault look our economic
说这是你的错，看看我们的经济状况
system is designed to profit off of
该系统旨在从中获利
people being financially
人们在经济上
stupid period Banks profit when you're
愚蠢时期，银行在你……时获利
financially stupid because that means
在财务上愚蠢，因为这意味着
you stay in debt and they keep making
你一直负债累累，他们却不断赚钱。
interest for the rest of your life
余生利息
corporations profit when you're
当你……时，企业就能获利。
financially illiterate because that
因为这个原因，他缺乏金融知识。
means you're going to keep buying their
这意味着你会继续购买他们的产品。
stuff and not think twice and they're
把东西拿出来，不加思考，他们就是
going to hire the best and smartest mbas
我们将聘请最优秀、最聪明的MBA。
to get you to open up their wallets to
让你掏出他们的钱包
open up your wallets number three the
打开你们的钱包，第三条
government is going to profit when
政府将从中获利
you're financially illiterate because
你缺乏金融知识，因为
that means you don't do anything outside
这意味着你什么户外活动都不做。
of your W2 job and you're going to pay
你的W2工作，你打算支付
the highest tax rates you profit when
你获利的最高税率
you're financially educated so now what
你已经具备一定的理财知识，那么接下来呢？
can you do you can say they're the
你可以说他们是
reason I'm broke this company is the
我破产的原因是这家公司……
reason why I'm broke my company is the
我破产的原因是我的公司……
reason why I'm broke the government's
我破产的原因是政府的
the reason why I'm broke the banks are
我破产的原因是银行……
the reason why I'm broke well that's not
我破产的原因，其实并非如此。
what I'm saying that's just part one the
我说的只是第一部分。
second part to part one before I get to
在我进入第一部分之前，第二部分是……
part two is once you understand this you
第二部分是一旦你理解了这一点，你
can learn how to win you can learn how
你可以学习如何取胜，你可以学习如何
to use the bank you can learn how to use
要使用银行服务，您可以学习如何使用。
corporations because you want to have
因为你想拥有公司。
nice stuff you can learn how to use the
你可以学习如何使用一些好东西
resources that the government has but
政府拥有的资源，但
now let's flip the script the second
现在让我们反过来想想第二幕。
part to this that you need to understand
你需要了解这部分内容
it's your own
这是你自己的
responsibility because if you spend
责任，因为如果你花费
every dollar that you earn you're never
你赚的每一分钱，你永远都不会
going to become wealthy if every time
如果每次都变得富有
you make money you go on a nice vacation
你挣了钱，就去享受美好的假期
you're never going to build wealth if
如果你这样做，你永远也积累不了财富。
you can't afford it if you just make
如果你只是单纯地赚钱，你根本负担不起。
money and you make everybody else around
金钱，以及你身边所有人的财富。
you rich before you make yourself rich
你还没让自己致富就已经富有了。
that's your choice people don't want to
那是你的选择，人们不想那样做。
take personal responsibility though you
虽然你也要承担个人责任，但你
know it's a topic I always talk about um
我知道这是个我总是会谈到的话题，嗯。
because that's like holding a mirror up
因为那就像举起一面镜子一样
to yourself it doesn't feel good does it
你自己感觉不太好，对吧？
to say that it was my mistake I'm the
要说这是我的错误，我就是
reason why I don't have money I'm the
我没钱的原因是……
reason why I'm living in this you know
你知道我住在这里的原因。
this little bedsit with these four
这间小单间公寓里住了四个人
strange guys when I was 18 years old and
我18岁的时候遇到了一些奇怪的人
I didn't have car Carpets on the floor
我的车地板上没有地毯。
and I was shoplifting food to feed
我当时为了养家糊口，偷窃食物。
myself I'm you know that hurts to say
我自己也知道，说这话很伤人。
that it was me it's my deficiencies the
是我，是我的不足之处。
self-esteem doesn't want to to take such
自尊心不想接受这样的事情。
an attack and you know what here's the
一次袭击，你知道吗，这就是……
thing it might not be all your fault
想想看，这可能不全是你的错。
there might be a lot of reasons why
可能有很多原因
you're in that crappy situation there
你现在处境很糟糕。
might be a lot of reasons why you're
你之所以会这样，可能有很多原因。
struggling with money today you might
今天你可能正为钱发愁
have grown up in a very crappy situation
我从小在非常糟糕的环境下长大。
you might have had horrible parents you
你可能有一个糟糕的父母。
might have had a horrible upbringing you
你可能有着糟糕的童年经历
might have had horrible surroundings you
你可能身处糟糕的环境。
might have been dealt a horrible set of
可能遭遇了一系列糟糕的事情
cards okay now what now what you were
卡片好了，现在怎么办？你之前是什么？
now the question is are you going to
现在的问题是，你打算……
take that responsibility today going
今天就承担起这份责任吧
forward or not and you have to take that
前进还是后退，你必须接受这个结果。
drastic responsibility you have to take
你必须承担重大责任
that drastic mindset shift and that's
这种思维方式的剧变，就是这样。
what you have to do and it's difficult
你必须做的事情，这很难。
who wants to blame
谁想责怪
themselves but if you want to change
他们自己，但如果你想改变
where you
你
are they're not going to do it your
他们不会这么做的
Banker is not gonna say
银行家不会这么说
Hey Stephen you know you can't afford
嘿，斯蒂芬，你知道你负担不起。
this car don't take this debt don't take
这辆车不用来偿还这笔债务，不用来偿还
this house because if they can sign you
这栋房子，因为如果他们能签下你
up they're going to want to get paid
他们最终都会想要拿到报酬。
they're in the business of making money
他们的生意就是赚钱。
not for you but for them Gucci is not
不是为你，而是为他们，Gucci 不是
going to say maybe you should buy some
或许你应该买一些。
stocks instead of this purse because
因为与其买这个钱包，不如买股票。
they're going to want you to buy their
他们会想让你买他们的产品。
stuff the government's not going to say
政府不会说的话
hey why don't you take a look at our
嘿，你为什么不看看我们的
balance sheet I'm gonna get I'm gonna
我要拿到资产负债表
take this little tangent
稍微跑题一下
the government says student loans are a
政府称学生贷款是
problem we've all heard that Millennials
我们都听说过千禧一代面临的问题
can't buy houses they can't buy their
他们买不起房子，他们买不起他们的
home they can't invest because they have
他们无法投资的房子，因为他们有
student loans the government says
政府表示，学生贷款
student loans are a problem really let's
学生贷款确实是个问题，我们来探讨一下。
take a look at the United States balance
看看美国的平衡情况
sheet your balance sheet is your asset
资产负债表就是你的资产。
and liability statement the number one
责任声明是第一要务。
largest asset on the United States
美国最大的资产
government balance sheet are student
政府资产负债表是学生
loans so here we keep saying oh student
贷款，所以我们一直说哦，学生
loans are bad we keep hearing this from
我们一直听到这样的说法：贷款不好。
the government but on the other hand the
政府，但另一方面
government is so rich because of the
政府之所以如此富有，是因为……
student loans because so many people are
学生贷款，因为太多人
stuck in these student loans and guess
深陷学生贷款泥潭，猜测
what you pay the highest tax rates when
当你缴纳最高税率时
you were just an employee I'm an
你只是个员工，而我是一个
attorney I'm not your attorney but I am
律师，我不是你的律师，但我……
a licensed attorney and I spent a lot of
我是一名持证律师，我花了很多时间
time studying the tax
花时间研究税收
law and what I can tell you is that the
法律，我可以告诉你的是……
tax law rewards you when you are an
当你符合以下条件时，税法会给予你奖励：
investor in
投资者
2024 the CEO of Coca-Cola James Quincy
2024年可口可乐首席执行官詹姆斯·昆西
is going to make about $8 million in
预计将赚取约 800 万美元
cash compensation he'll also get Equity
现金补偿外，他还将获得股权。
but about $8 million in cash
但大约有800万美元现金
compensation his top tax rate on that $8
他获得的补偿金按最高税率计算，这8美元将用于支付他的8美元所得税。
million is going to be 37% on the
百万将占37%
federal taxes in the US Warren Buffett
美国联邦税 沃伦·巴菲特
is going to make over $700 million from
将从中获得超过7亿美元的收入
Coca-Cola dividends in 2024 his his top
可口可乐2024年的股息是他最高的
tax rate is going to be
税率将是
20% he's making way more than the CEO
他赚的20%比CEO多得多。
but he's going to pay less in taxes on a
但他缴纳的税款会更少。
percentage level because he made that
因为他达到了百分比水平。
money as an
金钱作为一种
investor we're never taught that this
投资者，我们从未被教导过这一点。
goes one step further though doesn't it
但它又更进一步，不是吗？
because if you look at someone like an
因为如果你看看像……这样的人
Elon
埃隆
Musk they never even take a salary these
马斯克，他们甚至从未领取过薪水
people and people don't know about this
人们对此一无所知。
thing called loaning against your assets
就是用你的资产作抵押进行贷款。
I didn't know about it and I think it's
我之前不知道这件事，我觉得是……
a big secret that people need to know
一个人们需要知道的大秘密
about Elon Musk is interesting because
关于埃隆·马斯克的事情很有趣，因为
he's a risk
他是个风险人物。
taker and he chose to get paid not in
收款人，他选择不接受报酬。
salary and if we look at the tax benefit
薪资待遇，以及税收优惠
from this is because you are taxed not
这是因为你被征税了，而不是
on your income that's not what the tax
你的收入并非税收的范畴。
code says you are taxed based on your
法规规定，你的税款是根据你的收入征收的。
taxable income so now what every
应税收入，那么现在每笔收入又是多少呢？
accountant every smart accountant every
每个聪明的会计师
every smart accountant is going to focus
每个聪明的会计师都会关注这一点。
on reducing your taxable income and so
减少你的应税收入等等
what Elon Musk did is when he was
埃隆·马斯克所做的，是当他……
building TX Tesla he negotiated with the
在建设TX特斯拉时，他与……进行了谈判
investors and the
投资者和
board that I want to get paid not with a
我希望董事会成员不以任何方式获得报酬
salary I want to get paid with stock
我希望以股票形式获得薪水。
options a stock option gives you the
股票期权赋予你以下权利：
right to buy that stock and he was
他买入那支股票是对的，而且他是
awarded these Tesla stock options at
这些特斯拉股票期权是在
about $6 a
大约6美元
share which means if the Tesla stock
股票份额，这意味着如果特斯拉股票
goes up to to $7 a share he could sell
股价最高可达每股 7 美元，他可以出售
the stock option for $6 and profit $1
以 6 美元的价格买入股票期权，获利 1 美元。
for each stock option now he was given
他现在拥有的每份股票期权都给了他
millions and millions and millions of
数百万、数百万、数百万
these stock
股票
options and so now when the Tesla stock
期权，所以现在特斯拉股票
goes up to $100 a
最高可达100美元
share now he is Rich on paper he doesn't
现在他账面上很富有，但实际上并非如此。
have any money in his bank he hasn't
他银行里没有存款。
gotten a salary so he has no taxable
他领的是工资，所以没有应税收入。
income because he hasn't actually
因为他实际上并没有收入。
received any money he has the option to
他收到的任何款项都可以选择
sell this stock for six
以六的价格卖出这支股票
and in return get $100 so net
作为回报，我获得了100美元，净收益为100美元。
94 but if he sold that stock he would
94，但如果他卖掉那些股票，他就会
have $94 of income now you have a tax
你现在有94美元的收入，你需要缴税。
because you have taxable income so
因为你有应税收入，所以
instead what he does is he goes to the
相反，他却去了
bank and he says Hey bank I have these
银行，他说：“嘿，银行，我有这些。”
millions and millions of stock options
数百万份股票期权
that are worth billions of dollars would
价值数十亿美元的
you like to loan me a million $10
你想借给我一百万美元吗？
million $100 million at three four or 5%
百万美元，1亿美元，按三、四或5%计算
interest no bank is going to say no
没有哪家银行会拒绝利息
because the collateral is so valuable
因为抵押品价值很高。
what's the collateral the collateral is
抵押品是什么？抵押品是
the company it's his assets the stock
这家公司是他的资产，股票
options which is Tesla in this which is
特斯拉的期权就在这里。
Tesla in this
特斯拉
instance so then he gets let's call it a
例如，然后他就得到了我们称之为……
$10 million loan from the bank now he
他现在从银行获得了1000万美元的贷款。
has $10 million in his bank account but
他的银行账户里有1000万美元，但是
it's not an income it's debt debt is not
这不是收入，这是债务；债务不是
taxed if you go out and get a mortgage
如果你去申请抵押贷款，就要缴税。
for a half a million dollars you're not
五十万美元？你不是。
taxed if you do a Cash out refinance
如果你进行套现再融资，则需要缴税。
you're not taxed because that's debt so
你不用缴税，因为那是债务。
now he gets this $10 million of loans
现在他获得了这1000万美元的贷款
that he can spend to buy a house to buy
他可以用这笔钱买房。
a car to buy food to buy vacations to
一辆车，用来买食物，买假期。
buy whatever you want buy Twitter to buy
买任何你想买的东西，买推特账号来购买
Twitter and pay no money in taxes and
Twitter 无需缴纳任何税款
it's 100% legal now you're going to say
现在这完全合法了，你会这么说吗？
well just prit how does he pay it
好吧，就写一下，他怎么付钱？
back well let's just assume that you're
好吧，我们假设你是
going to get a 5% interest on this if
如果这样做，我将获得 5% 的利息。
the value of Tesla goes up by say
假设特斯拉的价值上涨了……
7% he made a profit so now he can go
他赚了7%，所以现在他可以走了
back to the bank and say how about you
回到银行，问问你怎么样
give me an additional $10
再给我10美元
million and he can pay back the old loan
他有100万美元，可以偿还旧贷款。
because the value keeps going up and as
因为其价值持续上涨，而且
long as the value keeps going up no
只要价值持续上涨，就不会
problem but you can start to see where
问题在于，但你可以开始看出问题所在。
this gets risky because if Tesla goes
这样做有风险，因为如果特斯拉
bankrupt now we're talking about a house
现在我们说的是房子，我们破产了。
of cards that can collapse and now you
卡牌可能会崩溃，现在你
have all this debt that you've already
你已经背负了这么多债务。
spent and no more collateral but in his
钱都花光了，抵押品也用完了，但他
case he could
如果他能……
if Tesla starts to fall in value then
如果特斯拉的价值开始下跌……
the bank will call payment so if it say
银行会打电话催款，所以如果电话里说……
it might be I don't know Tesla Falls
可能是我不知道的特斯拉瀑布
from let's say 100 to $10 a share
比如说，从每股 100 美元降到 10 美元。
they're going to call payment he's going
他们会打电话通知他付款，他要走了。
to get what what's that called he's
想知道那叫什么来着，他是
going to get a um Margin Call a margin
即将收到追加保证金通知
call which means that they're going to
打电话，这意味着他们要……
say give me the money back quick yes and
快点把钱还给我，好的。
or they're going to sell off the
或者他们会把……
asset and to get their money back quick
资产并尽快收回资金
and it's a losing transaction the bank
这是一笔银行亏损的交易。
will lose because if they Banks do not
将会失败，因为如果银行不这样做的话
profit from margin calls because once
从追加保证金中获利，因为一旦
you start making margin calls that's in
你开始发出追加保证金通知，那就是……
panic hits yeah and now you have to
恐慌袭来，现在你必须……
scramble to sell and now the bank is
争相抛售，现在银行……
just trying to get pennies back out of
只是想从中捞回几个便士而已
every dollar that they lent out I'm
他们借出的每一美元，我
going to get old
会变老
someday and um I think a lot
总有一天，嗯，我想了很多。
about making sure I'm wealthy enough so
关于确保我足够富有这件事。
that I can take care of myself when I
当我……的时候，我可以照顾好自己
probably can't work a lot of people talk
可能因为很多人谈论太多而无法正常工作。
about this retirement crisis MH that the
关于这场退休危机，MH表示
UK and the US are in what is the
英国和美国处于什么状态？
retirement crisis and why why does it
退休危机及其原因
matter to any of us and what do we do
这对我们每个人来说都很重要，我们该怎么办？
about it this is a multifaceted
关于这一点，这是一个多方面的问题。
issue the first issue is we have this
第一个问题是我们有这个问题
huge population of old people Baby
老年人口众多
Boomers that are retired or entering
已退休或即将退休的婴儿潮一代
retirement that have not enough money
退休金不够用
this is not just the US this is also the
这不仅仅是美国的问题，这也是……
UK like you said which creates a few
正如你所说，英国造成了一些问题。
issues
问题
number one who's going to take care of
第一名将负责照顾
them number two who's going to fund that
第二名是谁来资助这件事？
taking care of them the government
政府照顾他们
doesn't have that
没有那个
money and the people that are going into
金钱和进入其中的人们
retirement don't have that money and
退休后没有那么多钱，
their kids many times don't have that
他们的孩子很多时候都没有那种机会。
money that's the first
这是第一笔钱
issue and now as we start to dig into
问题，现在我们开始深入探讨
that we have people that are working
我们有正在工作的人员
longer
更长
and it creates now now this problem in
现在这就造成了这个问题。
the future that we can see today if
我们今天所看到的未来，如果
you're in your 50s 40s 30s 20s teens you
你正处于50多岁、40多岁、30多岁、20多岁、十几岁……
can see that there's this problem that's
可以看出，存在这样一个问题：
happening how do we prevent that
如果这种情况发生，我们该如何预防？
today because I don't know what the
今天因为我不知道什么
solution is for this retirement crisis I
针对这场退休危机，我的解决方案是……
don't have a solution for that the
对此我没有解决方案。
average retirement savings for Americans
美国人的平均退休储蓄
age 60 is roughly
60岁左右
$500,000 and the average age of death in
50万美元和平均死亡年龄
the US is 77 years old so if you retire
美国建国已有77年，所以如果你退休
at 67 years old which is the average age
平均年龄为67岁
of retirement in the United States then
当时在美国的退休生活
for the next 10 years you're going to
接下来的10年你将……
have to live off about
不得不靠其他东西勉强糊口
$50,000 um and the stats say that well I
5万美元，嗯，统计数据也表明，嗯，我
actually got this from your YouTube
实际上这是我从你的 YouTube 频道上看到的。
channel the minority mindset YouTube
少数族裔思维模式 YouTube
channel said that the average American
该频道称，普通美国人
needs between1 to2 million to retire
退休需要100万到200万美元。
comfortably according to USA Today We
据《今日美国》报道，我们舒适地
need about $1.8 million to comfortably
大约需要180万美元才能过上舒适的生活
wow
哇
and the reason why is every year we have
原因在于，我们每年都有
inflation so if you live off of
通货膨胀，所以如果你靠……生活
$50,000 this year you're going to need
今年你需要5万美元
maybe 52 53 $54,000 next year more the
明年或许能达到 52、53 美元，甚至更多。
year after that more the year after that
那之后的一年，以及再过一年……
and $50,000 doesn't buy you what it did
5万美元买不到它曾经拥有的东西。
30 years
30年
ago and so now when we take a look at
以前，所以现在当我们审视……
all these issues happening the question
所有这些问题都与此有关。
question is what do you do today to
问题是，你今天做了什么？
prevent these issues in the
防止出现这些问题。
future and starting with in the United
未来，从美国开始
States we have what's called Social
我们各州都有所谓的社会
Security which is a government check
政府检查
that you get when you
你得到的
retire the first problem with Social
解决社交方面的第一个问题
Security because Social Security is
保障，因为社会保障是
drying up this is a fact that if you
干涸是事实，如果你
read the headlines they'll say social
看看新闻标题，他们会说社交媒体
security is going to be dry by
安全问题将会变得棘手。
20134 if nothing changes the problem is
20134 如果情况没有改变，问题在于
people are paying money in but the
人们都在投入资金，但是
government is paying out more than
政府支出超过
what's going in so from any business
任何企业都在做什么？
perspective if you have more cash
如果你手头更宽裕，情况会是怎样的呢？
outflows and cash inflows you have a
您拥有的现金流出和现金流入
problem and the reason for that is well
问题及其原因显而易见。
number one the math was wrong and number
第一，数学计算有误；第二，数字
two people are living longer so when the
两个人寿命更长，所以当
government keeps paying your social
政府会继续支付你的社会保险费。
security check longer and longer and
安检时间越来越长
longer because people are living longer
因为人们寿命更长了，所以寿命也更长了。
life expectancy is getting higher that
预期寿命越来越长
means they have to keep paying that's
这意味着他们必须继续支付这笔费用。
not good for the
不利于
government now on the plan right here to
政府现在正在制定这项计划。
La I sat next to somebody who was
我坐在一个人旁边，那个人是
telling me I didn't verify this but he
他告诉我我没有核实这件事，但他
told me that the government knew that
有人告诉我政府知道这一点。
this was going to be a problem from the
这将是个问题。
get-go because he told me that the first
一开始，因为他告诉我第一
recipient of the Social Security program
社会保障计划的受益人
lived to a 100 I don't know if that's
活到100岁？我不知道这算不算。
true or not but you can Google that to
真假难辨，你可以上网搜一下。
see but that's the problem right now
你看，但这就是现在的问题所在。
Social Security is is running out of
社会保障资金即将耗尽。
money and this is where everyone says
钱，这就是大家常说的。
Social Security is going to run dry
社会保障金即将枯竭
you're never going to get a social
你永远不会获得社交
security check that's not true either
安全检查，那也不是真的。
the reason why I say that is because
我这么说的原因是：
because the government won't let it fail
因为政府不会让它失败
they'll either raise your taxes or
他们要么会提高你的税收，要么
they'll just print that money but the
他们会直接印钞票，但是
problem with it is you will never be
问题在于你永远不会……
able to live comfortably off of Social
能够靠社会救济金过上舒适的生活
Security that was never the intention
这并非本意的安全措施
but many people are looking at it as I'm
但很多人都像我一样看待这件事。
going to be able to live comfortably
能够过上舒适的生活
from this government
来自本届政府
check but here's the problem let's take
检查一下，但问题是这样的，我们来看看
a look at what's happening today between
让我们来看看今天发生了什么
2024 to
2024年
2025 social security recipients are
2025年社会保障金领取者是
going to receive a
即将收到
2.5% raise for inflation what they're
为应对通货膨胀，他们提高了2.5%
saying is we have this inflation in
也就是说，我们现在面临通货膨胀。
2024 and because of this inflation in
2024年，由于这种通货膨胀……
2024 you're going to get a 2 and a half%
2024年你将获得2.5%的涨幅。
raise there two problems with that
这里提出了两个问题。
number one that raise is not enough
第一，提高工资还不够。
things are getting a lot more expensive
东西越来越贵了。
even though the rate of inflation is
即使通货膨胀率是
falling I mean 2 and a half% raise is
我的意思是，涨幅只有2.5%。
not going to keep up over the real cost
无法跟上实际成本
of living growth that most people feel
大多数人都能感受到的那种鲜活的成长。
the second problem is it's a delayed
第二个问题是延迟了。
raise the government gives you a raise
政府给你涨工资
in 2025 based off of the inflation you
根据通货膨胀率，2025 年你
had in 2024 so we already had this price
2024年就已经有了，所以我们当时已经有了这个价格。
growth and then you get the raise next
然后你就能获得晋升，接下来你就能加薪了。
year and guess what we're going to have
今年，猜猜我们将拥有什么？
more inflation in
通货膨胀加剧
2025 so relying on social security is a
到2025年，依靠社会保障金是……
losing proposition which brings the next
失败的提议会带来下一个问题
part of this three-legged stool see have
这三脚凳的一部分可以看到
social security then you have
那么你就有社会保障金了。
pensions pensions have become a thing of
养老金已经成为……
the P I mean if you're under the age of
P 的意思是，如果你未满……
45 chances are you're not getting a
有 45% 的几率你得不到
pension and even if you're over the age
即使您已超过年龄，也能领取养老金。
of 45 and you're promised a pension you
45岁，你就能获得养老金。
better cross your fingers to hope that
最好祈祷吧。
that pension fund does not go bankrupt
那个养老基金不会破产
because there have been many Pension
因为有很多养老金
funds that have gone bankrupt and people
破产的基金和人们
are left with
剩下的
nothing which leaves number three your
没有任何东西能让你排在第三位。
own savings and
自有储蓄和
Investments and this is where we have so
投资，而这正是我们拥有的领域。
much a lack of understanding because
由于缺乏理解，造成这种情况。
people are not doing
人们没有这样做
enough this goes back to the whole
这就回到了整个……
financial
金融的
education we make money to spend money
教育，我们赚钱是为了花钱。
that's what the American culture is I
这就是美国文化。
make $1,000 I'm going spend $1,000 maybe
赚了1000美元，我可能要花掉1000美元。
$1,200 but you're never going to be able
1200美元，但你永远不可能拥有。
to retire with that sort of mindset and
带着这种心态退休
here's the second problem with that I'm
这是第二个问题，我……
just going to lay the problem so we'll
我先把问题说清楚，所以我们……
come up with a solution you might say
提出一个解决方案，你可能会这么说。
well I need a financial
我需要一笔资金
adviser no good financial adviser
顾问不是好的财务顾问
nowadays wants to work with anybody
如今他想和任何人合作。
under $500,000 in assets maybe $250,000
资产低于50万美元，可能只有25万美元。
in assets maybe if you get lucky
也许在资产方面，如果你运气好的话，就能有所斩获。
$100,000 in assets but if you have under
拥有10万美元资产，但如果您少于
that they don't want to work with you
他们不想和你一起工作
because they want people to have some
因为他们希望人们拥有一些
money to actually make money off of
真正用来赚钱的钱
right the financial advisers got to eat
没错，财务顾问们得吃饭了。
too so if you don't have the Investments
所以，如果你没有投资的话……
you don't have the education now you're
你现在没有受过教育
stuck and this is where now your
卡住了，这就是你现在的情况
Financial education comes in because if
金融教育之所以重要，是因为如果
you want to build wealth you want to
你想积累财富，你想
have quote unquote retirement you got to
有了所谓的“退休”，你就得……
do something different you can't keep
做一些你无法坚持下去的与众不同的事情
doing what the majority of people do
做大多数人都会做的事
because if you keep doing what the
因为如果你继续这样做……
majority of people do you're going to
大多数人都会这么做。
end up like the majority people and
最终变得和大多数人一样，
right now that's broke in debt living
现在他已经负债累累，生活拮据。
paycheck to paycheck fat and unhappy and
每月工资都用来支付薪水，又胖又不快乐
I'm not saying this as a general term I
我不是在泛指……
mean
意思是
statistically that's what the majority
从统计数据来看，大多数人都是如此。
of people are especially in America so
尤其是在美国，很多人都这样。
now let's come up with the solution cuz
现在让我们一起想出解决方案，因为
we have laid out the problem
我们已经阐述了这个问题。
the first solution is Define what is
第一个解决方案是定义什么是
retirement because I'm going to get a
退休，因为我要获得……
little philosophical here but I have my
这里有点哲学意味，但我有我的
issues with traditional retirement
传统退休制度存在的问题
there's a saying that says Those Who
有一句谚语说：那些
retire early die early the reason why is
早退休、早逝的原因是什么？
because if you work from the age of 21
因为如果你从21岁开始工作
to 65 maybe 67 at a job you hate but you
也许到65岁甚至67岁，做着一份你讨厌的工作，但是你
work every single day and all you're
每天工作，而你却……
looking forward to is retire at 67
期待67岁退休
you retired 67 you have this great big
你67岁退休了，你拥有了这巨大的财富
retirement party now you come home and
现在你回家参加退休派对吧
you sit on the sofa and you start
你坐在沙发上，然后开始
watching
观看
TV you start to lose your sense of
看电视时，你会开始失去感觉。
purpose and I've seen this very closely
目的，而且我已经非常仔细地观察过了。
with people in my not my family but
和我身边的人，不是我的家人，而是
close to my
靠近我
family where I've seen people who were
在我的家庭里，我见过一些人，他们
healthy energetic maybe didn't love
健康、精力充沛，也许并不爱
their work but they had a reason to get
他们的工作，但他们有理由获得
up every day go to work retire and
每天起床上班，退休……
literally go insane I mean you you have
真的要疯了，我的意思是，你已经疯了。
nothing to do and now you start to see
无事可做，现在你开始看到了
health issues that you didn't have
你之前没有的健康问题
before you start to have mental health
在你开始出现心理健康问题之前
issues which you didn't have before and
你以前没有遇到的问题以及
all these things just start to happen
所有这些事情就这样开始发生了。
when you were going to enter your golden
当你准备进入你的黄金时代时
years even if you have the money to do
即使你有钱，也需要很多年才能做到。
things so when we talk about what is
所以当我们谈论什么是……的时候
retirement I want to caution
我想提醒大家注意退休事宜。
everybody or if you have parents to
每个人，或者如果你有父母
start thinking about what do you want to
开始思考你想要什么
do during retirement because if your
退休期间这样做是因为如果你
goal is to do
目标是做
nothing you might enjoy it for the first
没什么，你可能第一次会喜欢它。
few weeks maybe 6 months but eventually
几周，也许六个月，但最终
you're going to get bored so you got to
你会感到无聊，所以你必须……
have something to do then is the
那时有事可做就是
financial side of retirement what is
退休的财务方面是什么？
retirement and I have a different
退休后，我有了不同的想法。
definition than most people most
比大多数人的定义更甚
financial advisers don't like me for the
财务顾问不喜欢我，因为……
things that I say but my definition of
我说的话，但我对……的定义
retirement is the same as my definition
退休的定义与我的定义相同。
of
的
wealth wealth is for me when my cash
对我而言，财富就是我的现金。
flow from my investments exceeds my
我的投资收益超过了我的
expenses
开支
it's very simple if my expenses are
如果我的支出是……那就很简单了。
$4,000 a month and my cash flow from my
每月4000美元，以及我来自我的现金流
stocks and my real estate and everything
股票、我的房地产以及所有的一切
else is paying me $4,000 And1 a month I
否则每月给我4000美元，外加1美元。
am
是
wealthy so now the question is how do
富有，所以现在的问题是如何……
you actually achieve this type of wealth
你真的能获得这种财富吗？
retirement the reason why I don't like
退休是我不喜欢退休的原因
the word retirement as well besides the
除了“退休”这个词之外，
connotation of I'm going to do nothing
“我什么也不做”的含义
is they assume there's I got to be 67
他们是不是认为我必须67岁？
years old to hit this retirement when
达到退休年龄时
you can achieve this wealth way
你可以通过这种致富方式实现财富目标。
sooner and now you have more options so
时间更早，现在你有了更多选择。
retirement Is wealth wealth is when your
退休就是财富，财富就是当你……的时候
cash flow from your assets exceeds your
您的资产现金流超过了您的
expenses how do you actually do this
费用方面，你具体是怎么做的？
now well you got to buy the
现在你得买下它
assets and in order to do that you have
资产，而要做到这一点，你需要……
to have the
拥有
money and many people assume that the
金钱，许多人认为
way you get rich is by Investing For
致富之道在于投资。
passive income you get rich by investing
通过投资获得被动收入，从而致富
in real estate you get rich by buying
在房地产领域，买入房产可以让你致富。
this cash flow that's a
这条现金流是
lie you have to have the money
撒谎，你必须得有钱。
first you have to have the money to
首先你得有钱。
invest in real estate you have to have
投资房地产，你必须具备以下条件
the money to buy the cash flow so if we
我们需要资金来购买现金流，所以如果我们
just make the numbers very round and
只需把数字弄得很整数即可。
simple if I need
如果需要的话，很简单
$70,000 a year to live my life and I can
每年7万美元够我过日子了，我可以
get a 7% cash cash flow on my
我的现金流收益率为 7%。
investments I need to invest a million
我需要投资一百万美元
dollar to have that $70,000 a year to
用一美元就能每年赚到7万美元
fund my
资助我
lifestyle now you're going to say where
现在你的生活方式是什么？你要说的是哪里？
in the world are you going to get a
在这个世界上，你会得到一个
million dollars you don't need it today
你今天不需要那一百万美元
it can happen over time right when
这种情况可能会随着时间的推移而发生，就在……的时候
people talk about retirement planning
人们谈论退休计划
they're thinking about 45 years so when
他们考虑的是45年，所以当
we talk about wealth why can't we talk
我们谈论财富，为什么我们不能谈论其他事情
about the long term it's not going to
从长远来看，这不会发生。
happen in two days but it can happen if
两天内可能会发生，但如果
you put in that work
你付出了努力
so now you have to put aside this amount
所以现在你必须把这笔钱存起来。
of cash to buy certain Investments that
现金用于购买某些投资，
can pay you this type of cash
可以支付你这种类型的现金
flow the second thing is well what about
第二件事是，嗯，那又如何呢？
inflation jit you talk about this all
通货膨胀专家，你一直在谈论这些。
the time the buying power of my dollar
时间影响了我美元的购买力。
is going down $70,000 when I'm 65 years
等我65岁的时候，我的账户里会损失7万美元。
old in a few decades is not going to
几十年后变老并不会……
have the same buying power as today
拥有与今天相同的购买力
you're right but here's the thing when
你说得对，但问题是……
you invest your money into dividend
你将钱投资于股息。
paying stocks which are stocks that pay
支付股息的股票，即支付股息的股票。
you or into strong real estate these are
您是否对优质房地产感兴趣？这些都是
inflation adjusted Investments which
经通胀调整后的投资
means
方法
generally as inflation happens rental
通常情况下，通货膨胀会导致租金上涨。
prices go up as inflation happens stock
随着通货膨胀发生，价格上涨。
values and dividends also go
价值和股息也随之变化
up and this is where now if we start to
向上，这就是我们现在要开始的地方
understand this you'll understand the
理解了这一点，你就会理解了。
power of this
这种力量
because it's actually a little bit more
因为实际上还要多一点。
extreme we've probably heard about you
极端分子，我们可能听说过你
know the wealth Gap in America and how
了解美国的财富差距及其成因
the rich are getting richer and the poor
富者愈富，穷者愈穷。
are getting
正在获得
poorer well the reason why that
贫穷的原因就在于此。
happens is because investment values
这种情况的发生是因为投资价值
grow faster than
增长速度比
incomes and inflation benefits
收入和通货膨胀福利
investors so you see how we start to tie
所以你看，我们是如何开始与投资者建立联系的。
this all together because wealth is
这一切加在一起，是因为财富是
about owning
关于拥有
Investments the way you become wealthy
投资是致富之道。
by owning Investments our economic
通过拥有投资，我们的经济
system is designed to benefit investors
该系统旨在使投资者受益。
if we take a look at 2019 to
如果我们回顾一下2019年
2024 over those 5
2024 年超过这 5 年
years household incomes the median
多年来家庭收入中位数
household income grew by around
家庭收入增长了约
18% during those 5 years the S&amp;P 500 the
在这五年间，标普500指数上涨了18%。
stock market has grown by almost
股市增长了近
100% which means that the wealth for
100%，这意味着财富
investors has grown almost five times or
投资者人数增长了近五倍或
about five times faster than
比……快大约五倍
incomes this is why you can't earn your
收入，这就是你无法赚取收入的原因
way to wealth you can't save your way to
通往财富的道路并非只有储蓄一条。
wealth you have to invest your way to
你必须通过投资来积累财富
wealth and remember wealth is retirement
财富，记住，财富就是退休
and you might say well despy that's just
你可能会说，好吧，德斯皮，那只是
because of the pandemic and everything
因为疫情等等
that after happened after the pandemic
那是疫情之后发生的事情。
well let's go back in time let's look at
好，让我们回到过去，看看……
it a little bit broader let's look at
让我们把它拉宽一些，看看……
the five decades between
五十年
1971 and 20
1971年和20
21 over those five decades household
21 在过去的五十年里，家庭
income increased by around
收入增加了约
600% now mind you that between 1971 and
请注意，1971 年至 1972 年间，这一数字增长了 600%。
2021 we also saw the number of workers
2021年我们也看到了工人数量的变化。
in a household increase between in
家庭增长介于
1971 the average household had one
1971年，平均每个家庭拥有一台
person that went to work the man went to
那个去上班的人，那个人去了
work and the woman didn't that's how
工作，而那个女人没有，就是这样。
life was in early 1970s in 2021 many
2021年，生活就像20世纪70年代初期的许多事情一样。
households are two household incomes so
家庭是指两个家庭都有收入的家庭。
1971 to 2021 the median household income
1971年至2021年家庭收入中位数
grew by around
大约增长了
600% the S&amp;P 500 the largest 500
600% 标普500指数，最大的500指数
companies in the stock market grew by
股市中的公司增长了
around
大约
4,000% so again inflation happens
通货膨胀率高达4000%，再次发生。
inflation benefits the investor how do
通货膨胀如何使投资者受益？
you become wealthy it's by investing
致富之道在于投资。
your
你的
money so if you want to retire if you
所以，如果你想退休，你需要钱。
want to build wealth you have to be an
想要积累财富，你必须成为一个
investor and you have to calculate what
投资者，你需要计算一下
is that wealth number for you for me the
这个财富数字对你我来说意味着什么？
way that I do it is I do it through cash
我的做法是用现金支付。
flow most of my investments my real
我的大部分投资都流向了我的真实
estate Investments pay me cash flow when
房地产投资给我带来现金流
I buy a property I buy it for the cash
我买房，我用现金买的。
flow most of my stock market Investments
我的大部分股票市场投资都流向了这里。
are dividend paying assets meaning they
它们是派息资产，这意味着它们
pay me cash flow dividends just for
给我现金流股息，就为了
owning the
拥有
stock some of my investments grow in
股票，我的一些投资正在增值
value they're more appreciative they're
他们更看重，也更懂得欣赏。
more
更多的
appreciation but when I think about
感激之情，但当我想到
retirement for me it's cash flow
对我来说，退休就是现金流。
exceeding my expenses
超出我的预算
what about starting a company should
那么，创办公司应该怎么做呢？
people become
人们会变成
entrepreneurs well I think everybody in
企业家们，我觉得每个人都应该如此。
America needs to be business owner but
美国人需要成为企业主，但是
the majority people should not operate a
大多数人不应该操作
business when you invest in a stock you
当你投资股票时，你会从事商业活动。
become a business owner you don't
成为企业主，你不需要
operate the business if I go out and buy
如果我出去买东西，就经营这家店。
a share of Amazon I'm not working in the
我持有亚马逊的股份，但我没有在亚马逊工作。
company I'm not operating the company
我并非该公司的经营者。
but I own some of it some people should
但我拥有其中一些，有些人应该拥有。
start a business I'm a huge advocate for
我非常支持创业。
entrepreneurship for the right person
创业适合合适的人
who's the right
谁是对的
person I used to
我以前认识的人
think everybody needs to become an
认为每个人都需要成为一个
entrepreneur because when I started to
因为我开始创业的时候
see success as an entrepreneur I crossed
作为一名企业家，我曾经历过成功与失败。
that invisible barrier I said oh my God
那道无形的屏障，我说，我的天哪
people need to see this you have to
人们需要看到这一点，你必须这样做。
become an entrepreneur you can do things
成为一名企业家，你就能做很多事。
on your own and I was preaching this to
你独自一人，而我当时正在向别人宣讲这一点
my friend friends I got one friend of
我的朋友，我有一个朋友
mine who was an engineer to quit his job
我那位工程师辞职了
and to then join me he would come to my
然后他会来找我，和我汇合。
office and I would talk to him about
我会和他谈谈办公室的事。
things and I said you know different
事情，我说你知道，不一样
ways you can do
你可以这样做
this and I realized pretty
我意识到这一点后，相当
quickly he is not meant to be an
他很快就不能算是一个
entrepreneur the work ethic was
企业家的工作伦理是
different when he would go home he
他回家的时候情况就不一样了
didn't want to work and that did not
不想工作，而且那也没……
click to me what do you mean you don't
点击我，你的意思是你不……？
want to work
想工作
after 5:00 like that there's no stop
五点以后就一直这样，没有停歇的可能。
point when you're starting a business
当你开始创业的时候
you got to
你必须
start the second thing
开始第二件事
was the way you think about risk it's oh
你对风险的看法是……哦
well if I invest $100 how fast I'm going
如果我投资100美元，我的投资速度会有多快？
to make the money back am I going to
为了把钱赚回来，我该怎么做？
make this money back it became all these
把这笔钱赚回来，它变成了这一切
like little
像小
analysises before you've even done
在你开始分析之前就已经进行分析了
anything you got to start and then it's
凡事你都得先开始，然后就……
the innovation of what are you going to
你打算如何进行创新？
do it's asking for a blueprint tell me
它要求提供蓝图，请告诉我。
exactly what to do tell me exactly what
具体该怎么做？告诉我具体该怎么做。
to sell tell me exactly how how to sell
要卖出去，请告诉我具体的销售方法。
it I don't know what you are good at I
我不知道你擅长什么。
don't know what problem you can solve I
我不知道你能解决什么问题。
don't know what Innovation you can
不知道你能做出什么创新
create and this is where I go back
创造，然后我又回到这里
to I am a big advocate for
我非常支持……
entrepreneurship for the right person
创业适合合适的人
who is that right person somebody who
谁是合适的人选？某个人
has this entrepreneurial itch that you
你是不是也有这种创业的冲动？
have this this I need to create
我需要创建这个
something this I can't work for somebody
我不能为某人做这件事
else's feeling this I want to build
其他人也有这种感觉，我想建立
something it's a very much like I don't
有什么东西很像，但我并不这么认为。
care what it takes I don't care what I
我不在乎要付出什么代价，我不在乎我
have to do this is what is my calling
我必须这样做，这是我的使命。
and as you say there you're going to
正如你所说，你打算……
have to tolerate
必须容忍
uncertainty and when I say uncertainty I
不确定性，当我说不确定性时，
mean comfort as well the lack of a
意味着舒适以及缺乏
blueprint the lack of certainty about
蓝图缺乏确定性
how much you're going to make this month
你这个月能赚多少钱
or how quickly you're going to make
或者你打算多快做出来
money or if you're going to make money
钱，或者如果你打算赚钱的话
risk which is you might have to put a
风险在于你可能需要投入
lot of things on the line including your
很多事情都岌岌可危，包括你的
reputation and you said hard work as
声誉，你还说努力工作
well so are you willing to work seven
那么，你愿意工作七天吗？
days a week and you're right you know
一周好几天，你说得对，你知道的。
when people say that they think it's
当人们说他们认为这是
super toxic but like in my own
剧毒，但就像我自己的一样
experiences of starting businesses but
创业经历
then on every friend that I have that
然后，我对我的每个朋友都这样说。
started a business they'll all tell you
他们都会告诉你，他们创办了自己的公司。
that there's absolutely no such thing as
根本不存在这种东西
9 to-5 you work you work whenever you
朝九晚五，你工作，你随时工作
have to work and if you're at a bar
你得工作，如果你在酒吧
mitzvah or a wedding or a anniversary
行善、婚礼或周年纪念
meal with your partner at any moment you
随时随地和你的伴侣一起用餐
might get a horrible email and you have
你可能会收到一封糟糕的邮件，而且你……
to act upon it you can't say I'm going
要付诸行动，你不能说“我要走了”。
to save that till Monday or not my
留到周一再说，还是不留？
problem oh yeah and I'm going to add one
问题，哦，对了，我还要补充一点。
more to that
还有很多关于这方面的内容。
list the willingness to be criticized oh
列出接受批评的意愿
yeah any business you start you are
是的，无论你创办什么企业，你都是
going to upset a lot of
会令很多人感到不安
people at every stage of the business I
企业各个阶段的人员
mean this is really important because
这意味着这件事非常重要，因为
much of the reason why people want to be
人们想要成为……的很大一部分原因
entrepreneurs is because they want to be
之所以成为企业家，是因为他们想成为企业家。
their own boss but what's so interesting
他们自己的老板，但有什么有趣的呢？
about the story you told about that
关于你讲的那个故事
tenant is you became her
房客是你成了她
boss whenever I speak to entrepreneurs
老板，每当我与创业者交谈时
there's one problem that always comes up
有一个问题总是会冒出来。
but today's sponsor LinkedIn has a
但今天的赞助商 LinkedIn 却拥有
solution and I think you'll want to hear
解决方案，我想你会想听听的。
it connecting your business with the
它将你的企业与
Right audience can be tough you can
找到合适的受众可能很困难，但你可以
spend a lot of time and money trying to
花费大量时间和金钱试图
get it right and still regardless fall
即使做对了，仍然会跌倒
short of that especially when it comes
除此之外，尤其是在以下方面：
to B2B marketing where you're not doing
到你没有涉足的B2B营销领域
business with one person you're dealing
与你交易的那个人做生意
with teams making decisions together
团队共同做出决策
through Linkedin ads you can connect
通过领英广告，您可以建立联系
with an extensive Professional Network
拥有广泛的专业人脉
of over a billion members including 10
拥有超过十亿成员，其中包括10
million seite Executives you can also
百万级高管，你也可以
Target specifically by job title
目标职位
industry company and more it's no
行业公司等等，它不是
surprise to me that LinkedIn is reported
令我惊讶的是，LinkedIn竟然被报道了。
to be the highest returning paid social
成为回报率最高的付费社交
platform in the world to help you get
全球领先的平台，助您获得
started LinkedIn is offering a $100
LinkedIn 发起了一项活动，提供 100 美元。
credit to launch your first campaign on
用于启动您第一个营销活动的信贷
the platform just go to linkedin.com
该平台只需访问 linkedin.com 即可。
doac 24 to claim your credit now that's
立即在24小时内领取您的信用额度
linkedin.com
linkedin.com
doac c24 terms and conditions apply this
doac c24 的条款和条件适用。
diary won't change your life but the
日记不会改变你的人生，但是
Habit it teaches you definitely will the
它教给你的习惯肯定会让你……
most unhelpful advice that I ever
我听过最没用的建议
received was don't sweat the small stuff
收到的信息是：别为小事烦恼。
you have to sweat the small stuff I
你必须在小事上斤斤计较。
sweat the small stuff I always have and
我总是会为一些小事烦恼。
I always proudly will because small
我将永远为此感到自豪，因为小
things that are easy to do are also easy
容易做的事情也容易
not to do it is easy to save a dollar so
不做这件事很容易省下一美元，所以
it's also easy not to it is easy to
不这样做也很容易，这样做很容易。
brush your teeth so it's also easy not
刷牙也很容易，所以不要
to it is easy to make a 1% Improvement
所以，做出1%的改进很容易。
so it's also easy not to understanding
所以也很容易不理解
the power of compounding 1% you can
复利的力量，1% 的收益，你可以
absolutely change your outcomes in your
彻底改变你的结果
life it isn't about drastic
生活并非总是充满戏剧性。
Transformations or quick wins it's about
是转型还是速成？关键在于
the small consistent actions that have a
那些持续的小行动
lasting change in your outcomes so two
结果的持久改变，所以两个
years ago we started the process of
几年前，我们开始了……的过程
creating this beautiful diary and it's
创作这本美丽的日记，而且……
truly beautiful inside there's lots of
里面真的很漂亮，有很多……
pictures lots of inspiration and
图片能给人带来很多灵感，
motivation as well some Interac Dev
动机以及一些 Interac 开发
elements and the purpose of this diary
这本日记的要素和目的
is to help you identify stay focused on
旨在帮助你识别并专注于
develop consistency with the one perents
与父母保持一致
that will ultimately change life we're
那最终将改变我们的生活
only going to do a limited run of these
这些产品只会限量生产。
Diaries so if you want one for yourself
日记本，所以如果你想给自己买一本的话。
or for a friend or for a colleague or
或者送给朋友，或者送给同事，或者
for your team then head to the diary.com
如果是你的团队，请前往 diary.com。
right now I'll link it below one one of
我现在就把链接放在下面其中一个
the things I really wanted to to talk to
我真正想谈论的事情
you about as well is just a word that I
你说的“差不多”只是一个词而已。
think is so pertinent to everything
认为这与一切都息息相关
we've talked about today which which I
我们今天谈到了我
think is important which is the word
思考很重要，这个词很重要。
patience because there's some areas of
耐心，因为有些领域
my it goes to what I said about my
我的，这跟我之前说的关于我的事有关。
friend my friend who's been in our group
我的朋友，我的朋友，他一直在我们这个小组里。
chat who's made more C than all of my
聊天室里谁赚的C比我所有人加起来都多
other friends in that group chat and
群聊里的其他朋友
he's done it by being boring
他靠的是无聊。
impatient like he's he's just flown
他像刚下飞机一样不耐烦
under the radar and when I think about
在不引人注意的时候，当我想到……
my life and many of the Investments I'm
我的生活和我的许多投资
making now I'm like oh God what is it
现在我感觉就像，哦天哪，这到底是什么？
I'm looking over there my friends buying
我正看着那边，我的朋友们正在买东西。
some like crypto meme coin and he's told
有些人喜欢加密模因币，他告诉过他。
me it's gone up 150x this month I'm
这个月它涨了150倍，我是
looking over there and people are
往那边看，有人
investing in I don't know the the
投资我不知道
they're picking stocks and stock trading
他们挑选股票并进行股票交易。
whatever and they're telling me it's
随便吧，他们告诉我就是这样。
gone up
上升
50% but in my wisdom as I've gotten
50%，但以我的智慧，正如我所获得的
older I've realized like the tortois in
年纪大了之后，我意识到就像乌龟一样……
the hair that boring and patient is such
那头头发，无聊又耐心，真是……
a wonderful investment strategy it's
这是一种绝妙的投资策略。
such like a paradoxical way to think I
就像一种自相矛盾的思考方式
have so many seeds that I've planted
我种下了好多种子
that are taking forever to grow but I
它们生长速度非常慢，但我
just now know because I've got enough
我现在才知道，因为我已经掌握了足够的信息。
case studies in my brain that that
我脑海中的案例研究表明，
boring impatient approach to wealth will
对待财富的枯燥乏味和缺乏耐心
put me in a better position at the end
最后让我处于更有利的地位
of the game
游戏
yes and you have to be sometimes
是的，有时候你必须这样做。
impatiently patient
不耐烦的耐心
so if we talk about Building Wealth
所以，如果我们谈论的是积累财富。
through investing your money the numbers
通过投资你的资金来了解数字
have shown that over the last century
已经表明，在过去一个世纪里，
the stock market has gone up by an
股市上涨了
average of 10% a year
平均每年10%。
historically but many people lose money
从历史上看，很多人会赔钱。
when investing in stocks I mean if you
投资股票时，我的意思是，如果你
go around talking people have you
到处跟人说你有什么事
invested in stocks yes yes yes how many
投资股票了吗？是的，是的，是的，有多少？
of you have made money the hands start
如果你已经赚到钱，那就开始行动吧。
dropping well if the stock market has
如果股市下跌，情况会好转
gone up by around 10% a year on average
平均每年上涨约10%。
every year for the last 100 years why
过去一百年来每年都是如此，为什么？
why are so many people losing money
为什么这么多人赔钱
because we start playing the wrong game
因为我们开始玩错误的游戏。
and so now what happens if you invest
那么，如果你投资会发生什么呢？
your money into the stock market and by
把你的钱投入股市，然后
the stock market I mean let's just say
股票市场，我的意思是，我们姑且这么说吧。
you buy the S&amp;P 500 which is a basket of
你购买的是标普500指数，它是一篮子……
the 500 largest companies in the stock
股票市场中最大的500家公司
market for example not Financial advice
例如市场，而非财务建议
if you invest in spy that is an ETF that
如果你投资SPY，那它就是一种ETF。
gives you exposure to the 500 largest
让您有机会接触到最大的500家公司。
companies we know that historically
我们知道，历史上这些公司
that's gone up by 10% a year but that's
虽然每年上涨10%，但这已经是……
not enough for a lot of people so now
对很多人来说还不够，所以现在
I'm going to play this game of I'm going
我要玩这个游戏，我要去
to try to beat the
试图击败
market and some people will most won't
市场，有些人会，但大多数人不会。
so now some people are going to try to
所以现在有些人打算尝试
get into the game of investing in
参与投资游戏
individual companies or maybe trading
个别公司或交易
companies because even investing in
公司，因为即使投资
individual companies if you invest for
如果您投资于个别公司，那么您可以考虑这些公司。
the long enough period of time you're
时间越长，你就会……
probably going to
大概会去
win but many people now want a quicker
赢了，但现在很多人想要更快的胜利
solution so now we start trading we
所以现在我们开始交易，这就是解决方案。
start finding hot companies the next
接下来开始寻找热门公司
Tesla the next Amazon we see what Reddit
特斯拉会是下一个亚马逊吗？Reddit 上有人会这么说 ...
says see what Google says and we start
他说，看看谷歌怎么说，然后我们就开始吧。
buying these things because we're
我们购买这些东西是因为
excited but that excitement is what's
兴奋，但这种兴奋本身就是……
killing your wealth because you're
你正在挥霍你的财富，因为你
investing On Emotion instead of
凭情绪投资，而不是凭感觉投资。
investing on
投资
financials and so this is where you talk
财务方面，所以这就是你要谈论的地方。
about what's
关于什么
boring just keep doing the market keep
无聊，就继续做市场交易吧
investing in the market when the
投资市场时
Market's up when the Market's down when
市场上涨时，市场下跌时
the market sideways just keep investing
市场横盘整理，继续投资
because that has been proven to win we
因为事实证明那样才能赢，所以我们
know that if you invest a $100 a mon
要知道，如果你每月投资 100 美元……
month from the age of 21 until your
从21岁到你的那个月
retirement
退休
6566 and you can get that same 10%
6566，你也可以获得同样的10%折扣。
return you're going to retire a
你将退休。
millionaire assuming you only invest
假设你只投资，你就能成为百万富翁
$100 a month from the age of 21 to 65 or
21岁至65岁每月100美元
66 it's so interesting because when I
66 这太有趣了，因为当我
asked you earlier what the best
之前问过你最好的是什么。
investment you ever made was you said
你曾经做过的投资就是你说的。
the investment you made in yourself and
你对自己的投资以及
maybe we've not spent enough time really
或许我们花的时间还不够多。
talking about how critical
谈到关键性
Knowledge and Skills are to wealth
知识和技能是财富之源。
generation maybe that is the first
或许这是第一代
principle of wealth creation maybe that
财富创造原则或许是
is the furthest thing Upstream is
最上游的东西是
Knowledge and Skills um and you can you
知识和技能，嗯，你可以
know dabble in stocks and whatever else
略懂皮毛，也涉足股票和其他领域。
but really over a 50-year Time Horizon
但实际上是跨越50年的时间跨度
your Knowledge and Skills and you know
你的知识和技能，以及你所知
your knowledge might be of patience your
你的知识可能与耐心有关
knowledge might be of real estate
知识可能与房地产有关
investing your knowledge might be of
运用你的知识可能很有价值
whatever your knowledge might be of a
无论你对……了解多少
philosophy towards investing really it's
投资理念其实是……
your Knowledge and Skills they're going
你的知识和技能，他们正在走向
to determine where you end up so as it
决定你最终的去向，以便它
relates to getting those Knowledge and
与获取这些知识有关
Skills where's the best place to people
技能，哪里是人们的最佳去处
to go other than obviously the Dio you
除了迪奥之外，你还可以去哪里呢？
know but outside of this podcast where
我知道，但在这个播客之外，还有什么地方
is the best place for people to go to
是人们去的最佳地点
get Knowledge and Skills that they can
获得他们能够掌握的知识和技能
trust without getting scammed without
信任而不被骗
having to pay for some call from some
不得不为某些人的来电付费
YouTuber who's charging $3,000 a month
一位每月收费 3000 美元的 YouTuber
for like a you know to tell them
就像你知道的那样告诉他们
something that reading off chat GPT what
读取聊天记录的 GPT 是什么
is like the best place well the best
就像是最好的地方，真的是最好的。
best place is to go out and do it screw
最好的办法就是出去做这件事
up make
化妆
mistakes but along with that start with
错误，但与此同时，开始
what's free YouTube podcasts best book
哪些YouTube播客免费？最好的书
you've ever read the first book I'll
你读过我第一本书吗？
start with that because the best is it
就从那开始吧，因为那才是最好的。
changes yeah the first book I ever read
是的，我读的第一本书发生了变化。
cover to cover was Rich Dad pad the
从头到尾都是《富爸爸》
second book was Total Money Makeover
第二本书是《彻底理财改造》。
Rich Dad pad is by Robert kosaki Total
《富爸爸》的作者是罗伯特·小崎·道达尔 (Robert kosaki Total)
Money Makeover is by Dave Ramsey the
《理财大改造》是戴夫·拉姆齐的作品。
third book is a book called uh the
第三本书叫做《呃》
creature from Jackal Island which talks
来自豺狼岛的会说话的生物
about the Federal Reserve Bank those
关于美联储那些
three books are going to give you a
这三本书会给你带来……
foundation of money and different
资金的基础和不同
perspectives of
视角
it so start by learning for free even
所以，即使是免费学习也可以开始。
before books start by watch a YouTube
在开始阅读书籍之前，先观看一段 YouTube 视频。
video start by listening to podcasts
视频可以先从听播客开始。
then you take the next step and you
然后你采取下一步行动，你
start reading books and what I talk
开始阅读书籍和我谈论的内容
about is if you go out and over the next
大概就是如果你出去，在接下来的时间里
12 months you read five books on money
12个月里你读了五本关于钱的书。
management and investing I just gave
管理和投资方面，我刚刚提到过。
three read five books on personal
三人读了五本关于个人的书
development and self-development read
发展与自我发展阅读
five books on how to start a business
五本关于如何创业的书
read five books on leadership and then
读五本关于领导力的书，然后
read five books on how to scale market
阅读五本关于如何扩大市场规模的书籍
and build grow your business you're
并发展壮大你的业务
going to have an MBA level education for
打算接受MBA级别的教育
a fraction of the cost start with that
从那开始，只需花费一小部分成本。
and then go out and make mistakes and as
然后出去犯错，然后……
you grow that's when you can start
你长大后就可以开始了
buying classes and other things because
因为购买课程和其他东西
you'll find people that you might want
你会找到你可能想要的人。
to get Consulting from but start with
要获得咨询服务，但首先要从
that what is the most important thing we
对我们来说，最重要的是什么？
didn't talk about
没有谈到
today as it relates to wealth creation
今天，就财富创造而言，它与此息息相关
the most important thing that I think we
我认为最重要的事情是我们
did not talk about is we we talked about
我们没有谈到我们谈论的是什么
the economic system we talked about the
我们讨论的经济体系
principles but I think we didn't get
原则上，但我认为我们没有做到。
into the actual steps now of how do you
现在进入实际步骤，你如何……
preserve and protect your wealth and how
如何保全和保护您的财富
do you now continue to use wealth
你现在是否继续使用财富
protection tools because there's a lot
防护工具有很多。
of that that every single wealthy person
那就是每一个富人
is investing a huge amount of time
投入大量时间
effort and money into that most people
大多数人都投入了精力和金钱。
have no idea even exists we started to
我们甚至不知道它的存在，我们开始
touch on taxes but there's so much more
会涉及到税收问题，但远不止这些。
so on those wealth preservation tools
所以，关于这些财富保全工具
what exactly are you referring to
你具体指的是什么？
starting with first your accounting and
首先从你的会计开始
taxes then we get into the legal your
然后我们再谈到税务问题，以及法律方面的问题。
estate planning what types of attorneys
遗产规划需要哪些类型的律师
what types of legal protection and
哪些类型的法律保护和
Shields and tools can you use to
你可以使用盾牌和工具来
structure your business your Investments
构建你的业务和投资体系
to protect you but also amplify your
既保护你，也增强你的
wealth and then things like
财富，以及诸如此类的事情
insurance but then also you're estate
保险，还有你的遗产。
planning because you talk about
因为你谈到了计划
generational wealth
代际财富
well generational wealth isn't just the
代际财富不仅仅是……
money it's what your money does after
金钱，关键在于你的钱之后会做什么。
you die and you can control that when
你会死，而你可以控制自己的死亡。
you're alive we have a closing tradition
你还活着，我们有一个结束的传统
on this podcast where the last guest
在本期播客节目中，上一位嘉宾的访谈内容是……
leaves a question for the next guest not
给下一位客人留下一个问题，不是吗？
knowing who they're leaving it for and
知道他们要把房子留给谁
the question that's been left for you
留给你的问题是……
is what wakes you up every
就是它每天早上把你叫醒。
morning oh I'm excited I don't use an
早上好，哦，我好兴奋，我不使用……
alarm I'm I'm I'm get up by the purpose
闹钟响了，我起床了，目的是为了……
I'm excited by the mission I mean I I
我对这项任务感到兴奋，我的意思是……
love what I do uh the purpose the
我热爱我所做的事，嗯，目的
mission that's what gets me up every
这就是我每天起床的动力。
morning what about yourself and your own
早上好，你和你自己呢？
happiness and mental health and you know
幸福和心理健康，你知道的
you
你
know I I am happy I I've been so
我知道我很开心，我一直都很开心
fortunate I've always been one of those
幸运的是，我一直都是其中一员。
people you could put me in a box and I'd
有些人，就算把我装进盒子里，我也会
have a great time I would turn that box
玩得开心！我会把那个盒子翻过来。
into an airplane and I'd be flying it
把它放进飞机里，然后由我来驾驶。
around before I came here my wife
在我来这里之前，我的妻子
recorded a video I found this so we were
我录制了一段视频，我发现了这个，所以我们……
in a hotel um and they gave these cans
在一家酒店里，他们给了我这些罐头。
of water okay
水质良好
these two cans of water I took them I
我拿了这两罐水。
said record this video I went on the
他说要录下这个视频，我就照做了。
balcony and I did a Stone Cold Steve
阳台上，我模仿了“冷石史蒂夫”的造型。
Austin mock video where I opened up the
奥斯汀模拟视频，我在视频中打开了
cans of water and just dumped it on
几罐水，然后直接倒了上去。
myself just I don't know why and I sent
我自己也不知道为什么，就发了。
it to my
给我
cousins I've been very blessed to uh I
我很幸运能拥有这么多优秀的表兄弟姐妹。
can have a good time with anything I'm a
我做什么都能玩得开心。
pretty light-hearted guy I know I talk
我知道我是一个性格比较随和的人，我说话也很健谈。
about serious stuff but I I've been very
关于严肃的事情，但我一直非常
fortunate on that and uh I can have fun
很幸运，而且我可以玩得很开心。
in a lot of situations
在很多情况下
I'm not driven by materialistic things
我并非受物质欲望驱使。
um there are some certain things that
嗯，有些事情是这样的……
are like I will spend money on luxuries
就像我会把钱花在奢侈品上一样
uh my wife got me into that into like
呃，是我老婆让我接触到那个领域的。
like nicer hotels and nicer travel and
比如更好的酒店和更好的旅行
those conveniences I
那些便利设施
like uh and I want to keep my wife happy
嗯，我想让我的妻子开心
so whatever you know she likes but I I'm
所以你知道她喜欢什么，但我……
not driven by fancy cars fancy
不是靠豪车驱动的
clothes uh that to me is not as
衣服，嗯，对我来说，那不是……
important I I I like to
重要 我 我喜欢
see change and I want to help Empower
我看到了改变，我想帮助赋能。
people people and that gets me excited
人们，人们，这让我很兴奋。
uh if you had to bring it down to five
呃，如果非要选五个的话。
things that are driving you then what
那么，是什么在驱使你呢？
are those five
那五个人是吗？
things number one taking care of my
第一件事就是照顾好自己
family yep number two is my own purpose
家庭，是的，第二点是我的个人目标
and Mission and feeling excited like my
还有任务，感觉很兴奋，就像我的
personal excitement yeah number three is
个人兴奋点，是的，第三点是
the mission yeah is to continue help
是的，我们的任务是继续提供帮助。
people number four is to bring light to
第四个人的目的是带来光明
the
这
community number five is to continue giv
第五个社区是继续给予
him back and to help
他回来帮忙
just PR thank you thank you so much for
公关稿，谢谢，非常感谢！
being so generous with your time and
感谢您慷慨地抽出时间
I've learned so much um about so many
我学到了很多关于……的知识
things and I've had so many sort
东西，我有很多种类
of ideas
想法
reinforced and sometimes that's it you
强化，有时候就是这样。
know I do these conversations because
我知道我之所以进行这些对话，是因为
I've been out there in the world and
我曾到过世界各地，
I've met people who have listened to
我遇到过一些听过……的人
these conversations about wealth and
这些关于财富的对话
finance and money and sometimes in life
金融、金钱，以及有时在生活中
all it is is just a little seed of
它只不过是一小颗种子而已
information that can absolutely change
绝对可以改变的信息
the trajectory of not just you but the
不仅是你，还有
generations that come after you and
你之后的世代和
that's exactly what you're doing that's
你做的正是这件事。
exactly what you've done on your YouTube
你在 YouTube 上做的一切都一样
channel for so many people that probably
很多人的频道，可能
will never get to say thank you to you
我永远没有机会对你道谢了
but it's to give these little seeds of
但这样做是为了给这些小种子……
inspiration and information and you
灵感和信息，还有你
never really know which seed is going to
你永远无法真正知道哪颗种子会发芽。
change someone's life but what you do is
改变他人的人生，但你所做的是
you just continue to plant them and
你只需要继续种植它们，
hopefully those people will water them
希望那些人会给它们浇水。
for themselves so thank you so much for
为了他们自己，所以非常感谢。
what you do thank you for being so
感谢你的付出，谢谢你如此。
generous with your time today and please
今天请您慷慨地抽出时间。
do keep doing it because our education
请继续这样做，因为我们的教育
system is a bit of a cookie cutter and
系统有点像千篇一律的模板，
optimizes for creating people that are
旨在培养以下类型的人才
part of of a system which doesn't seem
系统的一部分，而这个系统似乎并非如此。
to be designed with their best long-term
旨在以最佳的长期效益进行设计
interests in mind and that's why we have
我们始终以利益为先，这就是我们存在的原因。
these problems that's why we live in
这就是我们生活在其中的原因。
this credit Society that's why we have
这就是我们拥有信用社会的原因。
these retirement issues and that's
这些退休问题，就是这样。
probably why we have so much mental
这大概就是为什么我们有这么多心理问题的原因吧
health issues and depression but it's
健康问题和抑郁症，但这只是
people like you out there that
像你这样的人，
are giving us the information that gives
正在向我们提供信息，这些信息表明
us a chance a chance to live a different
我们有机会，有机会过上另一种生活。
life so thank you for that JRE I really
所以，谢谢你，JRE，我真的非常感谢你。
appreciate you thank you for having me
谢谢你们邀请我。
on it was really a
上面确实是一个
pleasure Chuck me that perfect Ted one
很高兴能把那个完美的泰迪熊扔给我
of the things that I think about all the
我思考的所有事情
time because my life is quite hectic and
因为我的生活非常忙碌，所以需要一些时间。
busy is how to manage my energy load and
忙碌让我学会了如何管理自己的精力负荷。
as a podcast you kind of have to manage
作为播客，你必须设法做到这一点。
your energy in such a way that you can
以某种方式运用你的能量，这样你就可以
have these articulate conversations with
与……进行这些清晰流畅的对话
experts on subjects you don't understand
你不懂的领域的专家
and this is why perfect head has become
这就是为什么完美头脑会成为
so important in my life because
对我的生活来说非常重要，因为
previously when it came to Energy
以前谈到能源时
Products I had to make a tradeoff that I
我不得不权衡利弊才能买到这些产品。
wasn't happy with typically if I wanted
如果我想要的话，通常情况下我并不满意。
the energy I had to deal with high sugar
我需要精力来应对高糖饮食
I had to deal with Jitters and crashes
我不得不应对系统抖动和崩溃问题。
that come along with a lot of the
伴随很多……
mainstream energy prod s and I also just
主流能源产品，我也只是
had to tolerate the fact that if I want
我不得不忍受这样一个事实：如果我想要
energy I have to put up with a lot of
我不得不忍受很多精力
artificial ingredients which my body
我的身体含有的人工成分
didn't like and that's why I invested in
不喜欢，所以我才投资了
perfect Ted and why they're one of the
完美的泰德以及他们为何是其中之一
sponsors of this podcast it has changed
本播客的赞助商已变更
not just my life but my entire team's
不仅是我个人的生活，还有我们整个团队的生活。
life and for me it's drastically
生活对我来说截然不同
improved my cognitive performance but
提高了我的认知能力，但是
also my physical performance so if you
还有我的体能表现，所以如果你
haven't tried perfect Ted yet you must
还没试过完美泰德呢，你一定要试试。
have been living under a rock now is the
我一直与世隔绝，现在才知道这件事。
time you can find perfect T at Tesco and
你可以在 Tesco 找到完美的 T 恤。
waitrose or online where you can enjoy
您可以在 Waitrose 或网上享受
40% off with code diary 40 at checkout
结账时使用优惠码 diary 40 可享 40% 折扣
head to perfect ted.com
前往 perfect ted.com
[Music]
[音乐]